<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<movie>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="0">MOVIEBEGINNING</sceneheader>
   </scene>
   <beginning>CARS 2


WRITTEN BY

BEN QUEEN



A sleek British sports car talks directly to us in a
pixilated, garbled video. He's OUT OF BREATH. Crates are
visible behind him. We're in the shadowy bowels of a steel
room.

LELAND TURBO
This is Agent Leland Turbo. I have
a flash transmission for Agent Finn
McMissile.

SUPERIMPOSE OVER BLACK: WALT DISNEY PICTURES PRESENTS

LELAND TURBO
Finn. My cover's been compromised.
Everything's gone pear-shaped.

SUPERIMPOSE OVER BLACK: A PIXAR ANIMATION STUDIOS FILM

LELAND TURBO
You won't believe what I've found
out here.

He angles our camera view, reveals a PORTHOLE through which
we can see flames rising in the distance.

LELAND TURBO
This is bigger than anything we've
ever seen. And no one even knows it
exists. Finn, I need backup. But
don't call the cavalry - it could
blow the operation. And be careful.
It's not safe out here!

ANGRY VOICES O.S. Time for Turbo to go.

LELAND TURBO
Transmitting my grids now. Good
luck!

Coordinates appear: 40 6.80' N - 172 23.84' W

TITLE CARD: CARS 2


</beginning>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="1">EXT. SOMEWHERE IN THE NORTH PACIFIC - NIGHT
</sceneheader>
      <meta> A TINY CRAB BOAT (CRABBY) crests over massive swells. </meta>
      <char name="CRABBY">
         <dialogue> Alright buddy, we're here. Right where you paid me to bring you. Question is, why?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  A metallic blue sports car, circa the `60s, emerges from the 2.   shadows. Cagey, smooth, he'd turn heads driving through any intersection in the world. Meet FINN MCMISSILE. </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> I'm looking for a car.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="CRABBY">
         <dialogue> A car? Hey pal, you can't get any further away from land than out here.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Exactly where I want to be.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="CRABBY">
         <dialogue> Well I got news for you, buddy. There's nobody out here but us.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Suddenly, a HORN -- a COMBAT SHIP, the size of most cruise ships. FINN quickly backs into the shadows, out of sight. </meta>
      <char name="COMBAT SHIP">
         <dialogue> What are you doing out here?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="CRABBY">
         <dialogue> What does it look like, genius? I'm crabbing!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="COMBAT SHIP">
         <dialogue> Well turn around and go back where you came from.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="CRABBY">
         <dialogue> Yeah? And who's gonna make me?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  A laser sight hits Crabby between the eyes. </meta>
      <char name="CRABBY">
         <dialogue> Alright, alright! Don't get your prop in a twist. What a jerk. Sorry, buddy. Looks like it's the end of the line. Buddy?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(as he turns to leave)  ON CRABBY'S DECK: Finn is gone. CUT TO:  FINN - He HANGS off the side of COMBAT SHIP, clandestine.  We're with Finn as the ship continues on, cuts through the darkness with purpose. Suddenly small flames appear, perhaps a knot or so away. Then WHOOSH!!! A flame rises above Finn, the ship. It illuminates an OIL DERRICK. 3.   THWAP! Finn fires a GRAPPLING HOOK to the derrick and SWINGS toward it. He's going to SLAM into the side with brute force</meta>
      <char name="WHEN ---">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="2">EXT. PLATFORM - OIL DERRICK - MOMENTS LATER
</sceneheader>
      <meta> Finn approaches a loading bay from above, hides. He watches as GREMLINS, PACERS and assorted other cars scurry about. </meta>
      <char name="FINN (INTO RADIO)">
         <dialogue> Leland Turbo, this is Finn McMissile. I'm at the rally point. Over.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  No response. </meta>
      <char name="FINN (INTO RADIO)">
         <dialogue> Leland, it's Finn. Please respond. Over.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  AN ACCESS DOOR OPENS LOUDLY below. A boxy, monacle-wearing German car enters. This is PROFESSOR OTTO ZUNDAPP. </meta>
      <char name="PROFESSOR ZUNDAPP">
         <dialogue> Too many cars here. Out of my way!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(in German and English) </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Professor Zundapp?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="PACER (O.S.)">
         <dialogue> Here it is, Professor.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Zundapp approaches a NOSY PACER who idles next to a CRATE. </meta>
      <char name="NOSY PACER">
         <dialogue> You wanted to see this before we load it?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="PROFESSOR ZUNDAPP">
         <dialogue> Ah, yes. Very carefully...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  A forklift opens the crate -- inside is a TV CAMERA, packed carefully in foam. Finn SNAPS PHOTOS FURIOUSLY. </meta>
      <char name="NOSY PACER">
         <dialogue> Oh. A TV camera. What does it actually do? 4.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="PROFESSOR ZUNDAPP">
         <dialogue> This camera is extremely dangerous.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> What are you up to now, Professor?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(TO HIMSELF)  Finn, angling for a better view, FIRES SUSPENSION WIRES ---  --- which sail clear to the other side of the derrick ---  --- THOK! They hook tightly onto a steel girder.  Finn slides out ONTO THE WIRE like an acrobat, then expels another cross-wire for support. </meta>
      <char name="PROFESSOR ZUNDAPP">
         <dialogue> This is valuable equipment. Make sure it is properly secured for the voyage.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="NOSY PACER">
         <dialogue> You got it.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Finn LOWERS HIMSELF. He snaps more pictures. </meta>
      <char name="GREM (O.S.)">
         <dialogue> Hey, Professor Z!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Zundapp turns as a CRANE LOWERS A CAR-SIZED CRATE. GREM and ACER, an orange Gremlin and a green Pacer, flank it. </meta>
      <char name="GREM">
         <dialogue> This is one of those British spies we told you about.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="ACER">
         <dialogue> Yeah. This one we caught sticking his bumper where it didn't belong.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Finn PRODUCES SEMI-AUTOMATIC GUNS from his side, readies himself for a tag-team spy fight with his buddy Leland. </meta>
      <char name="PROFESSOR ZUNDAPP">
         <dialogue> Agent Leland Turbo.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  The crate is lifted, revealing a CRUSHED, CUBED Leland Turbo.  Finn's eyes go wide. Suddenly --- WHOOOSHHH! Another derrick flame rises behind him, casts a Finn-shaped SHADOW over the Professor. He looks up. 5.  </meta>
      <char name="PROFESSOR ZUNDAPP">
         <dialogue> It's Finn McMissile! He's seen the camera! Kill him!!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Finn UNLOADS with bullets as he starts to retreat --- He STOPS:  BAD GUY CARS are waiting for him on the catwalk where he just came from - BLOWTORCHES ready.  Finn, stuck in midair, notices an angry CRANE. Finn GRINS, having just found his escape.  THWAPTHWAPTHWAP!!! Finn releases three of his four cables, swinging, Indiana Jones-style on the last one TOWARD THE</meta>
      <char name="CRANE ---">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
      <meta>  --- where he lands on its BOOM, drives UP and LAUNCHES OFF IT where he LANDS - MOVING - onto another deck!  Finn now DRIVES, spraying oil and screeching around corners. A GREMLIN in pursuit hits the oil patch, loses control ---  --- and PLUMMETS OFF the side of the rig!  The Gremlin FALLS... it's like an eternity...  He smashes into the water and breaks into a million pieces.  ON FINN - Now set upon by 20 or 30 MORE pursuing cars. He has nowhere to go but UP UP UP a ramp toward the helipad. He spies some GASOLINE BARRELS, fires a SINGLE BULLET which cuts through its leather straps, sending barrels DOWN the ramp,</meta>
      <char name="PAST FINN ---">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
      <meta>  --- PAST the pursuing CARS ---  --- to the bottom where they EXPLODE in a CHAIN REACTION back UP THE RAMP, taking out at least 15 CARS!  ON THE HELIPAD - Finn blasts into view, pulls to a stop. No more road. Nowhere else to go.  The 20 BAD GUY CARS that are still in pursuit surround him, fire up their blowtorches. About to pounce.  Finn GRINS. The second time we've seen this grin. It means he's got something cooking.  Finn's REVERSE LIGHTS appear. He DRIVES BACKWARD off the edge of the helipad to the SHOCK of the other cars.  Finn falls. He turns himself so he's grill first, cleanly cutting into the water. 6.   He EMERGES, now sprouting HYDROFOIL and speeds away. </meta>
      <char name="GREM">
         <dialogue> Get to the boats.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(NONPLUSSED)  THE BOATS - an army of combat ships quickly DROP into the sea and CHURN WATER with unprecedented fury as they quickly make up the distance between them and Finn, FIRING BULLETS as they do so. </meta>
      <char name="ACER">
         <dialogue> He's getting away!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="COMBAT SHIP">
         <dialogue> Not for long.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  The LEAD COMBAT SHIP quietly drops a TORPEDO into the water. It skips along, connecting with Finn in his rear and EXPLODING with such force that water skyrockets into the night clouds.  UNDERWATER - McMissile SINKS. Then, he blinks. He GRINS. We're starting to like this grin and what follows it. He now CONVERTS into a submarine. From his trunk he releases four DECOY tires which float to the surface like body parts.  ON THE DERRICK - Professor Zundapp watches it all from far away. </meta>
      <char name="GREM (OVER RADIO)">
         <dialogue> He's dead, Professor.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="PROFESSOR ZUNDAPP">
         <dialogue> Wunderbar. With Finn McMissile gone, who can stop us now?</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="3">EXT. RADIATOR SPRINGS - DAY
</sceneheader>
      <meta> TOW MATER, a rusty tow truck, putters into view. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Mater. Tow Mater, that's who... is here to help you!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  He approaches a broken-down sedan on the side of the road. He drives around to the front, catching OTIS' face for the first time. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Hey, Otis! 7.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="OTIS">
         <dialogue> Hey, Mater. Gosh, I'm so sorry. I thought I could make it this time, but... Smooth like pudding, huh? Ah, who am I kidding? I'll always be a lemon.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>engine, stalls)  Mater hooks his friend and starts towing him. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Well dadgum, you're leaking oil again. Must be your gaskets. Hey, look on the bright side: This is your tenth tow this month, so that means it's on the house.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="OTIS">
         <dialogue> You're the only one that's nice to lemons like me, Mater.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Don't sweat it. These things happen to everybody, Otis.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="OTIS">
         <dialogue> But you never leak oil.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Yeah, but I ain't perfect. Don't tell nobody, but I think my rust is starting to show through.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Mater and Otis drive past THE RADIATOR SPRINGS WELCOME SIGN. It has been amended to say: &quot;Home of Lightning McQueen.&quot; </meta>
      <char name="OTIS">
         <dialogue> Hey, is Lightning McQueen back yet?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Not yet.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="OTIS">
         <dialogue> He must be crazy-excited about winning his fourth Piston Cup. Four! Wow! 8.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Yeah, we're so dadgum proud of him. But I sure wish he'd hurry up and get back `cause we got a whole summer's worth of best friend fun to make up for. Just me and --</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Ahead of them, a half-mile off, a RED RACE CAR is visible. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> --- McQueen!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Mater FLOORS IT, dragging poor Otis behind him. </meta>
      <char name="OTIS">
         <dialogue> Uh, Mater? I'm in no hurry. You don't need to go so fast!</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="4">EXT. RADIATOR SPRINGS - DAY
</sceneheader>
      <meta> Lightning McQueen is surrounded by his hometown friends. </meta>
      <char name="LUIGI">
         <dialogue> Oh, Lightning. Welcome home.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  FLO Good to have you back, honey. </meta>
      <char name="FILLMORE">
         <dialogue> Congratulations, man.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="SARGE">
         <dialogue> Welcome home, soldier.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="SHERIFF">
         <dialogue> The place wasn't the same without you, son.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="LIZZIE">
         <dialogue> What? Did he go somewhere?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> It's good to be home, everybody.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER (O.S.)">
         <dialogue> McQueen!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  They all turn around, see Mater speeding into town, with Otis swerving behind him. </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Mater! 9.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> McQueen!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Mater skids into main street and in one swift motion, slingshots Otis forward --- </meta>
      <char name="OTIS">
         <dialogue> Woaahhhhh!</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="5">INT. RAMONE'S - CONTINUOUS
</sceneheader>
      <meta> --- where he lands perfectly on the hydraulic lift. Ramone lifts him up, routine. </meta>
      <char name="RAMONE">
         <dialogue> Hey. How far'd you make it this time, Otis?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="OTIS">
         <dialogue> Halfway to the county line.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="RAMONE">
         <dialogue> Not bad, man.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="OTIS">
         <dialogue> I know, I can't believe it either!</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="6">EXT. RADIATOR SPRINGS - CONTINUOUS
</sceneheader>
      <meta/>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> McQueen, welcome back!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Mater, it's so good to see you.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> You too, buddy.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Mater and McQueen do an ELABORATE TIRE BUMP (fist bump style). </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Oh, man. You ain't gonna believe the things I got planned for us.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Everyone watches as the tire bump continues. </meta>
      <char name="MACK">
         <dialogue> These best friend greetings get longer every year. 10.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(to Lizzie, an aside)  </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> You ready to have some serious fun?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(TO MCQUEEN) </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Well, actually I've got something to show you first.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="7">INT. RADIATOR SPRINGS MUSEUM - DAY
</sceneheader>
      <meta> CLOSE ON THE PISTON CUP. It has now changed, been adorned with a small likeness of Doc. It says &quot;Hudson Hornet Piston Cup.&quot; </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Wow. I can't believe they renamed the Piston Cup after our very own Doc Hudson.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  McQueen and Mater are alone, the museum closed to the public. McQueen approaches a &quot;Hudson Hornet&quot; wall with Doc's three Piston cups, framed articles, other racing ephemera. </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> I know Doc said these things were just old cups, but to have someone else win it just didn't feel right, you know?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Well, Doc would've been real proud of you. That's for sure.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="8">EXT. RADIATOR SPRINGS - LATER
</sceneheader>
      <meta> McQueen and Mater exit the Doc Hudson Museum. </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Alright, pal. I've been waiting all summer for this. What've you got planned?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> You sure you can handle it?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Come on, you know who you're talking to? This is Lightning McQueen. I can handle anything. 11.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="9">EXT. RADIATOR SPRINGS - DAY
</sceneheader>
      <meta> Mater and McQueen roll on an old train track, their tires off. They're on their rims. </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Uh.... Mater?!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Just remember, your brakes ain't gonna work on these!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  As they head INTO A DARK TUNNEL --- </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN (O.S.)">
         <dialogue> Mater!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER (O.S.)">
         <dialogue> Relax, these train tracks ain't been used in years!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  From inside the tunnel a loud TRAIN HORN. The two friends emerge, going as fast as they can on train tracks, uphill, with no tires. </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Come on, come on! Faster, faster!</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="10">EXT. FIELD - OUTSIDE RADIATOR SPRINGS - LATER
</sceneheader>
      <meta> An ENORMOUS EARTH MOVER sleeps. McQueen and Mater sneak up. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> This is gonna be good!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  They blow their horns and he TIPS OVER, tractor-tipping style. They LAUGH at the gag, but soon realize the earth mover's GIANT EXHAUST PIPE is directly above them. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Uh-oh. This ain't gonna be good.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="11">INT. RADIATOR SPRINGS - DUSK
</sceneheader>
      <meta> The sun sets. McQueen and Mater roll into town. McQueen looks exhausted. Mater is still full of energy. 12.  </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Boy, this was the best day ever! And my favorite souvenir?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Mater proudly shows off a dent. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> This new dent!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Boy, Mater. Today was, uh...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Shoot, that was nothing. Wait til you see what I got planned for tonight.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Mater, Mater. Whoa. I was kind of thinking of just a quiet dinner.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> That's exactly what I was thinking.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> No, I... I meant with Sally, Mater.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Even better! You, me and Miss Sally going out for supper.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  McQueen pulls around in front of Mater, stops. </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Mater, I meant it would be just me and Sally.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Oh.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> It's just for tonight. We'll do whatever you want tomorrow.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Okay.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(DISAPPOINTED) </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Thanks for understanding.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Yeah, sure. Y'all go on and have fun now. 13.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Alright, then. See ya soon, amigo!</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="12">EXT. THE WHEEL WELL - NIGHT
</sceneheader>
      <meta> It's been converted into a white-tablecloth restaurant, with cars dining al fresco and a hopping gastropub inside.  MCQUEEN AND SALLY have a prime table with a view of Radiator Springs and the starry night sky. </meta>
      <char name="SALLY">
         <dialogue> This is so nice.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> I can't tell you how good it is to be here alone. Just the two of us. Finally, you and me ---</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER (O.S.)">
         <dialogue> Good evening.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Mater is at their table, dressed as a waiter. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> My name is Mater and I'll be your waiter. Mater the waiter. That's funny right there.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(TO HIMSELF) </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Mater, you work here?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Well yeah I work here. What'd you think, I just snuck in here when nobody was looking and pretended to be your waiter, just so I could hang out with you?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  McQueen and Sally exchange a look. </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Oh, yeah. How ridiculous would that be?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Now, can I start you two lovebirds off with a couple drinks? 14.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Yes. I'll have my usual.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="SALLY">
         <dialogue> You know what? I'm going to have that too.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Mater blinks. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Uh, right. Your usual. CUT TO:</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  INSIDE AT THE BAR - Fillmore and Sarge watch as Guido mixes drinks, ala &quot;Cocktail.&quot; Mater arrives. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Guido! What's McQueen's usual?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="GUIDO">
         <dialogue> How should I know?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(in Italian, subtitled) </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Perfect! Give me two of `em.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="SARGE">
         <dialogue> Quiet! My program's on.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MEL DORADO (O.S.)">
         <dialogue> Tonight on &quot;The Mel Dorado Show&quot;!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  ON THE BAR TV - &quot;THE MEL DORADO SHOW,&quot; a cable talk show, begins with file footage of MILES AXLEROD, a sleek SUV. </meta>
      <char name="MEL DORADO (ON TV)">
         <dialogue> His story gripped the world! Oil billionaire Miles Axlerod, in an attempt to become the first car to circumnavigate the globe without GPS, ironically ran out of gas and found himself trapped in the wild!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  We see images of newspaper headlines, search crews. </meta>
      <char name="MEL DORADO (ON TV)">
         <dialogue> Feared dead, he emerged 36 days later, running on a fuel he'd distilled himself from the natural elements! Since then he's sold his oil fortune, converted himself from a gas-guzzler into an electric car, and has devoted his life to finding a renewable, clean-burning fuel! 15.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>   Images of oil derricks torn down; Miles Axlerod getting converted to electric; lab scientists testing chemicals. </meta>
      <char name="MEL DORADO (ON TV)">
         <dialogue> Now he claims to have done it with his Allinol.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Images of fields, rivers, vegetables, and mountains all combining to form the Allinol logo. </meta>
      <char name="MEL DORADO (ON TV)">
         <dialogue> And to show the world what his new superfuel can do, he's created a racing competition like no other, inviting the greatest champions from around the globe to battle in the first ever World Grand Prix. Welcome Sir Miles Axlerod.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  SIR MILES AXLEROD arrives, parks across from Mel's desk. </meta>
      <char name="MILES AXLEROD (ON TV)">
         <dialogue> Thank you, Mel. It is very good to be here. Now listen to me: Big Oil. It costs a fortune. Pollution is getting worse. I mean, come on. It's a fossil fuel. Fossil. As in dead dinosaurs. And we all know what happened to them. Alternative energy is the future. Trust me, Mel, after seeing Allinol in action at the World Grand Prix, nobody will ever go back to gasoline again.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> What happened to the dinosaurs, now?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(TO FILLMORE) </meta>
      <char name="MEL DORADO (ON TV)">
         <dialogue> And on satellite, a World Grand Prix competitor and one of the fastest cars in the world, Francesco Bernoulli.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Across the screen: LIVE FROM ROME, ITALY. We meet Formula race car FRANCESCO BERNOULLI. </meta>
      <char name="FRANCESCO (ON TV)">
         <dialogue> It is an honor, Signore Dorado. For you. 16.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="MEL DORADO (ON TV)">
         <dialogue> Miles, why not invite Lightning McQueen?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Mater, collecting his drinks, looks up, half-intrigued. </meta>
      <char name="MILES AXLEROD (ON TV)">
         <dialogue> Of course we invited him. But apparently after a very long racing season he is taking some time off to rest.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FRANCESCO (ON TV)">
         <dialogue> Lightning McQueen would not have a chance against Francesco!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Mater doesn't like this. </meta>
      <char name="FRANCESCO (ON TV)">
         <dialogue> I can go over 300 kilometers an hour! In miles that is like, uh... way faster than McQueen.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MEL DORADO (ON TV)">
         <dialogue> Let's go to the phones. Baltimore, Maryland, you're on the air.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="CALLER (ON TV)">
         <dialogue> Am I on? Hello?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MEL DORADO (ON TV)">
         <dialogue> You're on. Go ahead.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="CALLER (ON TV)">
         <dialogue> Hello?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MEL DORADO (ON TV)">
         <dialogue> Go ahead, caller.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Dial tone. </meta>
      <char name="MEL DORADO (ON TV)">
         <dialogue> Let's go to Radiator Springs. You're on, caller.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER'S VOICE (ON TV)">
         <dialogue> Yeah, that Italian feller you got on there can't talk that way about Lightning McQueen. He's the bestest race car in the whole wide world.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Fillmore and Sarge look around. Mater is visible in the back of the bar on an office phone. 17.  </meta>
      <char name="SARGE">
         <dialogue> Uh-oh...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FRANCESCO (ON TV)">
         <dialogue> If he is, how you say &quot;the bestest race car,&quot; then why must he rest, eh?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER'S VOICE (ON TV)">
         <dialogue> Cause he knows what's important. Every now and then he prefers just to slow down, enjoy life.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FRANCESCO (ON TV)">
         <dialogue> Ah, you heard it! Lightning McQueen prefers to be slow! Of course, this is not news to Francesco. When I want to go to sleep I watch one of his races. After two laps I am out cold.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Audible RXNS from the bar. A crowd has been forming ever since Mater started talking. </meta>
      <char name="MATER'S VOICE (ON TV)">
         <dialogue> That ain't what I meant. CUT TO:</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  MCQUEEN AND SALLY - They hear the commotion inside. </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Hey, what's going on over there? CUT BACK TO:</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  THE BAR - Sally and McQueen push through the crowd, see that they're watching Francesco on the television. </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Oh, it's that Italian Formula car. His name is ---</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(TO SALLY) </meta>
      <char name="SALLY">
         <dialogue> Francesco Bernoulli. No wonder there's a crowd.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  When Sally says his name, she enunciates each part, as if Italian were her mother's tongue. </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Wait, why do you know his name? And don't say it like that. It's three syllables, not ten. 18.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="SALLY">
         <dialogue> What? He's nice to look at. You know, open-wheeled and all.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> What's wrong with fenders? I thought you like my fenders.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER'S VOICE (ON TV)">
         <dialogue> Well let me tell you something else there, Mr. San Francisco ---</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Mater?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER'S VOICE (ON TV)">
         <dialogue> McQueen could drive circles around you.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FRANCESCO (ON TV)">
         <dialogue> Driving in circles is all he can do, no?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER'S VOICE (ON TV)">
         <dialogue> No! I mean yes. I mean he could beat you anywhere, anytime, any track.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  On McQueen - he looks at Guido who gives a nod over to ---  --- Mater, turned away from the crowd, still on the phone. </meta>
      <char name="FRANCESCO (ON TV)">
         <dialogue> Mel, can we move on? Francesco needs a caller who can provide a little more intellectual stimulation. Like a dump truck.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  ON MCQUEEN. He doesn't like this at all. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Ha ha! That shows what you know. Dump trucks is dumb.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Suddenly, Mater is YANKED from the booth and replaced by McQueen. </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN (INTO PHONE)">
         <dialogue> Yeah, hi, this is Lightning McQueen. Look, I don't appreciate my best friend being insulted like that. 19.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="FRANCESCO (ON TV)">
         <dialogue> McQueen! That was your best friend? This is the difference between you and Francesco. Francesco knows how good he is. He does not need to surround himself with tow trucks to prove it.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Those are strong words from a car that is so fragile.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FRANCESCO (ON TV)">
         <dialogue> Fragilé!? He calls Francesco fragilé? Not so fast, McQueen!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> &quot;Not so fast.&quot; What is that, your new motto?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Francesco goes ballistic in Italian. They cut his mic. </meta>
      <char name="MILES AXLEROD (ON TV)">
         <dialogue> Well, this sounds like something that needs to be settled on the race course. What do you say, Lightning McQueen? We've still got room for one more racer.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Well, I would love to. The only thing is my crew's off for the season so ---</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  A sound O.S. McQueen turns to see Fillmore, Sarge and Luigi flank a tablecloth which is hanging off the bar. Ramone backs away, having spray painted &quot;TEAM LIGHTNING MCQUEEN&quot; on it. Guido quickly uncorks three wine bottles. </meta>
      <char name="GUIDO">
         <dialogue> Pit stop.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  McQueen turns back to the phone. </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> You know what? They just got back. Deal me in, baby. Ka-chow!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  The place ERUPTS IN CHEERS.  MOMENTS LATER - General excitement as McQueen exits the phone booth where Sally waits. Off her look: 20.  </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> I know, I know. I just got back. But we won't be long and ---</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="SALLY">
         <dialogue> Oh, no, don't worry about me. I've got enough to do here. Mater's going to have a blast though. You're bringing Mater, right? You never bring him to any of your races.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(off McQueen's silence)  McQueen turns to the bar where Mater privately tries their drinks, hates it, spits it back in the glass. </meta>
      <char name="SALLY">
         <dialogue> Just let him sit in the pits, give him a headset. C'mon, it'll be a thrill of a lifetime for him.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Mater arrives. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Your drinks, sir.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Mater.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> I didn't taste it!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> How'd you like to come and see the world with me?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> You mean it?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> You got me into this thing. You're coming along.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="13">EXT. MUSEUM - TOKYO - NIGHT
</sceneheader>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="14">INT. TOKYO MUSEUM - NIGHT
</sceneheader>
      <meta> Team McQueen enters via a second floor landing which overlooks a massive indoor party in a converted museum. As they roll down a ramp to the party, they are awed. </meta>
      <char name="LUIGI">
         <dialogue> Guido, look! Ferraris and tires! Let's go!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Hey, look at this. Okay now Mater, remember: best behavior.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(IMPRESSED) </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> You got it, buddy. Hey, what's that?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  He sees something, peels away. </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Mater!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="LEWIS HAMILTON">
         <dialogue> Hey, McQueen, over here! 22.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>   It's fellow racers JEFF GORVETTE and LEWIS HAMILTON. McQueen now has no choice but to let Mater go. </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Hey, Jeff. Lewis! CUT TO:</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  MATER as he approaches a GLASS-ENCLOSED ROCK GARDEN where a pitty RAKES rocks with precision. He knocks on the glass with his hook. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Hey! You done good! You got all the leaves!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  People turn at the noise he's making. CUT BACK TO:  MCQUEEN, JEFF and LEWIS. </meta>
      <char name="JEFF GORVETTE">
         <dialogue> Check out that tow truck.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="LEWIS HAMILTON">
         <dialogue> I wonder who that guy's with?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Will you guys excuse me just for one little second?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  He zips over to Mater's side, quickly pulls him out of sight. </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Mater, listen. This isn't Radiator Springs.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> You're just realizing that? Boy, that jet-lag really done a number on you.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Mater, look -- things are different over here. Which means maybe you should, you know, act a little different too.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Different than what?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Well, just... help me out here, buddy. I --- 23.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> You need help? Shoot, why didn't you just say so? That's what a tow truck does. Hey, looky there, it's Mr. San Francisco!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  FRANCESCO is visible across the room, holding court. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> I'll introduce you.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Mater, no.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Look at me -- I'm helping you already!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(already on his way)  On FRANCESCO - MOMENTS LATER. Mater approaches, giddy. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Hey Mr. San Francisco, I'd like you to meet ---</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FRANCESCO">
         <dialogue> Lightning McQueen! Buona sera.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Nice to meet you, Francesco.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FRANCESCO">
         <dialogue> Yeah, nice to meet you too. You are very good-looking. Not as good as I thought, but you're good.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Excuse me. Can I get a picture with you?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(TO FRANCESCO) </meta>
      <char name="FRANCESCO">
         <dialogue> Anything for McQueen's friend.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  As Mater poses for a photo with Francesco: </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Miss Sally is gonna flip when she sees this. She's Lightning McQueen's girlfriend.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FRANCESCO">
         <dialogue> Oooh. 24.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> She's a big fan of yours.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FRANCESCO">
         <dialogue> Hey, she has good taste.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Mater's prone to exaggeration. I wouldn't say she's a &quot;big&quot; fan.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> You're right. She's a huge fan. She goes on and on about your open wheels here.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Mentioning it once doesn't qualify as going &quot;on and on.&quot;</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FRANCESCO">
         <dialogue> Francesco is familiar with this reaction to Francesco. Women respect a car that has nothing to hide.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Yeah, uh...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FRANCESCO">
         <dialogue> Let us have a toast.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  McQueen doesn't like where this is going, covers. </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Let's.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FRANCESCO">
         <dialogue> I dedicate my win tomorrow... to Miss Sally.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(raising a drink) </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Oh, sorry. I already dedicated MY win tomorrow to her. So if we both do it, it's really not so special. Besides, I don't have a drink.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> I'll go get you one. You mind if I borrow a few bucks for one of them drinks? 25.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> They're free, Mater.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(could kill him) </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Free? Well, shoot, what am I doing here?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Mater ZIPS OFF. </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> I should probably go keep an eye on him. See you at the race.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  McQueen starts to leave. </meta>
      <char name="FRANCESCO">
         <dialogue> Yes, you will see Francesco. But not like this.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Francesco does a 180, so his rear end now faces McQueen. </meta>
      <char name="FRANCESCO">
         <dialogue> You will see him like this, as he drives away from you.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Francesco wears a bumper sticker that says &quot;Ciao, McQueen!&quot; </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> That's cute. So you had one of those made up for all the racers?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FRANCESCO">
         <dialogue> No.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Okay.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  He rolls off. </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> He is so getting beat tomorrow.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="15">INT. PARTY - MOMENTS LATER
</sceneheader>
      <meta> Lights caress the main stage where a crowd has formed. </meta>
      <char name="VOICE">
         <dialogue> Ladies and gentlecars... Sir Miles Axlerod!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  MILES AXLEROD drives through an infinity fountain, appears. 26.  </meta>
      <char name="MILES AXLEROD">
         <dialogue> It is my absolute honor to introduce to you the competitors in the first-ever World Grand Prix. From Brazil. Number eight...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  ON FINN MCMISSILE. He appears from the shadows, keeps a careful distance from the stage. He ZEROES HIS GAZE ON ---  --- THE WORLD GRAND PRIX TV CAMERAS which roll, catching Miles Axlerod's speech for publicity and posterity.  Finn's ONBOARD COMPUTER ANALYZES each one, compares to the photos we saw him snap on the oil platform. Each one is &quot;NOT A MATCH.&quot; His view is suddenly disrupted by A BEAUTIFUL SPORTS CAR. She approaches Finn. Meet HOLLEY SHIFTWELL. </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> A Volkswagen Karmann Ghia has no radiator.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> That's because it's air-cooled.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> I'm Agent Shiftwell, Holley Shiftwell from the Tokyo Station. I have a message from London.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Not here. You must try the canapes on the mezzanine!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(LOUDLY)  He moves her onto an elevator. The doors close on them. </meta>
      <char name="IN THE ELEVATOR, GOING UP.">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> So the lab boys analyzed the photo I sent? What did they learn about the camera?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> It appears to be a standard television camera. They said if you could get closer photos next time, that would be great.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> This was London's message? 27.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Oh -- no, no. No sir. Um, the oil platforms you were on? Turns out they're sitting on the biggest oil reserve in the world.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> How did we miss that?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> They'd been scrambling everyone's satellites. The Americans actually discovered it just before you did. They placed an agent on that platform, under deep cover. He was able to get a photo of the car who's running the entire operation.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  The doors OPEN and they exit onto the Mezzanine. </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Who is it? Has anyone seen the photo yet?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> No, not yet. The American is here tonight to pass it to you. He'll signal you when he's ready.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> GOOD ---</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Finn suddenly STOPS COLD. </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Oh no.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Professor Zundapp is visible below them. He talks with a few Pacers and Gremlins. Finn quickly retreats into the shadows. Holley follows suit. </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> What is it?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Change of plan. You're meeting the American.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> What, me? 28.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Those thugs down there were on the oil platform. If they see me, the whole mission is compromised.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> No, no. I'm technical, you see. I'm in Diagnostics. I'm not a field agent.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> You are now. CUT TO:</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  MATER as he grabs a drink, keeps moving. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> I'll take one of them.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  He snatches it, drops it in the back where we now see a large assortment of drinks balanced. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Never know which one McQueen'll have a hankering for.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  He approaches a sushi bar. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Hey, what you got here that's free? How about that pistachio ice cream?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  He refers to wasabi, of course. </meta>
      <char name="SUSHI CHEF">
         <dialogue> No, no. Wasabi.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Oh, same ol', same ol'. What's up with you? That looks delicious.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  The chef starts to carve a small scoop aside for Mater. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Uh, a little more, please. It is free, right? Keep it coming. A little more. Come on, let's go, it's free! You're getting there... Scoop scoop!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(the chef adds more)  The chef gives in. Scoops a baseball-sized ball out. 29.  </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> There you go. Now THAT's a scoop of ice cream.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="SUSHI CHEF">
         <dialogue> My condolences. CUT BACK TO:</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(in Japanese, subtitles)  MILES AXLEROD - He's now nearly done with his intros. </meta>
      <char name="MILES AXLEROD">
         <dialogue> ... and now, our last competitor --- Number 95, Lightning McQueen!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  MCQUEEN approaches the microphone, flashes his headlights. </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Thank you so much for having us, Sir Axlerod. I really look forward to racing. This is a great opportunity.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MILES AXLEROD">
         <dialogue> Oh, the pleasure is all ours, Lightning. You and your team bring excellence and professionalism to this competition.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  As if on cue, Mater arrives with a piercing scream of pain. Everyone turns as he charges head first toward the stage, making a bee-line for that FOUNTAIN. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Somebody get me water!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  He laps up water from the fountain like a diabetic cat. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Sweet relief...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(LAPPING WATER)  Miles Axlerod is shocked. The crowd can't believe it. Francesco cackles. Mater, now sated, approaches the mic. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Whatever you do, do not eat the free pistachio ice cream. It has turned!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(to the crowd) </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Sir Axlerod, I can explain. This is Mater. 30.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="MILES AXLEROD">
         <dialogue> I know him. This is the bloke that called into the television show. You're the one I have to thank.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(TO MATER) </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> No, thank you. This trip's been amazing.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MILES AXLEROD">
         <dialogue> He's a little excited, isn't he?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(TO MCQUEEN)  TILT DOWN to reveal a pool of oil beneath Mater. </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Mater!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> But wait, I... oh, shoot.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  McQueen quickly pulls Mater aside, out of earshot of Miles Axlerod and the others. McQueen is beside himself. </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Mater, you have to get a hold of yourself. You're making a scene.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> But I never leak oil. Never.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Go take care of yourself right now.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Mater drives off. </meta>
      <char name="ON MATER - MOMENTS LATER">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
      <meta>  He drives through the party, frantic. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Coming through! Excuse me, leakin' oil. Where's the bathroom? Thank you. I gotta go!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Someone points Mater down a hallway. He whips around the</meta>
      <char name="CORNER ---">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
      <meta>  --- and STOPS. Finds himself in front of TWO BATHROOM DOORS, neither of which clearly indicate MALE or FEMALE. 31.  </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> What the...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(CONFUSED)  Mater chooses one, drives inside. A SHRIEK is heard and Mater zips out. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Sorry ladies!</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="16">INT. MEN'S ROOM - NIGHT
</sceneheader>
      <meta> Mater rolls in, still `holding it in' like a kid. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> I never leak I never leak I never leak...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  He sees someone leaving a stall. He heads in.  IN THE STALL - Mater enters, looks up. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Wowee...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  The stall is a complicated apparatus with buttons and lights. High-tech Japanese. It suddenly GRABS MATER, hoists him up as if he's going to get an oil change. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> What in the---</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  A Japanese style cartoon CARICATURE appears on a TV MONITOR, followed by images of waterfalls and rivers. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Hey, that tickles.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(GIGGLING)  The caricature starts talking in Japanese. Suddenly WATER FIRES UP underneath Mater's undercarriage, goosing him. He freaks out.  OUTSIDE THE STALL - With Mater's yells audible we see a GREMLIN enter, furtive. Suddenly, inexplicably, his frame BREAKS APART like an egg, revealing an AMERICAN MUSCLE CAR underneath. The pieces of the Gremlin disappear under him, clearly his disguise. This is ROD REDLINE - American Agent. 32.  </meta>
      <char name="ROD REDLINE">
         <dialogue> Okay, McMissile. I'm here. It's time for the drop.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="17">INT. PARTY - SAME
</sceneheader>
      <meta> HOLLEY, rolls along by herself. Nervous. DING! Her rearview monitor springs to life. </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY (INTO RADIO)">
         <dialogue> The American has activated his tracking beacon.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN (OVER RADIO)">
         <dialogue> Roger that. Move in.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="18">INT. BATHROOM - SAME
</sceneheader>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="19">INT. PARTY - SAME
</sceneheader>
      <meta> Holley isolates the tracking beacon's location in the party. </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Oh, you've got to be joking.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> What's the problem, Shiftwell?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> He's in the loo. 33.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> So go in!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> I can't just go into the men's loo.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Time is of the essence, Shiftwell.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="20">INT. BATHROOM - OUTSIDE THE STALL
</sceneheader>
      <meta> Rod Redline is in bad shape. He backs away, betrays a look of concern. He's in trouble here.  ACER burns rubber, ready to finish him off. Just as he shifts into DRIVE ---  --- MATER'S STALL DOOR KICKS OPEN, knocking ACER out. Mater jumps out, face-to-face GREM. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Whatever you do, I would not go in there.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(out of breath)  The door SWINGS shut, revealing the pulverized Acer. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> A Gremlin and a Pacer!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Rod Redline, now behind Mater and sensing an opportunity here, quickly produces A SMALL DEVICE. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> No offense to your makes and models, but you guys break down harder than my cousin Betsy after she got left at the ---</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(to Grem and Acer)  Rod Redline, surreptitiously attaches the device to Mater's undercarriage. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> --- altar!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(as he's goosed)  He spins around, sees Rod Redline for the first time. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Are you okay?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="ROD REDLINE">
         <dialogue> I'm fine. 34.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="GREM">
         <dialogue> Hey. Tow truck.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Mater turns back to Grem and Acer. </meta>
      <char name="GREM">
         <dialogue> We'd like to get to our private business here, if you don't mind.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Oh, yeah. Don't let me get in the way of your &quot;private business.&quot; Oh! A little advice: When you hear her giggle and see that waterfall, you best press that green button.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="GREM">
         <dialogue> Thank you.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> It's to adjust the temperature.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="ACER">
         <dialogue> Got it.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Remember it's in Celsius, not Fahrenheit.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="GREM AND ACER">
         <dialogue> Get outta here!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Alright then.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="21">EXT. BATHROOM - MOMENTS LATER
</sceneheader>
      <meta> Holley arrives at the door. She takes a breath, is about to enter when Mater EXITS. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Excuse me, ma'am.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  He passes her, expelling some exhaust in the process. Holley's rearview tracking confirms that the device is on him. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Dadgum pistachio ice cream. 35.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(TO HIMSELF)  </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY (INTO RADIO)">
         <dialogue> This cannot be him.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN (OVER RADIO)">
         <dialogue> Is he American?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Look out, ladies. Mater's fittin' to get funky!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(driving off, to himself) </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY (INTO RADIO)">
         <dialogue> Extremely.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN (OVER RADIO)">
         <dialogue> Then it's him.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  It's settled. Holley takes one more nervous breath, quickly closes the distance between her and Mater, cuts him off. He is forced to STOP. </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Hello.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Well, hello.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> A Volkswagen Karmann Ghia has no radiator.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Well of course it doesn't. That's `cause it's air-cooled!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Perfect. I'm from the Tokyo Station OF THE---</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(RELIEVED) </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Course, Karmann Ghia's weren't the only ones. Besides the Beetles you had your Type-3 Squarebacks, with the pancake motors...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Yeah. Okay, I get it---</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> ... And before both of them, there's the Type-2 buses - my buddy Fillmore's one of them. 36.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Listen! We should find somewhere more private.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Uh, gee. Don't you think that's a little, uh ---</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> You're right. Impossible to know which areas here are compromised. So, when can I see you again?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(NERVOUS ENERGY) </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Well, let's see. Tomorrow I'll be out there at the races.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Got it. We'll rendezvous then.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="22">INT. PARTY - MOMENTS LATER
</sceneheader>
      <meta> Mater returns to his team, lost in thought. </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> There you are. Where have you been?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> What's a rendezvous?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="LUIGI">
         <dialogue> It's like a date.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> A date?!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Mater, what's going on?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Well, what's going on is I've got me a date tomorrow.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Guido makes a crack in Italian. </meta>
      <char name="LUIGI">
         <dialogue> Guido don't believe you.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Well, believe it. My new girlfriend just said so. Hey, there she is.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Mater points out Holley, who's within earshot. 37.  </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Hey! Hey lady!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(YELLING)  Holley, caught in plain view, DRIVES OFF. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> See ya tomorrow!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Guido makes another crack in Italian. </meta>
      <char name="LUIGI">
         <dialogue> Guido still don't believe you.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="23">EXT. SHIPYARD - THE DOCKS - TOKYO NIGHT
</sceneheader>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="24">INT. SHIPYARD - NIGHT
</sceneheader>
      <meta> Rod Redline dangles from a car magnet. He's been beaten up, clings to consciousness. </meta>
      <char name="GREM (O.S.)">
         <dialogue> I gotta admit ---</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Grem, Acer, and a bunch of nasty looking troublemakers look up at Rod amidst crates and shipping containers. </meta>
      <char name="GREM">
         <dialogue> --- you tricked us real good.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="ACER">
         <dialogue> And we don't like being tricked.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Rod Redline laughs to himself. </meta>
      <char name="ACER">
         <dialogue> Hey, what's so funny?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="ROD REDLINE">
         <dialogue> Well, you know, I was just wearing a disguise. You guys are stuck looking like that.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  This doesn't help him. They DROP HIM onto a TREADMILL, lock him down. A container is wheeled forward and Rod is plied with Allinol brand gasoline. </meta>
      <char name="ROD REDLINE">
         <dialogue> Allinol? Thanks, fellas. I hear this stuff is good for you. 38.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="PROFESSOR ZUNDAPP (O.S.)">
         <dialogue> So you think.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  The Professor emerges from the darkness, behind Rod. </meta>
      <char name="PROFESSOR ZUNDAPP">
         <dialogue> Allinol by itself is good for you.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Zundapp hits a button and the TREADMILL starts Rod's wheels spinning at a high rate of speed. </meta>
      <char name="PROFESSOR ZUNDAPP">
         <dialogue> But after microscopic examination, I have found that it has one small weakness. When hit with an electromagnetic pulse, it becomes extremely dangerous.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="GREM">
         <dialogue> SMILE ---</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Grem pushes a World Grand Prix CAMERA - the same one that was in the box back at the oil derrick. He points it at Rod Redline. </meta>
      <char name="GREM">
         <dialogue> --- for the camera.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="ROD REDLINE">
         <dialogue> Is that all you want? I got a whole act.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="PROFESSOR ZUNDAPP">
         <dialogue> You were very interested in this camera on the oil platform. Now you will witness what it really does.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="ROD REDLINE">
         <dialogue> Whatever you say, Professor.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Acer pushes a TV MONITOR toward Rod. On it, surveillance footage from the party. Clearly, they were watching and recording him there. </meta>
      <char name="ACER">
         <dialogue> You talked up a lot of cars last night. Which one's your associate?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="ROD REDLINE">
         <dialogue> Your mother. Oh no, I'm sorry. It was your sister. You know, I can't tell them apart these days. 39.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="GREM">
         <dialogue> Could I start it now, Professor?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(HAD ENOUGH) </meta>
      <char name="PROFESSOR ZUNDAPP">
         <dialogue> Fifty percent power. This camera is actually an electromagnetic pulse emitter.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(to Rod Redline) </meta>
      <char name="ACER">
         <dialogue> What about her? Did you give it to her?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(re: a girl on the TV) </meta>
      <char name="PROFESSOR ZUNDAPP">
         <dialogue> The Allinol is now heating to a boil, dramatically expanding, causing the engine block to crack under the stress, forcing oil into the combustion chamber.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Rod Redline's engine starts to CRACK and BREAK. </meta>
      <char name="ACER">
         <dialogue> How about him? You talk to him?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(re: a guy on the TV) </meta>
      <char name="ROD REDLINE">
         <dialogue> What do I care? I can replace an engine block.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(to Professor Zundapp) </meta>
      <char name="PROFESSOR ZUNDAPP">
         <dialogue> You may be able to, but after full impact of the pulse, unfortunately, there will be nothing to replace.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="ACER">
         <dialogue> How about him? Does he have it?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  The monitor reveals MATER, rolling out of the bathroom and down the hall.  Rod Redline, seeing this, does the world's most subtle double take. We caught it, but there's no way anyone else in the room could have --- </meta>
      <char name="PROFESSOR ZUNDAPP">
         <dialogue> That's him. He's the one.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="GREM">
         <dialogue> Roger that, Professor Z. 40.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="ROD REDLINE">
         <dialogue> No!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  As Grem turns up the machine even MORE, the Professor makes a call. </meta>
      <char name="PROFESSOR ZUNDAPP (INTO PHONE)">
         <dialogue> Yes sir. We believe the infiltrator has passed along sensitive information. I will take care of it before any damage can be done.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(beat, listening)  The Professor hangs up, turns to the room. </meta>
      <char name="PROFESSOR ZUNDAPP">
         <dialogue> The project is still on schedule. You will find this second agent ---</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Zundapp kicks the camera's power into the RED. </meta>
      <char name="PROFESSOR ZUNDAPP">
         <dialogue> --- and kill him.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="25">EXT. JAPAN - DAY
</sceneheader>
      <meta> Over television pre-roll of Japan: </meta>
      <char name="BRENT MUSTANGBURGER (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> Japan. Land of the rising sun. Where ancient tradition meets modern technology. Welcome to the inaugural running of the World Grand Prix.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  ON OUR ANNOUNCERS as they introduce themselves: </meta>
      <char name="BRENT MUSTANGBURGER">
         <dialogue> I'm Brent Mustangburger, here with racing legends Darrell Cartrip and David Hobbscap. There's never been a competition like this before.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  SHOTS OF THE PITS as the racers fuel up. </meta>
      <char name="BRENT MUSTANGBURGER (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> First, Allinol, making its debut tonight as the required fuel for all these great champions. 41.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(MORE) </meta>
      <char name="BRENT MUSTANGBURGER (V.O.) (CONT'D)">
         <dialogue> Second, the course itself, and it's like nothing we've ever seen. David, how exactly does this competition work?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="DAVID HOBBSCAP (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> Well, Brent, all three of these street courses are classic round- the-house racetracks.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  OUTLINES OF THREE RACE COURSES are shown. They're labeled Japan, Italy and England, and are different in shape and size. </meta>
      <char name="DAVID HOBBSCAP (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> This means that the LMP and Formula cars should break out of the gate in spectacular fashion.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  SHOTS OF THE RACERS as they weave up the track, practicing. </meta>
      <char name="DAVID HOBBSCAP (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> Look for Francesco Bernoulli in particular to lead early.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  SHOTS OF Francesco, featured in an inset. </meta>
      <char name="DAVID HOBBSCAP (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> And with a series of technical turns throughout ---</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  MORE SHOTS of the course, now highlighting the tech turns. </meta>
      <char name="DAVID HOBBSCAP (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> GT and Touring cars like Spain's Miguel Camino should make up some ground but I doubt it'll be enough to stop Francesco from absolutely running away with it.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="DARRELL CARTRIP (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> Woah, now just hold your horsepower. You're forgetting the most important factor here. That early dirt track section of the course! The dirt is supposed to be the great equalizer in this race.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  GRAPHICS OF THE COURSES now isolate a stretch after the first couple turns, label it &quot;DIRT SECTIONS.&quot; 42.  </meta>
      <char name="BRENT MUSTANGBURGER (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> French Rally car Raoul ÇaRoule is counting on a big boost headed through there.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="DARRELL CARTRIP (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> And don't forget Lightning McQueen! His mentor, the Hudson Hornet, was one of the greatest dirt track racers of all time. In my opinion, McQueen is the best all-around racer in this competition.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="BACK IN THE STUDIO">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="DAVID HOBBSCAP">
         <dialogue> Really, Darrell, I think you need to clean your windshield. You're clearly not seeing this for what it is: Francesco's race to lose.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="26">EXT. STARTING LINE - DAY
</sceneheader>
      <meta/>
      <char name="BRENT MUSTANGBURGER (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> It's time to find out. The racers are locking into the grid ---</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Engines rev as everyone gets ready to go. Everyone's bright eyed and alert except for McQueen who we find in the back of the grid. He CLOSES his eyes. </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Speed. I am speed.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(TO HIMSELF)  A LAUGH O.S. McQueen opens his eyes. Francesco is next to him on the grid. </meta>
      <char name="FRANCESCO">
         <dialogue> Really? You are &quot;speed&quot;? Then Francesco is triple speed. Francesco. Is. Triple speed. Francesco likes this, McQueen. It's really getting him into the zone!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(closes his eyes) </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> He is so getting beat today.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  The starting lights click down from RED to YELLOW to GREEN. The race begins. Francesco quickly grabs the lead. He's pulling away within seconds. 43.   ON PIT ROW - We TRACK PAST as the various Crew Chiefs on their crash carts bark orders to their racers. We end on Team McQueen. No Crew Chief, just a solid looking team. </meta>
      <char name="SARGE">
         <dialogue> His suspension stats look good.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="LUIGI">
         <dialogue> Tire pressure is excellent.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FILLMORE">
         <dialogue> He's got plenty of fuel.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> And he's awesome! CUT TO:</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  The same view of Mater but now THROUGH A TELESCOPIC DISPLAY. Reveal Finn and Holley watching from high above in a downtown office building, behind reflective glass. </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Why is he in the pits? He's so exposed.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> It's his cover. One of the best I've seen, too. Look at the detail on that rust. It must have cost him a fortune.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> But why hasn't he contacted us yet?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> There's probably heat on him. Be patient.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Right, of course. He'll signal us when he can.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> And then we find out who's behind all this.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  ON THE TRACK - VARIOUS SHOTS OF THE RACE through Tokyo as Francesco extends his lead and McQueen attempts to make up ground. 44.   IN MCQUEEN'S PIT - Mater watches the monitors, sees them approaching the dirt section. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> McQueen! It's time to make your move. Get on the outside and show 'em what Doc done taught you.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN (OVER RADIO)">
         <dialogue> Ten four, Mater.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  ON THE TRACK - Francesco hits the dirt section and loses all control. He SLAMS to a halt, his tires getting no traction. </meta>
      <char name="DAVID HOBBSCAP (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> Francesco is brought to a screeching halt!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  MCQUEEN skids into view, turning right to go left, passing Francesco, followed by other cars --- </meta>
      <char name="BRENT MUSTANGBURGER (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> Lightning McQueen is the first to take advantage. And just like that, folks, Francesco's lead is left in the dust.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Nice call, Mater. Keep it up!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  McQueen now leads the pack, zooming out of the dirt now starting to relax. </meta>
      <char name="DARRELL CARTRIP (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> Who-hoo! Man, McQueen looks happier than a rollbar at a demolition derby!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="ON PAVED ROAD AGAIN - MOMENTS LATER">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
      <meta>  The field of cars thunders into a tunnel. </meta>
      <char name="BRENT MUSTANGBURGER (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> Everyone's jostling for position as we hit the asphalt again.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Francesco crests the hill, in last place. He bites down, determined, then CHASES. </meta>
      <char name="BRENT MUSTANGBURGER (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> Francesco lost a lot of momentum in the dirt. He's got some serious work ahead of him if he wants to get back in this race. 45.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>   VARIOUS SHOTS OF TOKYO as the racers move through the Rainbow Bridge. Bit by bit, Francesco ekes his way toward the front, toward Lightning McQueen as we CUT TO ---  --- A ROOFTOP, and a VIEW THROUGH THE WGP CAMERA LENS. Grem and Acer are manning this one. They focus it on the racers as they approach. </meta>
      <char name="PROFESSOR ZUNDAPP (OVER RADIO)">
         <dialogue> It is time.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="GREM">
         <dialogue> Roger that.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  ON THE TRACK - A racer (Miguel Camino) suddenly PLUMES WITH SMOKE and skids out. </meta>
      <char name="DARRELL CARTRIP (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> Oh! Miguel Camino has blown an engine!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="BRENT MUSTANGBURGER (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> Very unusual, Darrell. He's been so consistent all year.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Camino quickly pits, passing McQueen's pit where Mater is visible.  ON GREM AND ACER, watching from above. </meta>
      <char name="GREM">
         <dialogue> You gotta be kidding me.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="ACER">
         <dialogue> What is it?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="GREM">
         <dialogue> It's that tow truck from the bathroom.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="ACER">
         <dialogue> The one from the bathroom?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="GREM">
         <dialogue> Yeah, the one the American Agent passed the device to.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="ACER">
         <dialogue> What about him?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="GREM">
         <dialogue> What about him? He's in the pits! 46.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="ACER">
         <dialogue> Not for long.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Acer exits, with purpose.  ON FINN AND HOLLEY, still in their office hideaway. Holley's onboard computer flashes an ALERT. </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Hold on. I think I've got something.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> What is it?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> The Pacer from the party last night.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  She's spotted Acer, moving swiftly forward. </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Cross-referencing with the photos from the oil derricks... Yep. His VIN numbers match.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Anyone with him? He won't be alone.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Conducting analysis on the target.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  The computer finds more and more bad guy Pacers and Gremlins are in the crowd. </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> He's not the only one here. Three... five... they're everywhere. And they're all closing in on... oh no.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  We PAN OVER to see it's MATER. </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Finn? Finn, where are you?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  She turns. He's GONE, leaving only an open window. </meta>
      <char name="FINN (OVER RADIO)">
         <dialogue> Get him out of the pits now!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  IN MCQUEEN'S PIT. A car WHIPS BY O.S. 47.  </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Wow! Some of them fellers is really loud.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY (OVER MATER'S RADIO)">
         <dialogue> Can you hear me? Over.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Uh, what?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY (OVER MATER'S RADIO)">
         <dialogue> Get out of the pit now. Do you hear me?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Mater realizes this girl has somehow broken into his radio. </meta>
      <char name="MATER (INTO RADIO)">
         <dialogue> Hey, I know you. You're that girl from the party last night. You wanna do our date right now?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  ON THE TRACK - McQueen boxes out Francesco, holds his slim lead, but barely. </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Guys, a little too much chatter. Let's keep this line clear.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  BOOM! A racer behind McQueen suddenly expels black smoke, skids out of control.  ON GREM - laughing. That was clearly his handiwork. </meta>
      <char name="IN MCQUEEN'S PIT - SAME">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY (ON MATER'S RADIO)">
         <dialogue> There's no time for messing about. You've got to get out of the pits.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Is there gonna be cable where you is so I can watch the rest of the race?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  ON HOLLEY - Watching from the downtown building. </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY (INTO RADIO)">
         <dialogue> You're running out of time!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN (OVER RADIO)">
         <dialogue> They're coming, Shiftwell.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY (INTO RADIO)">
         <dialogue> Yes, I know. 48.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="FINN (OVER RADIO)">
         <dialogue> Get him out of there.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> I'm trying. Get out now!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(TO MATER)  We CUT BACK TO ---  --- MATER. He gives in, exits the pit. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Well, all right but I usually like to have a proper detailing done before I meet a lady friend.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  He moves toward the back PIT DOOR, is about to open it.  OUTSIDE THE PITS - ACER and another Pacer approach McQueen's pit door on the other side. Ready to pounce. The doors OPEN,</meta>
      <char name="REVEALING ---">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
      <meta>  --- Finn, holding a fire extinguisher. </meta>
      <char name="ACER">
         <dialogue> Finn McMissile? But you're dead!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Then this shouldn't hurt at all.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  He empties the extinguisher in their eyes, speeds past. They try and follow, but have been blinded. One of them crashes right into a COP.  ON FINN - Already on the move, along a side street. </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Miss Shiftwell?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  ON HOLLEY - Tracking everything on a grid map. Mater looks like Pac Man, weaving through the streets as bad guys close in all around him. </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> I've got him in the back alleys east of the garages. Multiple assailants are closing in quickly.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN (OVER RADIO)">
         <dialogue> Keep him moving. I'm on my way.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  ON MATER - He turns a corner, sees a flower shop. 49.  </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Hey, new lady friend? You like flowers?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  ON THE TRACK - McQueen, hearing this, is taken aback. </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> What?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  ON MATER - Slowing at the flower shop. </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY (OVER RADIO)">
         <dialogue> No! Don't go 'in' anywhere. Just keep moving.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Stay outside. Gotcha.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="ON THE TRACK">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Outside?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  McQueen drifts outside allowing Francesco to slip past! </meta>
      <char name="FRANCESCO">
         <dialogue> Grazie and arrivaderci!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="DARRELL CARTRIP (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> I cannot believe what I just saw, Brent. That was a bonehead move. You don't open up the inside like that!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  IN THE BACK ALLEYS - As Mater moves on he's followed by Pacers and Gremlins. Suddenly ---  --- CABLES whip in front of them, pulling over flower vending machines and sending the shop's owners into a frenzy. They direct their attention to the AMCs, who try and explain.  ON FINN, admiring his handiwork as he appears. Just as he turns to leave he's BROADSIDED and pushed INTO A DARK ALLEY.  IN THE ALLEY - Finn finds himself boxed by two Pacers and pushed toward ---  --- ACER, who now holds a FLAME THROWER. </meta>
      <char name="ACER">
         <dialogue> This time I'm gonna make sure you stay dead.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  He hits the flame. WHOOOSSSH!! 50.   ON ANOTHER STREET - Mater clicks along, still looking for Holley. Just as he passes the alley entrance where Finn stares down death: </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY (OVER RADIO)">
         <dialogue> You're doing brilliantly. Now just stay focused.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> What's that? You want me to head toward that ruckus?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Mater turns INTO the alley. </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY (OVER RADIO)">
         <dialogue> No! Don't go down that street!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  IN THE ALLEY - Finn, now nearly pushed completely into the flame thrower, leaps into the air. He FIGHTS BACK, using his wheels, axle, indeed his entire car frame as if he were human, kicking and tossing and shooting his enemies.  Mater witnesses the whole thing. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Wow! A live karate demonstration!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  ON THE TRACK - McQueen, now playing catch-up again, scowls. </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Stop it, Mater. Just sign off.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  IN THE BACK ALLEY - Finn polishes off the AMCs by firing a bullet into a gas main line, causing an EXPLOSION that tosses Acer through the air where he lands in a NOODLE SHOP'S SIGN.  ON THE TRACK - The end of the race is nigh --- </meta>
      <char name="BRENT MUSTANGBURGER (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> They're bumper to bumper as they approach the finish line!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  The Formula car gets there first. </meta>
      <char name="BRENT MUSTANGBURGER (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> Francesco's the winner, McQueen's number two!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  IN THE ALLEY - Finn heaves breaths, surveys his damage. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> That was cool! Hey, can I get your autograph? 51.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>   Mater approaches when a MASS OF RACE FANS burst out a door, momentarily blocking Mater's view of Finn. Once the fans have past, Finn has disappeared. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Hey, where'd he go?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY (OVER RADIO)">
         <dialogue> Our rendezvous has been jeopardized. Keep the device safe. We'll be in touch.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Dadgum, did I miss our date?</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="27">EXT. PRESS STAGE - LATER
</sceneheader>
      <meta> Post race press conference. Francesco is center stage. </meta>
      <char name="DARRELL CARTRIP">
         <dialogue> Francesco, over here! Hey, what was your strategy today?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FRANCESCO">
         <dialogue> Strategia? Francesco needs no strategy, it's very simple. You start the race, wait for Lightning McQueen to choke, pass him, then win. Francesco always wins. It's boring.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  McQueen, waiting in the wings, rolls his eyes. He suddenly notices something O.S.  McQueen's P.O.V. - It's MATER, appearing from a side street, moving toward the pits, oblivious of the press conference. </meta>
      <char name="DARRELL CARTRIP">
         <dialogue> I gotta tell you, dude. You were in trouble for awhile. That dirt track section had you crawling!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(TO FRANCESCO)  As McQueen SNEAKS AWAY --- </meta>
      <char name="FRANCESCO">
         <dialogue> To truly crush one's dream, you must first raise their hopes very high.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  IN MCQUEEN'S PIT GARAGE - Mater looks around for everyone as McQueen approaches. 52.  </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Mater.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Hey McQueen! What happened? Is the race over? You won, right?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Mater, why were you yelling things at me while I was racing?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Yelling? Oh, you thought... that's funny right there. Nah, see that's `cause I seen these two fellers doing some sort of karate street performance. It was nutso. One of them even had a flamethrower ---</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> A flamethrower? What are you talking about? I don't understand. Where were you?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Going to meet my date.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Your date?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> She started talking to me as a voice in my head, telling me where to go ---</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> What?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Wait a minute -- I didn't screw you up, did I?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> I lost the race because of you!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Well, I'm sorry. I didn't mean ---</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> An imaginary girlfriend, flamethrowers. This is exactly why I don't bring you along to these things. 53.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Maybe if I, I don't know, talked to somebody and explained what happened I could help.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> I don't need your help. I don't want your help.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="PRESS (O.S.)">
         <dialogue> Hey, there he is!!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  The press finds McQueen, swarms him. Mater is pushed backwards as the questions fly again. </meta>
      <char name="PRESS">
         <dialogue> - McQueen, you had it in the bag! - Yeah, what happened?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> I made a mistake. But I can assure you, it won't happen again.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  On Mater. He takes this badly. </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Look, guys. We know what the problem is and we've taken care of it. SMASH TO:</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  OVER FOOTAGE OF FRANCESCO and various other highlights: </meta>
      <char name="BRENT MUSTANGBURGER">
         <dialogue> Lightning McQueen loses in the last lap to Francesco Bernoulli in the first race of the World Grand Prix and three, count em, three cars flamed out leading some to suggest that their fuel, Allinol, might be to blame.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  FOOTAGE OF MILES AXLEROD, speaking to an aggressive press. He must SHOUT over the press. </meta>
      <char name="MILES AXLEROD">
         <dialogue> Allinol is safe! Alternative fuel is safe! There is no way my fuel caused these cars to flame out! 54.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>   IN THE TV STUDIO - Darrell, Brent and David talk to camera. </meta>
      <char name="DARRELL CARTRIP">
         <dialogue> Well the jury may still be out on whether Allinol caused these accidents, but one thing's for sure: Lightning McQueen blew this race.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Off a FROZEN IMAGE of McQueen crossing the finish line, a look of severe consternation across his face --- </meta>
      <char name="BRENT MUSTANGBURGER">
         <dialogue> Team McQueen can't be happy right now.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="28">INT. AIRPORT - JAPAN - DAY
</sceneheader>
      <meta> --- McQueen's SMILING FACE, on a Team McQueen poster.  REVERSE to reveal Mater looking at it, sadly. He drives on, passing (but not noticing) ---  --- GREM and ACER.  AT THE SECURITY CHECK - MOMENTS LATER. Cars take off their tires, move through the metal detector. Mater waits in line. A SECURITY CAR approaches Mater. </meta>
      <char name="SECURITY CAR">
         <dialogue> Come with me please, sir.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(in Japanese and English) </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> But I'm gonna miss my plane.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  IN THE ADMIRAL'S LOUNGE - MOMENTS LATER. The Security Car leads Mater inside. </meta>
      <char name="SECURITY CAR">
         <dialogue> Right this way.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  As they move past us the Security Car covertly drops a BALL BEARING which rolls into a corner. The ball bearing then sprouts MECHANICAL LEGS, tripods itself and IRISES out, revealing itself to be a tiny CAMERA. </meta>
      <char name="IN THE MAIN ROOM - ADMIRAL'S LOUNGE - CONTINUOUS">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
      <meta>  Mater follows the Security Car in, nervous. 55.  </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Doggone it. This is about my hook, isn't it? I know I should've checked it, but I can't really, look -- it's attached to me.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  ZWAPPPPPP!! The Security Car suddenly DECLOAKS himself, reveals himself to be Finn McMissile! </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Hey, I know you. You're that feller from the karate demonstration.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> I never properly introduced myself. Finn McMissile. British Intelligence.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Tow Mater. Average intelligence.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Who are you with? FBI, CIA?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Let's just say I'm triple-A affiliated. You know, I know some karate. I don't wanna brag or nothing, but I've got me a black fan belt.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  BEEP! Finn's rearview alarms. His camera has picked up Grem and Acer. They've just entered the lounge, are right around the corner. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Hey, you wanna see some moves I made up?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> You're being followed.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Finn quickly turns, fires a tiny GLASS CUTTING BEETLE at the window. As Mater talks, oblivious, the beetle cuts out a round hole. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> This first one I can reach into a car's hood, pull out his battery, and show it to him before he stalls. I call it, &quot;What I accidentally did to my friend Luigi once.&quot; 56.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>   Mater does his best (worst) karate moves as Acer and Grem turn the corner. </meta>
      <char name="GREM">
         <dialogue> There he is!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  The glass drops away, leaving a car-sized hole. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Look, I probably ought to go. I'm about to miss my flight.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(eyes the clock) </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Don't worry.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Finn HOOKS Mater from behind. He YANKS HIM forward --- </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> I've taken care of that. Hang on.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="29">EXT. TARMAC - AIRPORT - JAPAN
</sceneheader>
      <meta> Finn pulls Mater down HARD onto the tarmac, towing him away from the terminal. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> This is First Class service. You don't even have to go through the terminal.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  ACER and GREM appear, chasing them. Mater, who is facing backward as he is being pulled along, faces them. They're about a hundred yards back. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Your karate partners are back here. They kinda look like they're trying to catch up!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(TO FINN) </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Drive forward. Whatever you do, don't stop.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Finn SKIDS around, whipping Mater in a 180 so that Mater is now towing Finn.  Grem produces a ROCKET, lines up Finn as his target. 57.   Finn, without hesitation, fires a MINI ROLLING-JACK. The jack DRIVES ITSELF toward Grem, anchors itself under his frame and flips him like a turtle but not before Grem gets the rocket</meta>
      <char name="OFF ---">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
      <meta>  THE ROCKET - it flies toward Mater and Finn.  FINN aims and launches a MISSILE back. </meta>
      <char name="THE ROCKET AND MISSILE COLLIDE IN MID-AIR, EXPLODE.">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Is everything okay back there?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(only hearing this) </meta>
      <char name="SIDDELEY (O.S.)">
         <dialogue> Finn, it's Sid. I'm on approach.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  A GULFSTREAM JET wings into view overhead. This is SIDDELEY. </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Roger that.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Mater looks up: ACER screeches into view up ahead, dragging a long row of luggage carts in Mater's path, attempting to create an accident. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> You remember that whole thing about me not stopping no matter what?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(TO FINN)  Just as it looks dire --- RATATATATATATAT!!! SIDDELEY descends, hawklike, fires bullets and blows the luggage carts sky-high. Mater and Finn burst through them, luggage now raining down from above. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> I knew I should've done carry-on!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Thanks, old boy!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(TO SIDDELEY)  Siddeley LANDS HARD on the tarmac ahead of them. No time to stop, he DROPS his back open, revealing HOLLEY. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Hey, doggone it. It's my imaginary girlfriend!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Come on! Get in here! 58.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>   Mater SPEEDS UP toward Siddeley's ramp, Holley. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Boy I tell you what, you really do want this first date, don't ya? That's a no-quit attitude right there.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(TO HOLLEY)  Just as Mater's wheels touch the ramp, BULLETS PING around him in a spray. Siddeley is HIT, a tire BLOWN. He yells in pain. </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Hold on, Sid!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Siddeley peels off the runway onto the grass.  A gunfight ensues between Finn and Acer. Finn SHOOTS ACER'S TIRE, blowing it and throwing him off-course.  Acer CAREENS out of control, drives up and THROUGH A JET ---  --- OUT THE OTHER SIDE where he lands in an oil tanker.  ON SIDDELEY - He's headed toward the edge of the tarmac, where the grass and runway meet WATER. He HITS THE GAS, his only hope. </meta>
      <char name="SIDDELEY">
         <dialogue> Finn, it's now or never!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Finn BRAKES, 180s and grabs the ramp just as Siddeley gets air. </meta>
      <char name="SIDDELEY">
         <dialogue> Hold on!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Mater, the only thing not in the jet, dangles and recedes from our view as Siddeley climbs toward the clouds. As he's PULLED in through the back hatch: </meta>
      <char name="MATER (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> By the time you read this, I will be safely on an airplane, flying home.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="30">INT. LOBBY - HOTEL - TOKYO - DAY
</sceneheader>
      <meta> CLOSE ON a handwritten (er, tire-written?) NOTE in childish scrawl. We don't see all of it, only a bit. Mater's voice O.S. begins the note with the first sentence, but we DISSOLVE into McQueen's voice. 59.  </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> &quot;I'm so sorry for what I did. I don't want to be the cause of you losing any more races. I want you to go prove to the world what I already know - that you are the greatest race car in the whole wide world. Your best friend, Mater.&quot;</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  McQueen takes this in. </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> I didn't really want him to leave.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="LUIGI">
         <dialogue> Wait, there's more here. &quot;P.S. Please tell the hotel I didn't mean to order that movie. I thought it was just a preview and I didn't realize I was paying for it. P.P.S... That's funny right there -- PP.&quot; There's a few more pages of P.S.'s here.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(to the others) </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Well, at least I know if he's at home he'll be safe.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="31">EXT. SKY - DAY
</sceneheader>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="32">INT. JET - DAY
</sceneheader>
      <meta> A well-appointed spy jet. Various computers line the walls. </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Now that's how I like to start the day! You never feel more alive than when you're almost dead.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> I hope that device didn't fall off.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(SCANNING MATER) </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> That's the closest I ever been to missing my flight! That was --- 60.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>   With a ROBOTIC ARM, Holley grabs the THE DEVICE that Rod Redline hid under Mater. She yanks it out with a GOOSE. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Yow!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(JUMPS) </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Still in one piece, great.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Holley drops the device into a mainframe computer. It starts</meta>
      <char name="&quot;ANALYZING.&quot;">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> I gotta go to a doctor. I keep getting these sharp pains in my undercarriage.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Downloading the photo now.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Hey, lemme introduce you two. This here is Finn McSomething-or- other. He's a First Class VIP airport whatchamacallit. And Finn, this here's my date. I never did get your name.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(TO HOLLEY) </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Oh yes, sorry. It's Shiftwell. Holley Shiftwell.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> It's Shiftwell. Holley ---</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(TO FINN)  DING! The computer is done analyzing. The cabin lights dim. </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Finally. Time to see who's behind all this.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  AN IMAGE is blasted between the three of them. It's of a photograph, a complicated melange of metallic parts stuck together. </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> What is this? 61.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(to Mater, expectantly)  </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Well, that's one of the worst engines ever made. It's an old aluminum V8 with a Lucas electrical system and Whitworth bolts. Shoot, them Whitworth bolts is a pain, tell you what. Them ain't metric, they ain't inches...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Yes, OK, right. But who's engine is this, Mater?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Well, it's kinda hard to tell from this picture, ain't it?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> But you're the one who took it.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Holley.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Oh, right. Yes, of course. &quot;A good agent gets what he can, then gets out before he's killed.&quot; Sorry.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Agent? You mean like insurance agent, like, `Like a good neighbor, Mater is there'? Wait, you mean secret agents. You guys is spies!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(SINGS) </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Holley, in how many makes and models did this type of engine appear?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Holley has these stats in seconds. Kid's play. </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> It was standard in seven models over a 12-year period. At least 35,000 cars were made with this engine.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Mater MOVES HIS SEAT FORWARD, through one part of the hologram so he's face-to-face with Holley. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> You're pretty. 62.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Yes, alright. Thank you.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(ANNOYED) </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> And so nice.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Just pay attention.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  She moves the engine photo so it's now blocking Mater again. </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> This seems like a dead end. If there were something in the photo that could narrow this down a bit I'd be a lot happier.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> You might not be happy, but I bet this feller is. See how he's had most of his parts replaced? And see all them boxes over there? Them's all original parts. They ain't easy to come by.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Rare parts.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> That's something we can track.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Exactly!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Holley drops her screen down. </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Well done, Mater! I would never have seen that. I know of a black-market parts dealer in Paris, a treacherous lowlife. But, he's the only car in the world who can tell us whose engine this is. Mater, what would you say to setting up an informal task force on this one?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(TO HOLLEY) </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Wait, what? 63.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> You obviously have plenty of experience in the field.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Well yeah I live right next to one. I don't know, Finn. I ain't exactly been much help to anybody recently.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(thinks about it) </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> You're helping me. Please, Mater.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Well, okay. But you know I'm just a tow truck, right?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Right. And I'm just in the import/export business. Siddeley?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="SIDDELEY">
         <dialogue> Yes, Finn?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Paris. Tout de suite.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Yeah, two of them sweets for me too, Sid! You know, I always wanted to be a spy.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(TO HOLLEY) </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Really? Me too.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(SMILING SWEETLY) </meta>
      <char name="SIDDELEY">
         <dialogue> Afterburners, sir?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Is there any other way?</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="33">EXT. JET - MOVING
</sceneheader>
      <meta> Siddeley HITS THE JUICE, they kick forward like a mule as we</meta>
      <char name="CUT TO ---">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
      <meta>  A MONTAGE OF PARIS: Mater attempts to merge into roundabout traffic; mimes annoy tourists at the Eiffel Tower; a painter works his magic on an unattractive couple; a couple kisses on the most romantic spot in the world; we might even catch</meta>
      <char name="GASTOW'S RESTAURANT.">
         <dialogue> 64.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="34">EXT. STREET - DAY
</sceneheader>
      <meta> --- a dirty street in the 1st Arrondissement. Finn and Holley drive along together as Mater, playing &quot;spy,&quot; darts back and forth behind them from doorway to dumpster, &quot;hiding out.&quot; He's having a ball. </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Once we're inside, stay close. Don't bother checking VIN numbers for criminal records, they're all dodgy here.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(TO HOLLEY) </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> No VIN scans. Got it.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Don't talk to anyone. Don't look at anyone. And absolutely, positively no idling. Are we clear?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Yes, right. No idling. Yes, sir.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Mater?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Yeah, Finn?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> We're not here to go shopping.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  As Finn and Holley and Mater turn the corner... </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Shopping? What do you mean? Why would I ---</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Mater turns the corner and enters a massive Les Halles- inspired Parisian market filled with car parts. A tow truck's dream. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Dadgum.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MERCHANTS">
         <dialogue> - Parts for sale, Monsieur! - Monsieur! Parts for sale! 65.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="IN THE MARKET - MOMENTS LATER">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
      <meta>  Mater rolls along, impressed by the goods for sale. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> You gotta be kidding me - they've got everything here. Look at them hoods! I could use a hood.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Mater continues on though, heeding Finn's advice. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Sorry fellers, I gotta go.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="35">INT. ENCLOSED MARKETPLACE - DAY
</sceneheader>
      <meta> Mater, now out of sight of Finn and Holley, passes a darkened stall. He STOPS, peers in. There's someone in there. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Excuse me. What are you selling?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  It suddenly OPENS its headlights revealing... EYES!! In French, the mutant car pitches his wares to Mater. Mater FREAKS OUT, speeds off, TERRIFIED. </meta>
      <char name="AROUND THE CORNER - FINN AND HOLLEY">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
      <meta>  A few car lengths ahead of Mater. They roll along, looking for... Aha! Finn and Holley recede into the shadows.  In FINN'S SIDE MIRROR: TOMBER, a three-wheeled parts dealer, argues with a French customer. </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> There you are.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Mater suddenly turns the corner, sees Finn and Holley. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Man, there are some great ---</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Mater, get back!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Too late. Tomber sees Mater, then notices FINN, reflected in a hubcap. He BOLTS. Finn and Holley give chase. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Hey, wait for me!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Tomber, skidding away, kicks a tent in Finn's way. Holley quickly pivots RIGHT and disappears. Where did she go? 66.   Finn, hot in pursuit, leaps another obstacle and loses ground</meta>
      <char name="TO ---">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
      <meta>  --- Tomber who turns a corner and finds himself grill to grill with HOLLEY. He whips to the left but TURNS OVER, rolling sideways and CRASHING to a stop.  Holley ZAPS him with ELECTROSHOCKERS. Finn suddenly arrives, stops her. </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Have you lost your mind?!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(TO HOLLEY) </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> But I thought ---</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Mater! This chap needs a tow. Hook him up.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Sure thing. CUT TO:</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  MOMENTS LATER - Mater tows Tomber, following Finn and Holley. </meta>
      <char name="TOMBER">
         <dialogue> You rusty piece of junk, get your dirty hook off me!</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="36">INT. A SMALL GARAGE - MOMENTS LATER
</sceneheader>
      <meta> Finn throws open a door. Cars scatter like cockroaches. </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Allez! Maintenant - vite!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(to the cars)  Mater unhooks an angry Tomber who spits in French. Finn pulls the door down. As it LATCHES TIGHT --- </meta>
      <char name="TOMBER">
         <dialogue> Electroshock! Are you kidding me??</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(TO FINN) </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Easy, Tomber. This is her first field assignment - she didn't know you were my informant.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Informant? 67.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="TOMBER">
         <dialogue> A rookie, eh? I never liked new car- smell.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Holley FUMES with anger. </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Tomber was doing 20 to life in a Moroccan impound the first time I saved him, if I recall correctly.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="TOMBER">
         <dialogue> Speaking of recalls, you're getting up there in mileage aren't you, Finn?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Alright, we get it. You both know each other, you're both old. So.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Holley shoots a HOLOGRAPHIC PHOTO of the engine in front of Tomber. </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> There you go, informant. Inform us.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Tomber eyes the photo. He recoils, unimpressed. </meta>
      <char name="TOMBER">
         <dialogue> That is the worst motor ever made.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Suddenly, Tomber narrows his gaze. </meta>
      <char name="TOMBER">
         <dialogue> Wait. That oil filter... those wheel bearings.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Do those parts look familiar, Tomber?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="TOMBER">
         <dialogue> They should. I sold them.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> To whom?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="TOMBER">
         <dialogue> No idea. He's my best customer, but he always does his business over the phone. I was always wondering why he needs so many parts. Now I know. 68.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Well, a lemon needs parts. Ain't nothing truer than that.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> &quot;Lemon?&quot;</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Yeah, you know. Cars that don't ever work right. Lemons is a tow truck's bread and butter. Like them Gremlins and Pacers we run into at the party and the race and the airport.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Holley, pull up the pictures from the oil platform. I want to know what other type of cars were out there.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Holley complies and suddenly PHOTOS OF CARS FROM THE OIL PLATFORM hang suspended in the air in front of them. </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Right. Let's see. There were Hugos. And Trunkovs.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Mater, are these cars considered lemons?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Is the Popemobile Catholic?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Finn. Everyone involved in this plot is one of history's biggest loser cars.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Holley refers to the ENGINE PHOTO, which now rises forward as the prominent picture, perhaps the only one in view. </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> And they're all taking their orders from the car behind this engine.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="TOMBER">
         <dialogue> This explains it!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> What, Tomber? 69.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="TOMBER">
         <dialogue> Gremlin, Pacer, Hugo and Trunkovs never get together. But they're having a secret meeting in two days.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Where's this meeting taking place?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="TOMBER">
         <dialogue> Porto Corsa, Italy.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> That's where the next race is!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Then there's a good chance our mystery engine will be there too.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="TOMBER">
         <dialogue> Your chances are more than good. I just sent him a new clutch assembly yesterday... to Porto Corsa.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Holley, contact Stephenson and have him meet us at Gare de Lyon. Good work.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="37">EXT. FRENCH ALPS - NIGHT
</sceneheader>
      <meta> STEPHENSON, a THREE-CAR LUXURY BULLET TRAIN speeds along a snow-covered mountain in the dead of night, its halogen headlight cutting through the darkness. It DIPS into a</meta>
      <char name="TUNNEL ---">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER (O.S.)">
         <dialogue> Boy, I'll tell you what. That three- wheeled feller had to be right about a big meeting.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="38">INT. SPY CAR - MOVING - NIGHT
</sceneheader>
      <meta> Mater, Finn and Holley scroll through surveillance-style photos of TRAFFIC on an Italian street. They're in the front train car, which doubles as a luxury seating area and intelligence command center. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> You never see this many lemons in one town. Unless there's a swap meet, or something. 70.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(MORE) </meta>
      <char name="MATER (CONT'D)">
         <dialogue> Hey, how'd you get all them pictures?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Well, I remotely reprogrammed Porto Corsa's red light cameras to do recognition scans.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Wow, not only is you the prettiest car I ever met, but you the smartest too.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Thank you. I think.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> That's a familiar sight.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Mater refers to a photo of VICTOR HUGO, the HUGO Lemonhead, being towed by an EASTERN EUROPEAN TOW TRUCK. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> A Hugo being towed. But he looks absolutely perfect.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Of course. They must be the heads of the lemon families.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Makes sense. If I was rich and broke down every day, I'd hire me to tow me around all the time too.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> We've got to infiltrate that meeting. It's the only way to find out who's behind all this.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Hang on a minute.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(EYEING MATER) </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> What?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Hold still.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Holley SNAPS Mater's picture, temporarily blinding him. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Ahh! 71.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>   Holley turns back to her monitor. Mater's face appears on screen. She quickly GRAFTS it over the Hugo's tow truck's. </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Good job, Miss Shiftwell.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Holley isn't sure what surprises her more: the compliment or how pleased it makes her. </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Thank you, Finn.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Boy, I sure wish my friends could see me now.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="39">EXT. SMALL TOWN - ITALY - OUTSIDE PORTO CORSA - DAY
</sceneheader>
      <meta> A quaint Italian piazza. A pristine MASERATI FOUNTAIN, complete with ancient trident, looms in our view.  Luigi and Guido roll into view. </meta>
      <char name="LUIGI">
         <dialogue> Guido, your eyes do not deceive you. We are in Italy. We are home!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Sarge, Fillmore and McQueen exit a WGP transport truck. </meta>
      <char name="FILLMORE">
         <dialogue> Hey, Luigi. Which way to the hotel, man?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="LUIGI">
         <dialogue> What? No friends of mine will stay in a hotel in my village. You will stay with my --- Uncle Topolino!</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="40">EXT. PIAZZA - DUSK
</sceneheader>
      <meta> A festive homecoming party. Lights strung across the square. Music and dancing. Fillmore and Sarge are at a dining table. </meta>
      <char name="SARGE">
         <dialogue> How do they do it? These are the same ingredients as back home, but it tastes so good. 72.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="FILLMORE">
         <dialogue> It's organic, man.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="SARGE">
         <dialogue> Tree hugger.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  LIGHTNING MCQUEEN rolls along the periphery of the square, seems lost in thought. </meta>
      <char name="UNCLE TOPOLINO (O.S.)">
         <dialogue> Race car.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Uncle Topolino beckons McQueen over. </meta>
      <char name="UNCLE TOPOLINO">
         <dialogue> You look so down, so low. Is like you have flat tires.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  MAMA TOPOLINO, a hefty Italian grandmother pipes up, a mile a minute then drives off, now a car on a mission. </meta>
      <char name="UNCLE TOPOLINO">
         <dialogue> She said you look like you're starving. That she's going to make you a big meal, and fatten you up.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> No, Mama Topolino, please. You don't need to make a fuss!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Too late. She's disappeared inside her kitchen. </meta>
      <char name="UNCLE TOPOLINO">
         <dialogue> Capisco. I understand. Is a problem, yes? Between you and a friend?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> How'd you know that?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="UNCLE TOPOLINO">
         <dialogue> A wise car hears one word and understands two.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  McQueen takes this in, impressed. </meta>
      <char name="UNCLE TOPOLINO">
         <dialogue> That, and Luigi told me. While Mama cooks, come and take a stroll with me.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  They amble forward, Uncle Topolino setting the pace. 73.  </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> I brought my friend Mater along on the trip. And I told him he needed to act different, that we weren't in Radiator Springs.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="UNCLE TOPOLINO">
         <dialogue> This Mater. He's a close friend?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> He's my best friend.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="UNCLE TOPOLINO">
         <dialogue> Then why would you ask him to be someone else?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  McQueen considers this - a realization. </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> What did I do? I said some things during our fight...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="UNCLE TOPOLINO">
         <dialogue> You know, back when Guido and Luigi used to work for me, they would fight over everything.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  IN THE SQUARE - Guido dances with a girl. Luigi suddenly CUTS IN. They begin to ARGUE. </meta>
      <char name="UNCLE TOPOLINO">
         <dialogue> They fight over what Ferrari was the best Ferrari; which one of them look more like a Ferrari... There were even some non-Ferrari fights.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Guido now LIFTS Luigi, cuts BACK in. </meta>
      <char name="UNCLE TOPOLINO">
         <dialogue> So I tell them, va bene. It's okay to fight. Everybody fights now and then, especially best friends.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  McQueen takes this in. Seems to take some small comfort. </meta>
      <char name="UNCLE TOPOLINO">
         <dialogue> But you gotta make up fast.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  McQueen's comfort quickly evaporates. </meta>
      <char name="UNCLE TOPOLINO">
         <dialogue> No fight more important than friendship. 74.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>   Guido and Luigi now dance together with the girl and her friend who has just arrived. All having a great time. They dance past us, crossing in front of MCQUEEN AND UNCLE TOPOLINO. We STAY WITH them. </meta>
      <char name="UNCLE TOPOLINO">
         <dialogue> Chi trova un'amico, trova un tesoro.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> What does that mean?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MAMA TOPOLINO">
         <dialogue> Whoever find a friend, find a treasure.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(ARRIVING)  Mama Topolino drops a tray of food in front of McQueen. </meta>
      <char name="MAMA TOPOLINO">
         <dialogue> Now, mangia! Eat!</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="41">INT. TRAIN TUNNEL - LATER
</sceneheader>
      <meta> Stephenson glides along, all business. </meta>
      <char name="STEPHENSON">
         <dialogue> Finn, one hour to Porto Corsa.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="42">INT. TRAIN - MOVING - LATER
</sceneheader>
      <meta/>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Thank you, Stephenson.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Finn watches as HOLLEY attaches a new EMERGENCY LIGHT on Mater's roof. It looks exactly like his old one. </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> That should just about do it.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Perfect.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> So Mater, it's voice-activated. But you know, everything's voice- activated these days. 75.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> What? I thought you was supposed to be making me a disguise.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER'S COMPUTER">
         <dialogue> Voice recognized. Disguise Program Initiated.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  ZWWWWAT! A HOLOGRAPHIC disguise suddenly umbrellas out, emitted from Mater's roof. It drops a clean cloaking image of the EASTERN EUROPEAN TOW TRUCK over Mater. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Cool! Hey, computer. Make me a German truck!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER'S COMPUTER">
         <dialogue> Request acknowledged.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  ZWATTTT! Mater suddenly wears lederhosen and a German hat. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Check it out. I'm wearing Materhosen. Make me a monster truck!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER'S COMPUTER">
         <dialogue> Request acknowledged.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  He's transformed into Dracula, complete with fangs. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> I vant to siphon your gas. Now make me a taco truck!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(ALA DRACULA) </meta>
      <char name="MATER'S COMPUTER">
         <dialogue> Request acknowledged.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> A funny car!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER'S COMPUTER">
         <dialogue> Request acknowledged.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Finn suddenly pushes a button, stops the madness. </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> The idea is to keep a low profile, Mater.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Mater, chastened, moves on. 76.  </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> So I just go in, pretend to be this truck.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> And leave the rest to us.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Now hold still.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Holley turns back to her work. The disguise's cloaking is larger than Mater. As a result, Holley must dial it back to fit his body. As she carefully calibrates the hologram: </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> I have to do the final fitting on your disguise.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Holley STOPS. The 3D disguise is now flush with his frame, but dents SHOW THROUGH. </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Oh dear. That's no good.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  She deploys A BONDO SPRAYER on a robotic arm, moves it toward one of Mater's DENTS. Mater pulls away. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Hey, what are you doing?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> The disguise won't calibrate effectively without a smooth surface to graft onto.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Oh. For a second there I thought you was trying to fix my dents.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> I was.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Well then no thank you. I don't get them dents buffed, pulled, filled or painted by nobody. They're way too valuable.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Your dents are valuable?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> I come by each one of them with my best friend Lightning McQueen. 77.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(MORE) </meta>
      <char name="MATER (CONT'D)">
         <dialogue> I don't fix these. I want to remember these dents forever.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> So you were being serious in Paris? McQueen isn't just part of your cover?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Friendships can be dangerous in our line of work, Mater.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> But my line of work is towing and salvage.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Right. And Miss Shiftwell's is designing iPhone apps.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> No, I meant for real. I ---</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> It's okay. Say no more. I'll work around the dent.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> In the meantime...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Finn hits a button. The walls transform into a MASSIVE</meta>
      <char name="WEAPONS CACHE.">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> You look a little light on weapons.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="43">EXT. ALPS - DAWN
</sceneheader>
      <meta> --- STEPHENSON EMERGES LOUDLY from a tunnel. He powers forward, starts his descent into Italy --- </meta>
      <char name="BRENT MUSTANGBURGER (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> You are looking live at beautiful Porto Corsa, Italy, on the Italian Riviera. What a magnificent setting for the second race of the World Grand Prix.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="44">EXT. PORTO CORSA, ITALY - DAY
</sceneheader>
      <meta> Over sweeping helicopter BEAUTY SHOTS: 78.  </meta>
      <char name="DAVID HOBBSCAP (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> Well Brent, they call this place &quot;The Gem of the Riviera,&quot; and it's easy to see why.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  A local fishing boat chugs through an idyllic waterway, beneath bridges that connect hillside villas. </meta>
      <char name="DAVID HOBBSCAP (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> With its secluded beaches and opulent casinos, Porto Corsa truly is a playground for the wealthy.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  A long line of RICH-LOOKING YACHTS in the harbor. </meta>
      <char name="DAVID HOBBSCAP (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> And everyone who's anyone is here today.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Rich SPORTS CARS drive past pricey shops. </meta>
      <char name="DAVID HOBBSCAP (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> From the ultra-rich and super- famous, to world leaders and important dignitaries.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  THE POPEMOBILE, visible in a crowd, drives through town. </meta>
      <char name="DARRELL CARTRIP (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> You aren't kidding, David. You can't do a three-point turn around here without bumping into some celebrity!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  HELICOPTER SHOT of the Casino. </meta>
      <char name="BRENT MUSTANGBURGER (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> Welcome everyone to the second race of the World Grand Prix! CUT TO:</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  MUSTANGBURGER, HOBBSCAP and CARTRIP in the control booth. </meta>
      <char name="BRENT MUSTANGBURGER">
         <dialogue> The big news continues to be Allinol. Sir Miles Axlerod spoke to the press earlier today to answer questions about its safety.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  FOOTAGE OF THE PRESS CONFERENCE - Miles Axlerod, at a podium, addresses the press throng. He looks a bit exasperated. 79.  </meta>
      <char name="MILES AXLEROD">
         <dialogue> An independent panel of scientists has determined that Allinol is completely safe. Okay? Safe! There it is.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="BRENT MUSTANGBURGER">
         <dialogue> So the race will go on, folks.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  RACE GRAPHICS show Francesco with 10 points at the top of the race standings. </meta>
      <char name="DARRELL CARTRIP">
         <dialogue> But the question everyone is asking: Will the real Lightning McQueen show up today?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  ON THE TRACK - As the racers begin to get into position on the grid. </meta>
      <char name="BRENT MUSTANGBURGER (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> Well, he better. Talk about a home- track advantage. Francesco Bernoulli grew up racing on this course.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="ITALIAN TRACK ANNOUNCER (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> Signore e signori, in the pole position, numero uno...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  The crowd is cheering already, knows who this is. </meta>
      <char name="ITALIAN TRACK ANNOUNCER (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> ... Francescoooooo!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  The Italian crowd roars and chants for their hometown hero. </meta>
      <char name="FRANCESCO">
         <dialogue> Bellissima! Thank you for your support. And your big mistake, McQueen!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(TO MCQUEEN)  McQueen missed this comment. He approaches his grid position, lost in thought. </meta>
      <char name="ITALIAN TRACK ANNOUNCER (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> In the secondo position. Numero novantacinque. Lightning McQueen!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Cheers (not so thunderous, obviously) from the crowd. McQueen doesn't seem to notice. 80.   IN MCQUEEN'S PIT - His team exchanges looks, worried. </meta>
      <char name="LUIGI">
         <dialogue> McQueen? Is everything okay?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FILLMORE">
         <dialogue> If you're worried about your fuel, man, don't. It's perfectly safe.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="BACK ON THE STARTING GRID">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> No, guys, I just really wish Mater were here.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FRANCESCO (O.S.)">
         <dialogue> Francesco understands, McQueen.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Francesco parks next to him, grinning. </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Oh, great. Here it comes. What've you got, Francesco?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FRANCESCO">
         <dialogue> For famous race cars like Francesco and well... you, to be far away from home is not easy.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> I think you forgot the insulting part of that insult.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FRANCESCO">
         <dialogue> Is no insult. When Francesco is away from home, he misses his mama just like you miss your tow truck amico.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Gee, I maybe misjudged you, because that's exactly how I ---</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FRANCESCO">
         <dialogue> Of course, I am at home. And my mama is right here.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Francesco refers to his MAMA who sits in a special box in the crowd, cheering him on, blowing him kisses. </meta>
      <char name="FRANCESCO">
         <dialogue> Mama! Don't worry, Mama! 81.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(MORE) </meta>
      <char name="FRANCESCO (CONT'D)">
         <dialogue> McQueen is very sad! I will beat his cry-baby bottom today!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> And there's the insult we were missing. Grazie!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="THE LIGHTS - CLICK FROM RED TO GREEN ---">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="45">EXT. PORTO CORSA - DAY
</sceneheader>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="46">EXT. THE CASINO - MOMENTS LATER
</sceneheader>
      <meta> A group of thuggish HUGOS - ugly Eastern European cars - wait impatiently at the front. A LIMOUSINE-STYLE car carrier rolls up to the roundabout.  An esteemed, elderly GREMLIN rolls past with a group of GREMLIN THUGS who usher him into the casino. </meta>
      <char name="ALEXANDER HUGO">
         <dialogue> Gremlins. Man, those are some ugly cars. Look like someone stole their trunks.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  The THUGS all SNICKER. </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Scusatemi, tutti! Signori!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Holley arrives, sporting a decent Italian accent. </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Mio nonno, my grandfather, has broken down. If one of you would help I would be so thankful.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  IVAN, AN EASTERN EUROPEAN TOW TRUCK (the one Holley and Finn prepped Mater to impersonate), drives forward. </meta>
      <char name="IVAN THE TOW TRUCK">
         <dialogue> Sounds like you need some &quot;roadside assistance&quot;.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="ANOTHER HUGO">
         <dialogue> She was talking to me, Ivan. 82.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="IVAN THE TOW TRUCK">
         <dialogue> Oh really? Prove it.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> No, no, don't fight over me.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Holley directs her interest toward Ivan. </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Signore Tow Truck, per favore? CUT TO:</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  MATER - He watches this from a safe hiding spot around a corner. </meta>
      <char name="FINN (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> Get ready, Mater. CUT TO:</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  FINN, at an outdoor cafe on the casino grounds. </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> You're on any moment now. CUT BACK TO:</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  MATER, now looking a bit nervous. He backs out of sight. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> I don't know about this, Finn. What if I screw things up?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN (OVER RADIO)">
         <dialogue> Impossible. Just apply the same level of dedication you've been using to play the &quot;idiot tow truck&quot; and you'll be fine.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> It's just that them guys look pretty tough and --- Wait, did you say &quot;idiot&quot;? Is that how you see me?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN (OVER RADIO)">
         <dialogue> That's how everyone sees you. Isn't that the idea? I tell you, that's the genius of it. No one realizes they're being fooled because they're too busy laughing at the fool. Brilliant.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  While Finn talks, Mater takes this in. He catches his own reflection in a nearby window. Seems to be seeing himself with new eyes. 83.   ZZZZATTT! Mater jumps at the sound, turns in time to see Ivan SHOCKED UNCONSCIOUS by Holley's ZAPPERS. </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Why aren't you in disguise?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> I, uh---</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Come on, there's no time. Go!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Okay, okay. Computer: disguise.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER'S COMPUTER">
         <dialogue> Request acknowledged.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="47">EXT. AROUND THE NEXT CORNER - CONTINUOUS
</sceneheader>
      <meta> Mater, now disguised as Ivan the Tow Truck, approaches the Hugos. Another LIMO CAR CARRIER arrives. </meta>
      <char name="ALEXANDER HUGO">
         <dialogue> It's the boss! He is coming!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  The carrier parks and the back opens. VICTOR HUGO waits. </meta>
      <char name="VICTOR HUGO">
         <dialogue> Ivan!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Mater realizes Victor is talking to him. He hops to it. </meta>
      <char name="VICTOR HUGO">
         <dialogue> Ivan, why do you insult me so by making me wait?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Mater, now with Victor hooked, tows him in the front doors of the casino.  ON FINN - now joined in the cafe by Holley who monitors everything and SEES EVERYTHING MATER SEES on her display. </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> He's in.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="48">EXT. RACE COURSE - PORTO CORSA - DAY
</sceneheader>
      <meta> McQueen and Francesco battle for first place --- </meta>
      <char name="BRENT MUSTANGBURGER (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> The racers are now making their way around the hairpin, and headed downhill toward the casino bridge. 84.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="49">INT. CASINO - DAY
</sceneheader>
      <meta> Cars play craps with FUZZY DICE; slot machines with odometers for jackpot numbers; cigarette girls sell car items. </meta>
      <char name="CIGARETTE GIRL CAR">
         <dialogue> Air Freshener, antenna balls, sparkplugs...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  ON MATER - He tows VICTOR. They are flanked on all four corners by Hugo thugs, ala a presidential motorcade. The largess of the interior design seems to finally snap Mater out of his funk. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Wow, this place looks like it's made out of gold.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(WIDE-EYED)  The Hugos on either side of Mater exchange a look. </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY (OVER RADIO)">
         <dialogue> That's because it is, Mater. Now, be careful what you say.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Why is that? What do you mean don't talk to you? So you want me to stop talking to you. Right now?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>which we cannot hear) </meta>
      <char name="ALEXANDER HUGO">
         <dialogue> You are acting strange today, Ivan.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> I have no idea what you're talking about...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  MATER'S P.O.V. - A digital readout isolates the Hugo and starts to scroll reams of information alongside. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> ...Alexander Hugo, aka &quot;Chop Shop Alex.&quot;</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  IN A WIDER SHOT we realize this display is invisible to all but Mater. Some of Alex's other alias' include &quot;Alexander Hu- Don't Go&quot; and &quot;Alexander the Not-So Great.&quot; 85.  </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Hey, you got a lot of aka's, Alex. But I guess that makes sense seeings how you's wanted in France, Germany, the Czech Republic...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Mater! Stop it!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>DISPLAY)  Alexander Hugo, unaware of Holley's interruption, whispers to Mater as they turn a corner. </meta>
      <char name="ALEXANDER HUGO">
         <dialogue> Okay, okay. Keep your voice down. You're gonna make me arrested. Don't mess with Ivan today. He's in a bad mood.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="50">EXT. CASINO - DAY
</sceneheader>
      <meta> Holley, hearing this, can't believe it. </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> He's so good.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="51">INT. CASINO - DAY
</sceneheader>
      <meta> Mater tows Victor inside a private room, where inside are the WORLD'S WORST CARS including VLADMIR TRUNKOV, TUBBS PACER and</meta>
      <char name="J. CURBY GREMLIN.">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="VLADIMIR TRUNKOV">
         <dialogue> Victor!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="TUBBS PACER">
         <dialogue> Hey, Victor!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="J. CURBY GREMLIN">
         <dialogue> There you are.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="VLADIMIR TRUNKOV">
         <dialogue> Come in, come in.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="J. CURBY GREMLIN">
         <dialogue> Victor Hugo. I'm J. Curby Gremlin, from Detroit. It's good to see you. Now we can start.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="VICTOR HUGO">
         <dialogue> Is the big boss here yet? 86.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="VLADIMIR TRUNKOV">
         <dialogue> No, not yet.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="TUBBS PACER">
         <dialogue> He's supposed to be here any minute.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="52">EXT. CASINO - CONTINUOUS
</sceneheader>
      <meta/>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Here we go.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="53">INT. PRIVATE ROOM - CASINO - CONTINUOUS
</sceneheader>
      <meta> A car finally appears. It's Zundapp. </meta>
      <char name="PROFESSOR ZUNDAPP">
         <dialogue> Guten Tag!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Everyone looks disappointed. </meta>
      <char name="TUBBS PACER">
         <dialogue> It's just the Professor.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="VICTOR HUGO">
         <dialogue> Zundapp, when is he coming?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="PROFESSOR ZUNDAPP">
         <dialogue> He's already here.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  MONITORS descend from the ceiling. On them, an image of AN ENGINE - the same bloody engine from the photo. But this is a LIVE image. The car is being worked on. </meta>
      <char name="VOICE">
         <dialogue> Welcome, everyone.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  The VOICE is garbled, scrambled. No way to determine who. </meta>
      <char name="ENGINE VOICE">
         <dialogue> I wish I could be with you on this very special day but... my clutch assembly broke. You know how it is.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  The Lemons all nod in understanding. 87.  </meta>
      <char name="TUBBS PACER">
         <dialogue> Been there.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="J. CURBY GREMLIN">
         <dialogue> Forget about it.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="VLADIMIR TRUNKOV">
         <dialogue> We know how you feel.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="54">EXT. CASINO
</sceneheader>
      <meta/>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Descramble that voice!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> I'm trying... It's too sophisticated!</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="55">INT. PRIVATE ROOM - CASINO - CONTINUOUS
</sceneheader>
      <meta/>
      <char name="ENGINE VOICE">
         <dialogue> We are here to celebrate. Today all your hard work pays off. The world turned their backs on cars like us. They stopped manufacturing us, stopped making our parts. The only thing they haven't stopped doing is laughing at us. They've called us terrible names...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  On VICTOR HUGO. </meta>
      <char name="ENGINE VOICE">
         <dialogue> Jalopy. Rustbucket.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  On TUBBS PACER. </meta>
      <char name="ENGINE VOICE">
         <dialogue> Heap. Clunker.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  On J. CURBY GREMLIN: </meta>
      <char name="ENGINE VOICE">
         <dialogue> Junker, beater, wreck.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  On ZUNDAPP. </meta>
      <char name="ENGINE VOICE">
         <dialogue> Rattletrap.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  And finally back on the monitor. The ENGINE. 88.  </meta>
      <char name="ENGINE VOICE">
         <dialogue> Lemon. But their insults just give us strength. Because today, my friends...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  The monitors switch to LIVE RACE FOOTAGE. </meta>
      <char name="ENGINE VOICE">
         <dialogue> ...that all ends.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="56">EXT. RACE COURSE - CONTINUOUS
</sceneheader>
      <meta> Veloso swerves, attempts to mitigate a crash --- </meta>
      <char name="DARRELL CARTRIP (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> There's smoke! On the casino bridge!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="DAVID HOBBSCAP (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> Oh no.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="BRENT MUSTANGBURGER (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> It's Carla Veloso, the Brazilian race car.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="57">EXT. CASINO - CONTINUOUS
</sceneheader>
      <meta/>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> What just happened?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> I'm working on it.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="58">INT. PRIVATE ROOM - CASINO - CONTINUOUS
</sceneheader>
      <meta> The lemons are CHEERING. Mater is freaked out. </meta>
      <char name="ENGINE VOICE">
         <dialogue> They laughed at us. But now it's our turn to laugh back.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="59">EXT. RACE COURSE - SAME
</sceneheader>
      <meta> As the racer smashes into the railing --- 89.  </meta>
      <char name="DAVID HOBBSCAP (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> Another crash! It's number nine, Nigel Gearsley.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="ENGINE VOICE (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> Embrace your inner lemon! Let it drive you!</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="60">EXT. CASINO
</sceneheader>
      <meta/>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Holley?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> I'm detecting an extremely strong electromagnetic pulse.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Holley replays that last crash. The OUTLINE OF THE BEAM is seen hitting the racer. Holley TRACES THIS to its source ---  --- a WGP CAMERA, which Grem and Acer have pointed at the racers from a tower position. </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Finn, it's the camera!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Where?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> On the tower.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Finn TAKES OFF, speeding toward Grem and Acer --- </meta>
      <char name="ENGINE VOICE (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> This was meant to be alternative fuel's greatest moment.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="61">EXT. GRANDSTANDS - RACE COURSE - CONTINUOUS
</sceneheader>
      <meta> Angry fans knock over cans of Allinol. One drives over an Allinol sign. They're fed up with it. </meta>
      <char name="ENGINE VOICE (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> After today everyone will race back to gasoline.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="62">INT. PRIVATE ROOM - CASINO - CONTINUOUS
</sceneheader>
      <meta> The video screens are now filled with ONE IMAGE - of the OIL PLATFORMS in the Pacific from the beginning of the movie. 90.  </meta>
      <char name="ENGINE VOICE">
         <dialogue> And we, the owners of the world's largest untapped oil reserve, will become the most powerful cars in the world!</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="63">EXT. STREETS OF PORTO CORSA - CONTINUOUS
</sceneheader>
      <meta> Finn ducks, weaves, speeds, and pushes his way through</meta>
      <char name="BYSTANDERS ---">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Get out of the way! Andate!</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="64">EXT. RACE COURSE - PORTO CORSA - CONTINUOUS
</sceneheader>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="65">INT. PRIVATE ROOM - CASINO
</sceneheader>
      <meta/>
      <char name="ENGINE VOICE">
         <dialogue> They will come to us and they will have no choice, `cause they will need us.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  ON FINN - He SPEEDS up a road, Grem and Acer visible ahead of him. He LEAPS over the crevasse toward the AMC cousins ---  Suddenly, FINN FREEZES. He's immobilized in mid-air!  He looks up. A CHOPPER with a LARGE MAGNET hovers over him. </meta>
      <char name="ACER">
         <dialogue> We figured you might stop by.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(TO FINN) </meta>
      <char name="ENGINE VOICE (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> And they will finally respect us. So hold your hoods high. After today you will never again be ashamed of who you are!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Grem and Acer turn back to the camera. They line up Shu Todoroki, who's a bit further along now. </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> No!</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="66">INT. PRIVATE ROOM - CASINO - CONTINUOUS
</sceneheader>
      <meta/>
      <char name="ENGINE VOICE">
         <dialogue> Long live Lemons! 91.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="67">EXT. RACE COURSE
</sceneheader>
      <meta> Grem ZAPS THE RACER.  Flames burst from Todoroki. He loses control. </meta>
      <char name="BRENT MUSTANGBURGER (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> Number seven is loose! Shu Todoroki!</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="68">EXT. CASINO - SAME
</sceneheader>
      <meta> Holley sees Finn being flown away by the chopper. </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Finn.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="69">EXT. FINISH LINE - PORTO CORSA - CONTINUOUS
</sceneheader>
      <meta/>
      <char name="BRENT MUSTANGBURGER (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> Bumper to bumper as they approach the finish line.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  McQueen NOSES out Francesco for a win, both oblivious to what's just happened. </meta>
      <char name="BRENT MUSTANGBURGER (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> McQueen's the winner, Francesco's second. And they have no idea what happened behind them.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Yeah!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FRANCESCO">
         <dialogue> Dah! This is impossible!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> That's what I'm talking about. Kachow! Hey, where are all the other cars?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FRANCESCO">
         <dialogue> What is going on?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  They see the pile-up from an overhead monitor. Sirens blare as a MEDIC CHOPPER flies to the scene of the pile-up. 92.  </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Oh no. CUT TO:</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(REALIZES)  MILES AXLEROD - LATER. He's near the casino. He's completely surrounded, 360 degrees, by press. He's drowned out by a blizzard of questions. </meta>
      <char name="BRENT MUSTANGBURGER">
         <dialogue> Sir Axlerod! Is the final race in London still going to take place?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  PULL BACK to reveal we are watching this on monitors in the PRIVATE CASINO ROOM with the Lemonheads, Zundapp and Mater. </meta>
      <char name="MILES AXLEROD (ON TV)">
         <dialogue> I suppose that... Look, &quot;the show must go on&quot; as they say. But now is not the time to talk about...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="J. CURBY GREMLIN">
         <dialogue> I can't believe this is really happening.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="VLADIMIR TRUNKOV">
         <dialogue> Shh, quiet!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="BRENT MUSTANGBURGER (ON TV)">
         <dialogue> And Allinol? Will you require all the racers to still run on Allinol?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="VLADIMIR TRUNKOV">
         <dialogue> Here it comes.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  On Miles Axlerod: He's devastated. </meta>
      <char name="MILES AXLEROD (ON TV)">
         <dialogue> I cannot in good conscience continue to risk the lives of any more race cars. The final race will not be run on Allinol.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  WILD WHOOPING CHEERS fill the room. Lemonade corks are popped. </meta>
      <char name="BRENT MUSTANGBURGER (ON TV)">
         <dialogue> There you have it. A clearly devastated Sir Miles Axlerod announcing that he will not require the cars to use Allinol for the final race. 93.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="PROFESSOR ZUNDAPP">
         <dialogue> A toast! To the death of Allinol and alternative fuel forever!</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="70">EXT. CASINO - CONTINUOUS
</sceneheader>
      <meta> Holley is already on the run. Speeding away. </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Mater. Abort the mission. They've got Finn. Get out of there. Get out of there right now!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  She turns a corner and STOPS.  Her escape is now blocked by the same HUGO THUGS she tricked before. Another vehicle appears BEHIND HER, LOOMS. </meta>
      <char name="IVAN THE TOW TRUCK">
         <dialogue> How is your grandfather?</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="71">INT. PRIVATE ROOM - CASINO - CONTINUOUS
</sceneheader>
      <meta> The Lemonheads celebrate, chant &quot;Long live lemons!&quot; Mater, scared, turns to leave. He's stopped by ALEXANDER HUGO. </meta>
      <char name="ALEXANDER HUGO">
         <dialogue> Isn't this a great party, Ivan?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Oh yeah, it's unbelievable.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="ALEXANDER HUGO">
         <dialogue> You are not leaving, are you?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Uh, of course I ain't leavin'.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN (O.S.)">
         <dialogue> I'm just in shock like everybody...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> McQueen?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  He turns, sees that McQueen is being interviewed on the monitors. </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN (ON TV)">
         <dialogue> Crashes are part of racing, I know. But something like that shouldn't ever happen. 94.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="DARRELL CARTRIP (ON TV)">
         <dialogue> They're letting you choose your fuel for the final race. Do you have any idea what it's going to be?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN (ON TV)">
         <dialogue> Allinol.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  The excitement suddenly DRAINS from the room. </meta>
      <char name="LEMONHEADS">
         <dialogue> - What?! - Did he just say Allinol? After today?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN (ON TV)">
         <dialogue> My friend Fillmore says the fuel's safe. That's good enough for me. I didn't stand by a friend of mine recently. I'm not gonna make the same mistake twice.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  On Mater. He takes this in. </meta>
      <char name="BRENT MUSTANGBURGER (ON TV)">
         <dialogue> So a surprising revelation from Lightning McQueen...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Zundapp is already on the phone with their Big Boss who, based on his angry O.S. voice, sounds ticked off. </meta>
      <char name="PROFESSOR ZUNDAPP">
         <dialogue> Yes, sir. Of course.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Zundapp hangs up, turns to the room. </meta>
      <char name="PROFESSOR ZUNDAPP">
         <dialogue> Allinol must be finished for good. McQueen cannot win the last race. Lightning McQueen must be killed.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Mater's eyes open wide. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> No!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Mater backs up, KNOCKING his emergency light against one of the monitors. ZZZZZAT! His holographic disguise flickers away then quickly SCROLLS THROUGH all of his previous disguises, finally revealing rusty old Mater. </meta>
      <char name="PROFESSOR ZUNDAPP">
         <dialogue> It's the American spy! 95.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>   The thugs DRAW TERRIFYING WEAPONS. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Dadgum.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER'S COMPUTER">
         <dialogue> &quot;Gatling gun&quot; request acknowledged.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  WHIRRRRR! GUNS roll out of Mater on each side. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Shoot. I didn't mean ---</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER'S COMPUTER">
         <dialogue> Request acknowledged.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Mater SPRAYS BULLETS into the crowd. </meta>
      <char name="VLADIMIR TRUNKOV">
         <dialogue> Get down!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Whoa!!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  The Lemons and Lemonheads hit the deck and RETURN FIRE ---  Mater is THROWN BACKWARD by the force of the guns, back through some double doors and onto a BALCONY. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Wait wait! I didn't mean that kind of shoot!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER'S COMPUTER">
         <dialogue> Correction acknowledged. Deploying chute.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  WHOOM! A PARACHUTE BURSTS out of the back of Mater, he catches air and is YANKED INTO THE SKY!  The Lemonheads watch him float away, amazed.  ON MATER, out of the frying pan but still toasty. He looks around, notices:  LIGHTNING MCQUEEN, far away, leaving the press podium. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> McQueen!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Mater looks down at the harbor, over which he flies. He spots a MOTORBOAT. Mater WHIPS his hook down, steals a ride behind the boat TOWARD MCQUEEN. 96.  </meta>
      <char name="ITALIAN MOTORBOAT">
         <dialogue> Aspetti!</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="72">EXT. SECURITY CHECKPOINT - WINNERS CIRCLE
</sceneheader>
      <meta> --- a barricade. Separating the press from the public, ITALIAN SECURITY TRUCKS stand guard. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Lemme through! Lemme through!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  MATER barrels around a corner. He's now covered in Francesco memorabilia and palm leaves. The word `HOT' now dangles off him like the world's biggest bling. He looks INSANE. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> You gotta let me in! I gotta get through to warn McQueen!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(TO SECURITY)  Security eyes one another. This is serious. </meta>
      <char name="ITALIAN SECURITY #1">
         <dialogue> You cannot come through here. Back up, signore.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="ITALIAN SECURITY #2">
         <dialogue> We have a lunatic at Gate Nove.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(into a walkie-talkie) </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> No, listen! I was disguised as a tow truck to infiltrate this Lemonhead meeting and my weapons system misinterperated what I was SAYING ---</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="ITALIAN SECURITY #2">
         <dialogue> I repeat. Lunatic at Gate Nove.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Mater spots McQueen far off in the distance. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> McQueen! McQueen!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  JUST OFF THE PRESS STAGE - McQueen is led toward the exit. </meta>
      <char name="PRESS LIAISON">
         <dialogue> Right this way, signore. 97.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="MATER (O.S.)">
         <dialogue> McQueen!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(DISTANT) </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Mater?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  McQueen looks up but can only see A SEA OF VEHICLES, flashbulbs, cameras, TV trucks with those tall satellite antennae things that spindle toward the sky...  BACK AT THE SECURITY BARRICADE - Mater, like a nimble running back, dances around to avoid capture by security. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> McQueen!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="ITALIAN SECURITY #1">
         <dialogue> Back up, sir. Stop moving! Stop!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Mater head fakes them and pushes through, into the crowd --- </meta>
      <char name="ITALIAN SECURITY #1">
         <dialogue> Oy! Stop! Ferma li!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  IN THE CROWD - Mater shoves his way through. He's still far in the back. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> McQueen!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="ON MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> That really sounded like Mater. Mater?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="PRESS LIAISON">
         <dialogue> Signore...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(TO MCQUEEN)  ON MATER, getting CLOSER... </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> McQueen, they're gonna kill you!!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  ON MCQUEEN - Okay, he's positive that was his friend, but where is he? </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Mater?!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  McQueen spots a TOW HOOK, moving through the crowd toward him, &quot;Jaws&quot;-like. 98.  </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Excuse me.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  McQueen disappears into the press crowd. </meta>
      <char name="PRESS LIAISON">
         <dialogue> No, no, where are you going? Please, Mr. McQueen!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  McQueen pushes through the press. </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Scusi. Mater! Scusi...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  McQueen tracks the tow hook, gets closer. He pushes through the last few vehicles --- </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Mater, I'm so glad to see you. I'm so sorr ---</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  It's NOT MATER. It's IVAN, the Hugo Thug's tow truck. </meta>
      <char name="IVAN THE TOW TRUCK">
         <dialogue> Lightning McQueen! I am a huge fan.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Oh, I'm sorry. I thought I heard---</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(CONFUSED) </meta>
      <char name="IVAN THE TOW TRUCK">
         <dialogue> Yes, but that was me. I said, &quot;You killed out there today.&quot; You're the best.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> What? Oh. I mean, thanks.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="PRESS LIAISON">
         <dialogue> Right this way, signore ---</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Now the Press Liaison and his assistants are pushing McQueen back in the other direction --- </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> I really thought I heard my friend.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(as he's pulled away)  As he's pulled away, press and onlookers start to come between him and Ivan, who hasn't moved. 99.  </meta>
      <char name="IVAN THE TOW TRUCK">
         <dialogue> In England you'll be finished. At the finish line.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(TO MCQUEEN)  Ivan is now obscured again. </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Wait, what?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  The ITALIAN PRESS being to swarm. </meta>
      <char name="PRESS LIAISON">
         <dialogue> Please, the world press is waiting. You come with me, please.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="73">EXT. STREET - PORTO CORSA - MOMENTS LATER
</sceneheader>
      <meta> --- just as Mater, now BOUND and with HIS MOUTH TAPED, is pulled away and thrown into the back of a transport vehicle. He lands hard on his side, spits out his TAPE. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Let me go!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="PROFESSOR ZUNDAPP">
         <dialogue> You actually care about that race car. A pity you didn't warn him in time.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  As the doors close on Mater --- PHHHHHSSSSSSTTTTTTT! A thick, noxious gas starts to fill the truck.  On MATER as the knockout gas works its magic. HIS EYES CLOSE. CUT TO: </meta>
      <char name="BLACK SCREEN.">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> Idiot? Is that how you see me?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> That's how everyone sees you. I tell you, that's the genius of it.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  FADE IN on Mater, back at the Casino, eyeing his reflection in the glass window. It's the same moment from before except now we are watching it from a DETACHED, FLOATING PERSPECTIVE.</meta>
      <char name="100.">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="FINN (OVER RADIO)">
         <dialogue> No one realizes they're being fooled because they're too busy laughing at the fool.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  - IN THE KABUKI THEATER IN JAPAN - Again, from before. Mater makes a spectacle of himself, WHOOPING AND HOLLERING in the stands with the face paint on. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Domo arigato!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  McQueen, Fillmore, Guido, Luigi, Sarge and patrons eye Mater, embarrassed and angry.  - IN THE JAPANESE MUSEUM - The moment of Mater banging on the Zen rock garden's glass. Except that now we see all sorts of disappointed and eyebrow raising reactions. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> You done good! You got all the leaves!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="JEFF GORVETTE">
         <dialogue> Check out that tow truck.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="LEWIS HAMILTON">
         <dialogue> I wonder who that guy's with?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Will you guys excuse me just for one little second?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(HUMILIATED)  We now REVEAL that this FLOATING, THIRD PERSON PERSPECTIVE is MATER. He's INSIDE his past, watching it from others' points of view. He doesn't like what he sees.  - ON MATER, now at the sushi bar. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Now that's a scoop of ice cream!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Mater swallows the wasabi with one big bite. He SCREAMS! The sushi bar patrons blanch with revulsion at his wail.  - ON THE FOUNTAIN, as Mater peels into full view of everyone else at the party. As Mater laps up water from a fountain: </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Mater?! 101.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(EMBARRASSED)   ALL THE RACERS, with FRANCESCO front and center, guffaw at Mater.  - On MCQUEEN, now scolding Mater moments later. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> I never leak oil. Never.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Mater, you have to get a hold of yourself. You're making a scene!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  - IN MCQUEEN'S PIT GARAGE, after the Japanese race. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Wait a minute. I didn't screw you up, did I?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> I lost the race because of you!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Maybe if I talked to somebody, or---</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> I don't need your help. I don't want your help!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  - Now BACK AT THE PARTY, a moment we didn't see before but which presumably happened. Mater is BANGING a ceremonial GONG, to the horror of Japanese guests. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Bang a gong, get it on!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  GONNNNNNG!!! ---  On the PARTYGOERS, RACE CARS, PARTY STAFF - they're all laughing at Mater as McQueen's final words blend in, making a</meta>
      <char name="DISSATISFIED CACOPHONY">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Listen, this isn't Radiator Springs. This is exactly why I don't bring you along to these things!</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="74">INT. BIG BENTLEY - DAY
</sceneheader>
      <meta> --- to the GONG of a CLOCK.  CLOSE ON MATER as he OPENS HIS EYES.</meta>
      <char name="102.">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
      <meta>   All around him, all he sees are GIANT PIECES OF MECHANIZED</meta>
      <char name="CLOCKWORK.">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
      <meta>  HOLLEY and FINN are here too, strapped bumper to bumper in the divots of large clock movements. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Holley! Finn! Where are we?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> We're in London, Mater. Inside Big Bentley.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="75">EXT. BIG BENTLEY - CONTINUOUS
</sceneheader>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="76">INT. BIG BENTLEY - CONTINUOUS
</sceneheader>
      <meta> Suddenly Mater DROPS QUICKLY down toward ---  --- whirring, scary machinery. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Woaaaah! ---</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  WHAP! The chain yanks to a STOP.  Mater, instead of being 30 feet from death, is now 20.  Finn and Holley are only a few clicks closer to being crushed themselves. The clock ticks to 3:01. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> This... this is all my fault.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Don't be a fool, Mater.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> But I am, remember? You said so.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> When did I... Oh. Mater, I was complimenting you on what a good spy you are.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> I'm not a spy!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  This echoes throughout the clock.</meta>
      <char name="103.">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> I've been trying to tell you that the whole time. I really am just a tow truck.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Finn and Holley take this in. </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Finn, he's not joking.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> I know.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> You were right, Finn. I'm a fool. And what's happened to McQueen is `cause I'm such a big one. This is all my fault.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  GREM and ACER arrive on a lift, roll into view on a catwalk. </meta>
      <char name="GREM">
         <dialogue> Good, you're up!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="ACER">
         <dialogue> And just in time!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="GREM">
         <dialogue> Professor Z wanted you to have a front row seat for the death of Lightning McQueen.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> He's still alive?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(HOPEFUL)  Acer whips a sheet away, revealing the WGP CAMERA, turns it toward the clock face. </meta>
      <char name="ACER">
         <dialogue> Not for much longer.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="77">EXT. LONDON - DAY
</sceneheader>
      <meta> Big Bentley's big hand CLICKS ahead another minute. But we're a bit farther away from it than before. </meta>
      <char name="SALLY (O.S.)">
         <dialogue> We came as soon as you called. 104.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="78">INT. MCQUEEN'S PIT - LONDON
</sceneheader>
      <meta> Sally, flanked by Red, Flo and Ramone, are in front of ----  --- McQueen and the rest of the team. </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> I called to talk to Mater. It never occurred to me that he wouldn't be there.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="RAMONE">
         <dialogue> Sheriff is talking to Scotland Yard right now.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  FLO And Sarge is in touch with his friends in the British military. </meta>
      <char name="SALLY">
         <dialogue> You just need to focus on the race.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> I know, but Sal, with everything going on I'm not sure I should---</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  A HORN O.S. Someone's entering the pit. Everyone parts, revealing MILES AXLEROD. </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Sir Axlerod.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MILES AXLEROD">
         <dialogue> I'm sorry to interrupt.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> No, no, it's all right.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MILES AXLEROD">
         <dialogue> I just wanted to come down here and personally thank you. Because after Italy, I was finished. And then you gave me one last shot.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Listen, I ---</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MILES AXLEROD">
         <dialogue> And I probably shouldn't be saying this at all but... I hope you win today. Show the world that they've been wrong about Allinol.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  McQueen takes this in. He looks at Sally.</meta>
      <char name="105.">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="SALLY">
         <dialogue> Mater would want you to race.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> All right. For Mater.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="79">EXT. THE STARTING GRID - MOMENTS LATER
</sceneheader>
      <meta/>
      <char name="TIRES SQUEAL ---">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="80">EXT. RACE COURSE - LONDON - DAY
</sceneheader>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="81">INT. BIG BENTLEY - LONDON - CONTINUOUS
</sceneheader>
      <meta/>
      <char name="GREM">
         <dialogue> Here he comes!</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="82">EXT. RACE COURSE - LONDON
</sceneheader>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="83">INT. BIG BENTLEY - LONDON
</sceneheader>
      <meta> Zundapp suddenly SQUAWKS over the radio. </meta>
      <char name="PROFESSOR ZUNDAPP (OVER RADIO)">
         <dialogue> What happened!?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="GREM">
         <dialogue> I don't know, Professor.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="ACER">
         <dialogue> What did you do?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="GREM">
         <dialogue> I didn't do nothin'. Shh! I'm talking to the Professor---</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(TO ACER)  They're all talking at once and for a moment we cannot understand what is being said.</meta>
      <char name="106.">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="ACER">
         <dialogue> You broke it.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="GREM">
         <dialogue> Quiet! I understand, sir. Yes.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(INTO RADIO)  Grem hangs up. </meta>
      <char name="ACER">
         <dialogue> What'd he say?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="GREM">
         <dialogue> We go to the backup plan.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Backup plan??</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="GREM">
         <dialogue> We snuck a bomb in McQueen's pit!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="ACER">
         <dialogue> The next time he makes a stop, instead of saying &quot;ka-chow,&quot; he's gonna go &quot;ka-boom&quot;!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  They LAUGH. Mater shudders, upset. </meta>
      <char name="GREM">
         <dialogue> Don't feel bad, tow truck. You couldn't have saved him.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="ACER">
         <dialogue> Oh, wait. You could have!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Grem and Acer laugh. As they board the elevator: </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Dadgum lemons.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER'S COMPUTER">
         <dialogue> Request acknowledged.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Suddenly, Mater's GATLING GUNS rotate out again - a surprise to Mater. But they SPIN IN PLACE, empty.  Grem and Acer just laugh more. </meta>
      <char name="GREM">
         <dialogue> What, you didn't think we'd take your bullets?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Mater NOTICES SOMETHING.</meta>
      <char name="107.">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
      <meta>   CLOSE ON WHAT MATER SEES: A small piece of his ropes have been shaved away by the Gatling.  He carefully rotates his guns BACK IN, pretending like he's seen nothing. </meta>
      <char name="ACER">
         <dialogue> That's right! You got nothin'.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="GREM">
         <dialogue> Who's the lemon now, huh?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(as the elevator descends)  They're GONE. </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Nice try, Mater.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Dadgum!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER'S COMPUTER">
         <dialogue> REQUEST ACK-</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  The guns ROTATE OUT AGAIN, SPIN. Mater watches as the spinning barrels SLICE INTO the ropes, do some damage. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Dadgum! Dadgum! Dadgum!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  The COMPUTER responds with each &quot;dadgum.&quot; The barrels continue to SPIN, CUTTING THROUGH the ropes. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> DADGUMDADGUMDADGUMDADGUM ---</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  PING! The ropes BREAK AWAY and Mater FALLS --- right toward the whirring machinery! </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Mater!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Mater QUICKLY WHIPS his tow cable around, hooks a pipe and tosses himself to the ramp with a heavy THUD. He doesn't HESITATE: </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> I gotta get you all out of there!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> There's no time. McQueen needs your help, Mater. 108.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> But I can't, I'm just a tow truck.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> It's up to you. Go to the pits and get everyone out. You can do that.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> What about you guys?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> We'll be okay.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Go and get some more dents, Mater.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="84">EXT. BIG BENTLEY - LONDON
</sceneheader>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="85">INT. BIG BENTLEY - LONDON - SAME
</sceneheader>
      <meta> On Finn and Holley, now closer to death. </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> So we'll be &quot;okay&quot;? Really?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> He wouldn't have left if I'd told him the truth. Being killed by a clock. Gives a whole new meaning to &quot;your time has come.&quot;</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(re: his death trap)  At this mention Holley seems to perk up, gets an idea. </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Time. That's it!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  She spies a GEARBOX below them, at least 20 feet down. Holley</meta>
      <char name="FIRES HER ELECTROSHOCKERS ---">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
      <meta>  --- but they miss their target. She recoils them back. </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> What are you doing?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Trying to turn back time. If I can just reverse the polarity...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  She FIRES them again. Direct hit!</meta>
      <char name="109.">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
      <meta>   Holley JUICES the gearbox with HIGH VOLTAGE. The CLOCK STOPS. It reverses itself.  Finn and Holley's wheel now rotates AWAY from danger. </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Good job! Quick thinking, Holley!</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="86">EXT. LONDON - CONTINUOUS
</sceneheader>
      <meta> BIG BENTLEY, visible from street level, now moves BACKWARDS. Fast. CRANE DOWN TO ---  --- Mater, speeding toward the track, unaware. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> What's everybody on the wrong side of the road for?!</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="87">INT. BIG BENTLEY - CONTINUOUS
</sceneheader>
      <meta> Finn and Holley are now moving in the opposite direction, toward ANOTHER GEAR! And it's going MUCH FASTER. They're seconds from a crushing death... </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Oh no!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Drive!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  They both DRIVE, fast as they can with FULL FORCE --- </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Burn rubber!!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  They drive HARDER, separating bumpers with just enough room for the descending gear to SNAP THEIR ROPES!  Their tires spinning, they both LAUNCH off in opposite directions, LAND HARD on opposing platforms. As Finn squeals around to Holley's side of the clock: </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> We've got to get to the course. Calculate the fastest way to ---</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Holley pops WINGS out of her side. </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Done. 110.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Miss Shiftwell.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(IMPRESSED) </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> They're standard issue now.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> You kids get all the good hardware.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  They turn to leave when they STOP, see SOMETHING. It's an AIR FILTER on the ground. </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Oh no. That's Mater's.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> I knew his escape was too easy.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="88">EXT. BIG BENTLEY - LONDON
</sceneheader>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="89">INT. PIT ROW - TRACK SIDE - DAY
</sceneheader>
      <meta> Mater bursts through the security gate with aplomb, tears through the pits and stops at MCQUEEN'S. </meta>
      <char name="LUIGI">
         <dialogue> Mater!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Everybody get out! Get out now! Y'all gotta get out the pits!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  The ENTIRE RADIATOR SPRINGS GANG is here. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Hey, what are you guys doing here?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="SALLY">
         <dialogue> We're here because of you, Mater.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  FLO Is everything okay? </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> No! Everything's not okay! There's a bomb in here! Y'all gotta get out! Now! 111.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="EVERYONE">
         <dialogue> - A bomb? - Huh? - Woah.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN (OVER RADIO)">
         <dialogue> Mater!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER (INTO RADIO)">
         <dialogue> Finn! You're okay!</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="90">EXT. LONDON STREETS - CONTINUOUS
</sceneheader>
      <meta/>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Mater, listen to me. The bomb is on you.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  ON HIS REARVIEW DISPLAY: We can see that a BOMB has been detected, anchored to Mater's air filter. </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> They knew you'd try to help McQueen. When we were knocked out they planted it in your air filter.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="91">INT. MCQUEEN'S PIT - CONTINUOUS
</sceneheader>
      <meta> Mater SNORTS, blowing his air filter cover off. Cross-eyed, Mater sees the explosive device attached to him. He looks up:  An ALLINOL CONTAINER hangs ominously over his head. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Uh-oh.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Mater! There you are!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Mater turns. McQueen enters Pit Row, 100 yards away and closing in FAST. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Stop right there!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Oh man, I've been so worried about you! CUT TO:</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  The view of this scene through the window of a luxury box. Reveal Zundapp in the window's reflection. He's watching from inside. He's poised to push a DETONATOR BUTTON.  As Zundapp's front tire approaches the detonator ---</meta>
      <char name="112.">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="92">INT. MCQUEEN'S PIT - CONTINUOUS
</sceneheader>
      <meta/>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Don't come any closer!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Are you okay?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> No, I'm not okay. Stay away from me!!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Mater PEELS OUT BACKWARDS, out onto the track. </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> No, wait. Wait! CUT TO:</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  PROFESSOR ZUNDAPP - He hesitates, can't believe it. </meta>
      <char name="TV FOOTAGE OF MCQUEEN CHASING MATER">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="BRENT MUSTANGBURGER (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> Hold everything. A tow truck has just raced onto the track. And he's driving backwards!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="IN MCQUEEN'S PIT">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Mater, wait!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  He breezes right through his pit, goes after Mater. </meta>
      <char name="DAVID HOBBSCAP (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> Normally an emergency vehicle on the track means there's been an accident.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="BRENT MUSTANGBURGER (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> Wait, wait. Lightning McQueen is chasing him!</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="93">EXT. TRACK - DAY
</sceneheader>
      <meta> Mater drives up the track. McQueen gains, fast. Because Mater's going backwards, they're face-to-face (but still with some distance between them). </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Mater, wait! 113.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Stay back! If you get close to me, you gonna get hurt real bad!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> I know I made you feel that way before, but none of that matters because we're best friends! CUT TO:</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="TV FOOTAGE OF MCQUEEN CHASING MATER">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="BRENT MUSTANGBURGER (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> And McQueen seems to be having a conversation with the tow truck!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="DARRELL CARTRIP (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> I don't know who that truck is, Brent. But I'll tell you what, he's gotta be the world's best backwards driver.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  REVEAL ZUNDAPP is watching this footage from his luxury box. The closer McQueen gets to Mater the farther his tire ROLLS onto the detonator. But he holds back ever so slightly so as not to jump the gun.  ON THE TRACK - McQueen gains on Mater. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> McQueen, you don't get it. I'm the bomb!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Yes, Mater! You are the bomb! That's what I'm trying to say here. You've always been the bomb! And you'll always be the bomb.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Stay away!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> No! Never!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  ON ZUNDAPP. He watches as McQueen SPEEDS UP. </meta>
      <char name="PROFESSOR ZUNDAPP">
         <dialogue> Almost there...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  ON MCQUEEN. He's had enough screwing around. Here he comes. </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> I'm not...letting you... 114.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>   He's going to catch him now. </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> ...get away again!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  McQueen JUMPS FORWARD, in an attempt to grab Mater's HOOK --- </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Gotta keep away from McQueen.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(TO HIMSELF)  McQueen hooks Mater with his bumper JUST AS --- </meta>
      <char name="MATER'S COMPUTER">
         <dialogue> Request acknowledged.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  TURBINE ROCKETS slide out of Mater. </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Oh my gosh!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  BAWHOOOOOOM!!!!! Mater JOLTS forward with a rocket blast and disappears, taking McQueen with him.  ON ZUNDAPP. He now freely PUSHES the detonator, but it says</meta>
      <char name="&quot;OUT OF RANGE.&quot;">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
      <meta>  Zundapp can't believe it. He FLIPS OUT.  FARTHER UP THE TRACK - Francesco speeds along. ZHWAAAAAP!!! Mater and McQueen ZING PAST HIM with a RED BLUR. </meta>
      <char name="FRANCESCO">
         <dialogue> What is happening? It's a bad dream.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  NOW EVEN FARTHER UP THE TRACK - Mater takes a turn, SMASHES THROUGH A FENCE and skids around a corner out of sight. A white, smoky JET TRAIL is all that remains.  IN MCQUEEN'S PIT - All of Radiator Springs watches the television monitors, dumbfounded. </meta>
      <char name="BRENT MUSTANGBURGER (V.O.)">
         <dialogue> And Lightning McQueen just blasted away, hooked to the now rocket- propelled tow truck. CUT TO:</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="94">EXT. STREETS OF LONDON - DAY
</sceneheader>
      <meta> Overhead P.O.V.: Mater and McQueen swerve through the streets.</meta>
      <char name="115.">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="95">INT. LUXURY BOX - CONTINUOUS
</sceneheader>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="96">INT. ADJACENT LUXURY BOX - CONTINUOUS
</sceneheader>
      <meta> The LEMONHEADS watch, baffled, as Zundapp drives away. </meta>
      <char name="J. CURBY GREMLIN">
         <dialogue> The Professor's on the run.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="TUBBS PACER">
         <dialogue> Someone's gotta get McQueen.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="VLADIMIR TRUNKOV">
         <dialogue> Get McQueen!!</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="97">EXT. SIDE STREET - SAME
</sceneheader>
      <meta> Finn speeds into view, in time to see Zundapp turn a corner out of sight. </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Holley. I'll get Zundapp, you help Mater.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="98">EXT. TRACK - SAME
</sceneheader>
      <meta> Holley, still in the air, turns --- </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Got it!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  FARTHER UP THE TRACK - Holley THUNDERS past Francesco and out of sight. </meta>
      <char name="FRANCESCO">
         <dialogue> What is happening?!</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="99">EXT. STREETS OF LONDON - SAME
</sceneheader>
      <meta> Finn screams around a corner, sees ---  --- Professor Zundapp, speeding toward docks along the Thames where a COMBAT SHIP waits.</meta>
      <char name="116.">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="COMBAT SHIP">
         <dialogue> Hurry, Professor!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  ON ZUNDAPP - With Finn gaining fast, he accelerates. Suddenly --- WHAP!  He's been TETHERED by Finn with tensile cables now attached to his rear end. Zundapp SCREAMS like a little girl. </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Do you really think I'm going to let you float away, Professor?</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="100">EXT. LONDON STREETS - SAME
</sceneheader>
      <meta> Mater, still towing McQueen, rockets around a corner, zips down another street --- </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> McQueen, let go!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Never!</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="101">EXT. DOCKS NEAR THE THAMES - CONTINUOUS
</sceneheader>
      <meta> FINN, tires squealing, loses more and more ground to the boat. Zundapp, the &quot;rope&quot; in this tug-of-war, buckles under the tension. </meta>
      <char name="PROFESSOR ZUNDAPP">
         <dialogue> Give it up, McMissile!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Finn releases a mess of bullets, grenades, and other weaponry into the air ---</meta>
      <char name="117.">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
      <meta>   THE MAGNET SUCKS it in quickly like a black hole ---  THUNK! It all sticks to the magnet, right next to Finn's bullets. They're BOMBS, GRENADES, ROCKETS and one little detonator with a flashing, beeping light.  Off the boat's RXN --- CUT TO: </meta>
      <char name="ANOTHER PART OF LONDON, AT STREET LEVEL">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
      <meta>  KA-BOOOOOOM! A distant explosion (miles away) festoons into the air, visible over the rooftops. Holley suddenly WINGS into view. She sees ---  Mater and McQueen, speeding up the street. </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Mater, stop!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> No way! You could get hurt!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Then she looks over, catches a glimpse of GREM AND ACER, bearing down on them from a side street. They're going to broadside Mater and McQueen. </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Oh no.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  ON MATER AND MCQUEEN - They're not aware of the impending impact.  Holley DROPS FROM THE SKY, hits the pavement, SKIDS into the path of the AMCs and DEFLECTS THEM. They FLIP OVER Holley, Finn and McQueen and sail ---  --- INTO A PUB ---  --- where they skid across the room and SLAM into the bar, knocking a ROW OF BEER MUGS to the ground. </meta>
      <char name="IN THE PUB - MOMENTS LATER">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="102">EXT. LONDON STREET - MOMENTS LATER
</sceneheader>
      <meta> Holley, McQueen and Mater are now stopped. </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Mater, we've got to get that bomb off you. 118.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>   She's already SCANNING the bomb, working away. </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Bomb?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Yeah, they strapped it to me to kill you as a back-up plan.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Back-up plan? Mater, who put a bomb on you?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="PROFESSOR ZUNDAPP (O.S.)">
         <dialogue> Ahhhhh!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Professor Zundapp suddenly ROLLS to a stop next to (a now totally freaked) McQueen, entangled in grappling hooks care</meta>
      <char name="OF ---">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
      <meta>  --- Finn, who has him leashed. </meta>
      <char name="PROFESSOR ZUNDAPP">
         <dialogue> You. Why didn't my death ray kill you?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(TO MCQUEEN) </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Death ray?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Turn off the bomb, Zundapp!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="PROFESSOR ZUNDAPP">
         <dialogue> Are you all so dense? It's voice- activated. Everything is voice- activated these days.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Deactivate! Deactivate!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="BOMB'S COMPUTER VOICE">
         <dialogue> Voice denied.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  The BOMB suddenly TRANSFORMS into a TIME BOMB, now complete with a countdown mechanism from 4:59... 4:58... Mater GASPS. </meta>
      <char name="PROFESSOR ZUNDAPP">
         <dialogue> Oops. Did I forget to mention that it can only be disarmed by the one who activated it?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Holley immediately shoves a GUN in Zundapp's grill.</meta>
      <char name="119.">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Say it!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="PROFESSOR ZUNDAPP">
         <dialogue> Deactivate.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="BOMB'S COMPUTER VOICE">
         <dialogue> Voice denied.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  THE BOMB'S TIMER: It loses a full minute! Goes from 4:48 to 3:48 to 3:47... Mater GASPS. </meta>
      <char name="PROFESSOR ZUNDAPP">
         <dialogue> I am not the one who activated it. Would anyone else like to try?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(GRINNING)  ZZZZZZATTT! Holley shocks him unconscious. </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> You read my mind.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(TO HOLLEY) </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> He was getting on my nerves.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> What do we do?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="VICTOR HUGO (O.S.)">
         <dialogue> It's very simple.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  VICTOR HUGO blocks the entrance to a side street. He's surrounded by Hugo relatives. </meta>
      <char name="VICTOR HUGO">
         <dialogue> You blow up.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  The four streets surrounding them are now blocked by each of the Lemonheads and their families. </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> I'm gonna go out on a limb here. These are the guys that want me dead, correct?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(TO MATER) </meta>
      <char name="VLADIMIR TRUNKOV">
         <dialogue> It's nothing personal.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Fellers, listen. 120.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(MORE) </meta>
      <char name="MATER (CONT'D)">
         <dialogue> I know what you're going through. Everybody's been laughing at me my whole life too ---</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  McQueen turns to Mater - he wasn't expecting that.  The Lemons all eye each other, considering Mater's words. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> --- but becoming powerful and rich beyond your wildest dreams ain't gonna make you feel better.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="J. CURBY GREMLIN">
         <dialogue> Yeah, but it's worth a shot.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  WHOOM!!! He's BROADSIDED by a blast of water from O.S.  It's Red! He's sitting outside an underground entrance, followed by Sally and the rest of the Radiator Springs gang.  ALL OUT WAR ensues between the LEMONS, RADIATOR SPRINGS along with FINN and HOLLEY.  FINN attaches his four-way cable hooks to the thugs and springs high in the air, crushing the four of them together.  HOLLEY SPROUTS her wings, and knocks out two cars on her side.  VARIOUS SHOTS OF RADIATOR SPRINGS KICKING BUTT:  Guido pulls some LEMON tires off with his air gun. In seconds he has a stack of lugnuts next to him. </meta>
      <char name="GUIDO">
         <dialogue> Pit stop.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  The two Pacers' tires all FALL OFF.  Flo hits VLADIMIR TRUNKOV with her high-beams, BLINDING HIM. Sheriff BOOTS him. </meta>
      <char name="SHERIFF">
         <dialogue> Not today, boys!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Guido pushes away his tireless thug, YELLING AT HIM IN</meta>
      <char name="ITALIAN.">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
      <meta>  Mater KARATE CHOPS lemons, three and four at a time.  Ramone SPRAY PAINTS a lemon's windshield.</meta>
      <char name="121.">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="TUBBS PACER">
         <dialogue> Retreat!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  A few Lemons turn back the way they came. BLOCKING THEIR PATH are a line of BRITISH MILITARY VEHICLES clad in digital camo, led by SARGE. </meta>
      <char name="SARGE">
         <dialogue> Thanks for the help, Corporal.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="BRITISH CORPORAL">
         <dialogue> Anything for one of pop's mates.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  And in the middle of all of this craziness we CUT TO ---  --- MATER. WRENCH BITS are strewn all around him as Guido tries wrench after wrench to take the bolts off. No dice. Guido gestures wildly, spits Italian a mile a minute. </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> What's he saying?! What's wrong!?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="LUIGI">
         <dialogue> None of his wrenches fit the bolts!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  This is a light bulb moment for Mater. He eyes the bolts. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> I get it. I get it! I know what needs to be done.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Then do it!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> What? No, I can't do it. Look, nobody takes me seriously. I know that now. This ain't Radiator Springs.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Yes it is.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Mater looks at McQueen. It is? </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> You're yourself in Radiator Springs. Be yourself here. And if people aren't taking you seriously, then they need to change. Not you. I know that, because I was wrong before. Now you can do this. You're the bomb. 122.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Thanks, buddy.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> No no no, you're the actual bomb. Now let's go!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Oh, right! Hang on!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Mater HOOKS McQueen and they're off.  They SHOOT PAST FINN, who's in the middle of battling lemons. </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Where's he going?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  ON MATER AND MCQUEEN - Flying down a side street. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Computer!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER'S COMPUTER">
         <dialogue> Yes, Agent Mater.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> I need that thing you done before to get me away from McQueen!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER'S COMPUTER">
         <dialogue> Request acknowledged.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  The ROCKET THRUSTERS kick in. They head right for a WALL. </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Mater...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Now I need you to do the chute, the second kind not the first!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER'S COMPUTER">
         <dialogue> Deploying chute.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="103">EXT. BALCONY - BUCKINGHAM PALACE - DAY
</sceneheader>
      <meta> The QUEEN, her attendants, assorted dignitaries are here.</meta>
      <char name="123.">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="QUEEN">
         <dialogue> Who's winning the race?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Mater and McQueen drop from the sky. They land and skid to a halt just before the Queen's guards who DRAW THEIR WEAPONS. </meta>
      <char name="QUEEN'S GUARD">
         <dialogue> Back up! Back away!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="QUEEN">
         <dialogue> It's Lightning McQueen!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(STAR-STRUCK) </meta>
      <char name="QUEEN'S GUARDS">
         <dialogue> Get back!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> No, no, it's okay! Tell them, Mater. Explain.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Okay! Somebody's been sabotaging the racers and hurting the cars and I know who. Oh wait... Your Majesty.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Mater BOWS to the Queen. In doing so, the TICKING TIME BOMB angles into view. The clock's at T-minus 1:53. </meta>
      <char name="QUEEN'S GUARDS">
         <dialogue> - Bomb! - It's a bomb! - Everybody down! - Look out!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN (O.S.)">
         <dialogue> Hold your fire! He can't disarm it!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Finn dives onto the platform and rolls between the Queen and Mater. </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Mater, I don't know what you're doing but stand down now!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> This ain't nothing at all like Radiator Springs.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(aside, to McQueen) </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Mater, just cut to the chase!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Okay. 124.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>   He turns to Miles Axlerod. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> It's him.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MILES AXLEROD">
         <dialogue> What? Me? You've got to be crazy.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Everyone exchanges confused looks, including Finn and Holley. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> I figured it out when I realized you all attached this ticking time bomb with Whitworth bolts. The same bolts that hold together that old British engine from the photograph. Holley! Show that picture.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> O-kay...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Holley projects the much discussed PHOTO OF THE ENGINE. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> And then I remembered what they say about old British engines - &quot;If there ain't no oil under `em, there ain't no oil in `em.&quot;</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MILES AXLEROD">
         <dialogue> What is he talking about?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> It was you leaking oil at the party in Japan. You just blamed it on me.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MILES AXLEROD">
         <dialogue> Electric cars don't use oil, you twit.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Then you're faking it. You didn't convert to no electric. We pop that hood we gonna see that engine from that picture right there.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Mater moves toward Miles Axlerod to pop his hood. </meta>
      <char name="MILES AXLEROD">
         <dialogue> This lorry's crazy. He's going to kill us all!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Miles Axlerod BACKS UP to the edge of the stage.</meta>
      <char name="125.">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="MILES AXLEROD">
         <dialogue> Stay away!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> But Sir Axlerod created the race, Mater. Why would he want to hurt anyone?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> To make Allinol look bad so everybody'd go back to using oil. I mean, he said it himself with that disguised voice.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MILES AXLEROD">
         <dialogue> &quot;Dee-sguised voice?&quot; What are you talking about? You're nuts, you are!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  The QUEEN'S GUARDS have had ENOUGH. As has the PRINCE. </meta>
      <char name="PRINCE WHEELIAM">
         <dialogue> This is going nowhere fast. We really should go, Grandmother.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="QUEEN">
         <dialogue> One moment. I'd like to see where this is going.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Mater, he created Allinol.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Yeah, but what if he found that huge oil field just as the world was trying to find something else?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Mater sticks his ticking bomb-nose into Miles Axlerod's grill. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> What if he came up with Allinol just to make alternative fuel look bad?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MILES AXLEROD">
         <dialogue> &quot;What if?&quot; You're basing this on a &quot;What if&quot;?!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="GUARD">
         <dialogue> Okay, that's it.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  And the QUEEN'S GUARDS spirit the Queen and Prince Wheeliam out of there FAST ---</meta>
      <char name="126.">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="MILES AXLEROD">
         <dialogue> Wait! Somebody save me! The lorry's crazy!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Now it's just Miles Axlerod, Mater, McQueen, Finn and Holley. Miles Axlerod's back tires slip on the edge of the podium as he is cornered by Mater. </meta>
      <char name="MILES AXLEROD">
         <dialogue> Keep away, you idiot!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  00:00:08... </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Mater!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Mater!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  00:03...00:02... </meta>
      <char name="MILES AXLEROD">
         <dialogue> Someone do something!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Everyone FLINCHES, DUCKS or DIVES FOR COVER except McQueen, Mater and Axlerod --- </meta>
      <char name="MILES AXLEROD">
         <dialogue> You're insane, you are! Deactivate!!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  The bomb FREEZES at 00:01. </meta>
      <char name="THE BOMB'S COMPUTER VOICE">
         <dialogue> Bomb deactivated. Have a nice day, Sir Axlerod.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  General shock all around. Miles Axlerod realizes what he's done, looks terrified. Police surround him.  Mater FLINGS Miles Axlerod's hood open with his hook, revealing AN INTERNAL COMBUSTION ENGINE, oil dripping from all sides. It MATCHES the photo. </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> The engine from the photo.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> It's a perfect match!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MILES AXLEROD">
         <dialogue> How did the tow truck figure it out? 127.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> It's official. You're coming to all my races from now on.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(TO MATER) </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Now you're talking!</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="104">EXT. BUCKINGHAM PALACE - DAY
</sceneheader>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="105">INT. BUCKINGHAM PALACE - DAY
</sceneheader>
      <meta> Mater does the requisite &quot;silly faces&quot; in an attempt to break the composure of a Buckingham Palace Guard. It isn't working. McQueen approaches. </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Mater, let's go. You're on.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="106">INT. QUEEN'S CHAMBER - BUCKINGHAM PALACE - DAY
</sceneheader>
      <meta> The Queen sits in attention at the front of the Main Ballroom. As Mater and McQueen approach: </meta>
      <char name="LORD STEWARD">
         <dialogue> Your Majesty. May I present for the investiture of honorary Knighthood of the British Realm. Tow Mater of Radiator Springs.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Go get `em, buddy.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  McQueen joins his friends from Radiator Springs. Mater rolls forward. He bows, as if he's practiced it all day. </meta>
      <char name="QUEEN">
         <dialogue> I hereby dub thee &quot;Sir Tow Mater.&quot;</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Applause from all around. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> &quot;Sir?&quot; Shoot, you can just call me Mater, Your Majesty. I don't wanna hear none of this &quot;Sir&quot; business. By the way, have y'all met each other? Queen? McQueen. McQueen, Queen. McQueen? McMissile. 128.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(MORE) </meta>
      <char name="MATER (CONT'D)">
         <dialogue> McMissile, McQueen. Queen? McMissile.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="107">EXT. RADIATOR SPRINGS - DAY
</sceneheader>
      <meta> The town sign now reads &quot;WELCOME TO RADIATOR SPRINGS - HOME</meta>
      <char name="OF LIGHTNING MCQUEEN AND SIR TOW MATER.&quot;">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="108">EXT. FLO'S - DAY
</sceneheader>
      <meta> Cars surround Mater and McQueen. The rest of the Radiator Springs gang is here too, watches. VAN and MINNY are front and center. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> So there I was: rocket jets going full blast, McQueen hanging on for dear life when suddenly them two nasty lemons come out of nowhere, guns drawed. We was goners. But then out of nowhere, this beautiful spy car swoops in from the sky to save us!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MINNY">
         <dialogue> That's a very entertaining story, young man.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  VAN Oh, Minny, please. Come on, none of this happened. Rocket jets? Flying spy cars? </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> No, you're quite right. It does sound a bit far-fetched.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  The crowd turns, sees HOLLEY, wings out, swooping in. FINN is right below her, driving up the street. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Holley! Finn!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Hello, Mater. It's so nice to see you again.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> What're you doing here? 129.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Our satellites picked up an urgent communique.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="LUIGI">
         <dialogue> So you got my e-mail.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Oh, man. Y'all is gonna have a great time. Everybody! This here's Finn McMissile. He's a secret agent. Don't tell nobody. And this is Holley Shiftwell. She's ---</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(WHISPERS) </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> I'm Mater's girlfriend. It's so nice to meet you all.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Everyone is shocked. Including Mater. Guido's jaw drops. </meta>
      <char name="LUIGI">
         <dialogue> Guido believe you now.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(TO MATER)  FLO</meta>
      <char name="(TO HOLLEY)">
         <dialogue> Whoa, honey. You got a nasty dent there.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Indeed, Holley still wears the dent from when she saved Mater from Grem and Acer.  VAN (already crushing on her) Was that from when you swooped in and saved them in London? </meta>
      <char name="MINNY">
         <dialogue> Van!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  VAN What? I'm just asking.  FLO</meta>
      <char name="(TO HOLLEY)">
         <dialogue> Don't you worry, sweet pea. My baby Ramone can get that fixed up for you in no time.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="RAMONE">
         <dialogue> Yeah, sure thing. No problemo. Just let me go get my tools. 130.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Oh no no. I'm keeping that dent. It's way too valuable.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Mater takes this in. </meta>
      <char name="LIZZIE">
         <dialogue> A &quot;valuable&quot; dent? Oh, she's as crazy as Mater.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MACK">
         <dialogue> Those two are perfect for each other.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> You know, there's one thing I still don't get. The bad guys hit me with the beam from the camera, right? So why didn't I, you know...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Explode in a fiery inferno?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Yeah.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> We couldn't figure that one out either.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Our investigation proved that Allinol was actually gasoline. And Miles Axlerod engineered it so that when it got hit by the beam it would explode.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Wait a second. Fillmore, you said my fuel was safe.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  McQueen turns to Fillmore. Everyone does. </meta>
      <char name="FILLMORE">
         <dialogue> If you're implying that I switched out that rotgut excuse for alternative fuel with my all- natural, sustainable, organic biofuel just because I never trusted Axlerod, you're dead wrong, man. It was him. 131.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(RE: SARGE)  </meta>
      <char name="SARGE">
         <dialogue> Once Big Oil, always Big Oil. Man.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FILLMORE">
         <dialogue> Tree hugger.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="109">EXT. MAIN STREET - LATER
</sceneheader>
      <meta> A banner says &quot;Radiator Springs Grand Prix.&quot;  SHERIFF rolls up the street. </meta>
      <char name="SHERIFF">
         <dialogue> The Radiator Springs Grand Prix is about to begin! All spectators clear the starting line!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  MCQUEEN heads up Main Street, other racers following. </meta>
      <char name="LEWIS HAMILTON">
         <dialogue> Man, I can't wait to get rockin'. This is gonna be wicked.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="JEFF GORVETTE">
         <dialogue> Yeah, we should do this every year.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> I just figured, we never found out who the world's fastest car is. Plus: no press, no trophy. Just racing - the way I like it.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FRANCESCO">
         <dialogue> Francesco likes it like this too.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  McQueen SEES Sally. He and Francesco approach her. </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Francesco. I'd like you to meet ---</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FRANCESCO">
         <dialogue> Signorina Sally. It is official: Lightning McQueen is the luckiest car in the world.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="SALLY">
         <dialogue> Why, thank you ---</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(SWOONING) </meta>
      <char name="FRANCESCO">
         <dialogue> Which he will have to be to have a chance against Francesco today.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Francesco turns to leave. As he's moving away:</meta>
      <char name="132.">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="FRANCESCO">
         <dialogue> See you at the finish line, Mc---</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Francesco STOPS. </meta>
      <char name="FRANCESCO">
         <dialogue> What is that?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  McQueen has a new bumper sticker: &quot;Ka-ciao, Francesco.&quot; </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> It's just something I had made up for the occasion.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FRANCESCO">
         <dialogue> Is good, McQueen. Very funny. It was funnier when I did it, but it's very funny. What are you going to do next? Are you going to take off your fenders? Try it. You'll like it.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Francesco leaves. We stay with McQueen and Sally. </meta>
      <char name="SALLY">
         <dialogue> So he's not so good-looking.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Yeah. Nice try.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="SALLY">
         <dialogue> I'm serious.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> That's why I love you, Sally. Wish me luck.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(as he leaves) </meta>
      <char name="SALLY">
         <dialogue> You don't need it!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  He drives off. Flo approaches Sally.  FLO Mmm-mmm. That Francesco is fine- looking. </meta>
      <char name="SALLY">
         <dialogue> And those open wheels.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  FLO I'm gonna have to go get myself some coolant.</meta>
      <char name="133.">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="110">EXT. MAIN STREET - LATER
</sceneheader>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="111">EXT. WILLY'S BUTTE - DAY
</sceneheader>
      <meta> As the racers, led by McQueen and Francesco, take the wide, sweeping turn around Willy's Butte we CRANE UP to see MATER, FINN, HOLLEY, and the Radiator Springs gang watching. Everyone CHEERS. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Go McQueen!! Whoo-hoo!!!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Holley gets an alert. </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Finn, time to go. Siddeley's gassed, geared and ready to fly.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Finn starts to back up. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> You're leaving already?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> We've got another mission, Mater. Just stopped by here to &quot;pick something up.&quot;</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  They both eye Mater, expectantly. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Something tells me you're not talking about souvenir bumper stickers.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Her Majesty asked for you personally, Mater.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> But I told you all before. I'm not a spy.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> We know. 134.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> Spy or not, you're still the smartest, most honest chap we've ever met.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> Don't forget massively charming.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  Mater looks over at Holley. He looks touched. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Well, thanks. But as much fun as it was hanging with y'all, this...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  He looks over to his friends who watch the race, CHEER</meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN ON.">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> This is home.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="HOLLEY">
         <dialogue> That's alright, we understand. But I'll be back. You still owe me that first date.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="FINN">
         <dialogue> If there's ever anything I can do for you, just let me know.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Well, I sure appreciate that, thank you. Actually... there is one thing. CUT TO:</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene>
      <sceneheader id="112">EXT. RADIATOR SPRINGS - MOMENTS LATER
</sceneheader>
      <meta> MATER, blazing forward fast. </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Whoo-hoo!!!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  He ROCKETS FORWARD, through the whole town. In doing so he GRABS A BROKEN DOWN OTIS, hooking him --- </meta>
      <char name="OTIS">
         <dialogue> Whoa!!!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  --- and TOSSING him right into Ramone's. </meta>
      <char name="OTIS (O.S.)">
         <dialogue> Thanks, Mater! 135.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>   ON THE &quot;RACE TRACK&quot; - Mater flies past ALL the racers, including Francesco --- </meta>
      <char name="FRANCESCO">
         <dialogue> Impossible!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  --- until he approaches MCQUEEN. </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> Mater!?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Check it out. They let me keep the rockets!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>(KEEPING PACE) </meta>
      <char name="MCQUEEN">
         <dialogue> I'll see you at the finish line, buddy!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta> </meta>
      <char name="MATER">
         <dialogue> Not if I see you first!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta>  McQueen and Mater peel away from the rest of the racers, lead them off the road and into the dirt for another lap. The two friends are side by side when we FADE OUT.  </meta>
      <char name="THE END">
         <dialogue/>
      </char>
   </scene>
</movie>
