<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<movie>
   <info>Pitch Black
Writers : David Twohy
Genres : HorrorSci-FiThriller</info>
   <scene id="s0">
      <sceneheader>MOVIEBEGINNING</sceneheader>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s1">
      <sceneheader>INT. MAIN CABIN</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s1m1">A CRYO-LOCKER BLOWS OPEN, spitting out... CAROLYN FRY. She hits the deck of the main cabin: Four crew lockers in a forward section, countless more in back. But the deck is canted at a sick angle and ALARMS SCREAM everywhere: The world is dying around her. Legs wobbly, shivering like a flu victim, Fry stumbles to the next forward locker. It's riddled with holes. One DEAD CREWIE is seen through fractured plexi, body pocked and bloodied. But in the next cryo-locked... The CAPTAIN is struggling awake. Fry's face floods with relief. Slapping an intercom:</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s1d1">Hear me? Cap'n? Some kinda compromise to the hull...holding for now, but...Goddamn, I'm glad you're alive. Gotta pull your E-release...no, red handle, red handle. I'll get the warm-ups out while --</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s1m2">PHFUT-PHFUT-PHFUT-PHFUT: Particles bore through the cabin, blasting open the captain's chest, shattering plexi, DETONATING INSTRUMENTS on the opposite wall and leaving CONTRAILS HISSING in the air. Fry lands on her ass, horrified. Suddenly... Another LOCKER BLOWS OPEN. A body falls right on top of Fry -- but this one's still alive. Disoriented, frantic:</meta>
      <char name="OWENS">
         <dialogue id="s1d2">Why did I fall on you?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s1d3">He's dead. Cap'n's dead. Christ, I was looking right at him when --</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="OWENS">
         <dialogue id="s1d4">I mean, I mean, chrono shows we're 22 weeks out, so gravity wasn't supposed to kick in for another 19. I mean, I mean, I mean, why did I fall at all?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s1d5">You hear me? Captain's dead. Owens too.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="OWENS">
         <dialogue id="s1d6">Oh, no. Not Owens, not.... Wai', wai', wait. I'm Owens. Right?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s1m7">They swap nightmare looks, momentarily unsure of their own identities.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s1d7">Cryo-sleep. Swear to God, it sloughs brain cells.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s2">
      <sceneheader>INT. NAV-BAY - MAIN CABIN</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s2m1">They stumble into nav-bay. ALARMS CONTINUE. Fry grabs warm-up suits out of storage, pitches one to Owens, checks her screens.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s2d1">1550 millibars, dropping 20 MB per minute, shit, we're hemorrhaging air. Somethin' took a swipe at us.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="OWENS">
         <dialogue id="s2d2">Just tell me we're still in the shipping lane. Just show me all those stars, all those bright, beautiful, deep-space....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s2m3">Owens activates an exterior view: A planet rushes up at us. That's why they have gravity.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s2d3">Jesus God....</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s3">
      <sceneheader>EXT. SHIP - PLANET'S ATMOSPHERE - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s3m1">The SHIP PLOWS through the upper atmosphere, antennae pylons already disintegrating.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s4">
      <sceneheader>INT. PASSAGE TO FLIGHT DECK</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s4m1">Heart battering her ribs, Fry runs forward, using hand-holds to steady herself. Over a headset:</meta>
      <char name="OWENS (V.O.)">
         <dialogue id="s4d1">They trained you for this, right? Fry? FRY?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s4m2">She doesn't answer.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s5">
      <sceneheader>INT. FLIGHT DECK - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s5m1">Fry harnesses in, starts running switches -- but fumbles a few times, making mental errors. Finally she gets crash-shutters open to reveal... CLOUD STRATA sweeping up past the windscreen like floor-lights on a dropping elevator. We're shedding big altitude.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s6">
      <sceneheader>INT. NAV-BAY - MAIN CABIN</sceneheader>
      <char name="OWENS">
         <dialogue id="s6d1">... crisis program selected Number Two of this system because it shows at least some oxygen and more than 1,500 -- would you SHUT THE FUCK UP! (hammers a button,</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="SILENCES ALARMS)">
         <dialogue id="s6d2">-- more than 1,500-millibars of pressure at surface-level. Okay, so maybe the ship did something right for a change....</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s7">
      <sceneheader>INT. FLIGHT DECK - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s7m1">As Fry runs more switches.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s8">
      <sceneheader>INT. SHIP - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s8m1">As JETTISON DOORS CLOSE around the ship.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s9">
      <sceneheader>INT. FLIGHT DECK - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s9m1">As Fry flips up a security-latch -- and thumbs the switch below.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s10">
      <sceneheader>EXT. SHIP - PLANET'S ATMOSPHERE - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s10m1">MULTIPLE SHOTS: EXPLOSIVE BOLTS RAPID-FIRE around the ship's skin, blowing away non-essentials that hinder aerodynamics -- including big deep-space drives. But this last separation puts the ship into a dangerous roll.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s11">
      <sceneheader>INT. FLIGHT DECK - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s11m1">Out the windscreen, cloud strata roll vertiginously. Fry throws actuators...</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s12">
      <sceneheader>EXT. SHIP - PLANET'S ATMOSPHERE - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s12m1">And airbrakes deploy. She manages to kill the roll. But the ship's still coming in nose-high.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s13">
      <sceneheader>INT. NAV-BAY - MAIN CABIN</sceneheader>
      <char name="OWENS">
         <dialogue id="s13d1">...showing no major water bodies...maximum terrain, 220 meters over mean surface... largely cinder and gypsum with some evaporite deposits....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s13m2">JETTISON DOORS CLOSE behind Owens, segregating him from the passenger compartment. It scares him for a new reason.</meta>
      <char name="OWENS">
         <dialogue id="s13d2">Fry? What're you doing?</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s14">
      <sceneheader>INT. FLIGHT DECK - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s14m1">Fry flips up a new security-latch. INTERCUTTING:</meta>
      <char name="OWENS">
         <dialogue id="s14d1">Fry?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s14d2">Can't get my nose down...too much load back there....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="OWENS">
         <dialogue id="s14d3">You mean that &quot;load&quot; of passengers?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s14d4">So what, we should both go down too? Out of sheer fucking nobility?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s14m5">Tortured silence. Fry's thumb moves to the switch that will jettison the passenger cabin. Jettison 50 people.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s15">
      <sceneheader>INT. MAIN CABIN</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s15m1">SELECTED SHOTS of faces inside cryo-lockers, among them JOHNS. He's prime-of-life, badge on display, some kind of cop. Shaken awake, he clears condensation to check the locker directly across from his, finding... RIDDICK. Small black goggles hide his eyes. A metal bit wedged in his mouth lends a perpetual grimace. A read-out admonishes &quot;LOCK-OUT PROTOCOL IN EFFECT. ABSOLUTELY NO EARLY</meta>
      <char name="RELEASE.&quot;">
         <dialogue id="s15d1"/>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s16">
      <sceneheader>INT. FLIGHT DECK - DAY</sceneheader>
      <char name="OWENS">
         <dialogue id="s16d1">Look, Fry. Company says we're responsible for every one of those --</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s16d2">Company's not here, is it?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="OWENS">
         <dialogue id="s16d3">When captain went down, you stepped up -- whether you like it or not. Now they train you for this, so --</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s16d4">And there wasn't a simulated cockroach alive within 50 clicks of the simulated crash site! That's how they train you! On a fucking simulator!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s16m5">Owens unbuckles from his chair.</meta>
      <char name="OWENS">
         <dialogue id="s16d5">Don't touch that switch!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s16m6">Overcome by guilt, Fry retracts her thumb of mass destruction. But a HUGE JOLT puts the thumb right back.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s16d6">I'm not dying for them.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s16m7">She pushes it. But this time...</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s17">
      <sceneheader>EXT. SHIP - PLANET'S ATMOSPHERE - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s17m1">No bolts fire. Nothing separates from the SHIP THAT SCREAMS DOWN through the clouds.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s18">
      <sceneheader>INT. NAV-BAY - MAIN CABIN</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s18m1">Now we see why: Owens reopened the jettison doors locally -- and blocked them open.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s18d1">Owens!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="OWENS">
         <dialogue id="s18d2">70 seconds! You still got 70 seconds to level this beast out!</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s19">
      <sceneheader>INT. FLIGHT DECK - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s19m1">Seething anger and guilt, Fry pops more airbrakes, shedding more speed, more heat. The ship does level -- but it's still being pounded hellishly. She tries to get a stable view out... The windscreen. We're breaking through cloud-bottoms. There's just a glimpse of landscape before...</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s20">
      <sceneheader>EXT. SHIP - PLANET'S ATMOSPHERE - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s20m1">An airbrake fails. It shears off and pinwheels into...</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s21">
      <sceneheader>INT. FLIGHT DECK - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s21m1">The windscreen. It cracks into a thousand spiderwebs -- but impossibly it holds. For now.</meta>
      <char name="OWENS (V.O.)">
         <dialogue id="s21d1">What the shit was that?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s21m2">Sunlight flares from every fractured edge: It's like looking into burning diamonds, and Fry can only get an impression of the outside world. Now she has to rely on... A ground-mapping display. 120 meters altitude. And dropping.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s22">
      <sceneheader>INT. CRYO-LOCKER - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s22m1">INTERCUT Johns. Realizing he's in some kind of shit-storm, he claws at safety restraints.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s23">
      <sceneheader>INT. FLIGHT DECK - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s23m1">Ground-mapper: 60 meters. COLLISION ALARMS kick in. Out the fractured windscreen, we see a huge dark mass rise up into view. Land. 40 meters...30...20...10.... Fry braces. IMPACT. The WINDSCREENS IMPLODE. AIR HURRICANES in.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s24">
      <sceneheader>INT. NAV-BAY - MAIN CABIN</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s24m1">IMPACT. Chairs rip from their moorings. Strapped into one, Owens slams into the ceiling.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s25">
      <sceneheader>INT. MAIN CABIN - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s25m1">IMPACT. Johns BLOWS OUT of his locker -- and wishes to God he would've stayed inside, because just beside him... The hull is cracking open. NIGHTMARE SHOT: A huge section of the cabin tears free... skitters and CRASHES along the planetfloor behind us...and disintegrates out of sight. 40 cryo-lockers vanished with it. 40 lives.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s26">
      <sceneheader>INT. FLIGHT DECK - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s26m1">Hammered by WIND, Fry opens her eyes experimentally. FRY'S POV: A vortex of motion, of speed, of blurring debris. But the ship is burrowing in. Burrowing under. Fry pivots her chair 180 degrees a nanosecond before... Dirt avalanches into the cockpit. It buries CAMERA.</meta>
      <char name="BLACKOUT">
         <dialogue id="s26d1"/>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s27">
      <sceneheader>INT. MAIN CABIN - CRASH SHIP - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s27m1">Choking yellow dust. Ghostly silhouettes are COUGHING, MOANING, CALLING OUT to other survivors in English and, surreally, in Arabic. Soon we find... Johns. Ears running blood. Stumbling his way to... Riddick's cryo-locker. Empty. Johns reaches for his holster. Gone, torn right off his belt. No prisoner and no weapon -- spooky combination. Nearby he sees... The light of a cutting torch. Someone's using it to open a jammed cryo-locker. The plexi is torched away to reveal... AUDREY, 12 years old. Unscathed.</meta>
      <char name="AUDREY">
         <dialogue id="s27d1">Somethin' went wrong, huh?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s27m2">Johns searches for his pistol. Behind him, two chained feet lower into FRAME -- and then attack, swinging over Johns' head... getting the chain on his neck...twisting hard, using the chain as a choke-collar. Johns flicks open a baton, swings it up at... Riddick. Still in body chains and mouth-bit. Clinging to a ceiling support. Riding out the baton blows. Seconds from blacking out, Johns strains forward...forward...and finally breaks Riddick's grip on the support. He keeps hold of the chained feet so that... Riddick SLAMS HEADFIRST into the deck. Johns lays the baton on his neck.</meta>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s27d2">One chance and you blew it, Riddick. Never cease to disappoint me.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s28">
      <sceneheader>INT. FLIGHT DECK - CRASH SHIP - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s28m1">Darkness. A light beam sweeps the dusty air of the cockpit. It's packed with dirt, no signs of life. About to search elsewhere, Johns turns back at...</meta>
      <char name="FRY (O.S.)">
         <dialogue id="s28d1">Hey.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s28d2">Hey, who?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY (O.S.)">
         <dialogue id="s28d3">Hey, me. Over here.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s28m4">His light finds a headrest sticking up from the dirt. Johns crawls closer, checks the other side of the headrest and finds her. Fry. Buried to the gills.</meta>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s28d4">Amazing. I'm Johns.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s28d5">Carolyn Fry. I'd shake hands, but...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s28m6">He manages a smile and starts digging her out. Almost dreading to ask:</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s28d6">Are there any others, Johns?</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s29">
      <sceneheader>INT. MAIN CABIN - CRASH SHIP - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s29m1">Johns helps Fry through the carnage. She's stunned by it all -- but especially by the blast of sunlight where a hull used to be. Realizing she's in nav-bay, Fry starts digging like a search dog to uncover... Owens. Still strapped to his chair. Metal rod piercing his chest close to the heart. Dead. Fry reaches out to touch him.</meta>
      <char name="OWENS">
         <dialogue id="s29d1">Out, out, out, GET IT OUTTA ME!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s29m2">She recoils hard. He's still alive. The other survivors bungle over. Ten seconds of pure chaos:</meta>
      <char name="VOICES">
         <dialogue id="s29d2">Pull it out of him...No, it's too close to the heart...You gotta do it, just do it fast....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s29m3">Fry grabs the rod.</meta>
      <char name="OWENS">
         <dialogue id="s29d3">Don't touch it! Don't touch that switch!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="VOICES">
         <dialogue id="s29d4">You'll kill him, I'm tellin' you, shit, just leave it alone...delirious...doncha you got some drugs for this poor man....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="OWENS">
         <dialogue id="s29d5">Don't touch that switch!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s29d6">Awright, awright, someone...there's Anestaphine in the med-lock, that end of the cabin...next to....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s29m7">But there is no more &quot;that end.&quot; In exquisite pain, Owens screams on. REACTION SHOTS of Johns, Audrey. Seldom are human beings witness to such raw suffering.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s29d7">Get away. Everybody.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s29m8">The others leave -- except for Audrey, staying behind to watch in morbid fascination. Johns doubles back and collars her. Leaving, they pass... Riddick, cuffed to a bulkhead. His eyes, still hidden by goggles, track Johns and Audrey toward daylight.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s30">
      <sceneheader>EXT. CRASH SHIP - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s30m1">The survivors straggle outside. CAMERA SURVEYS new faces: ZEKE and SHAZZA. Male-female team of bushwhackers, partners in life. Shazza has a tough sexiness. Zeke's face shows aboriginal blood. (30s.) PARIS. Overfed, overgroomed. A puff pastry of a man. (40s or 50s.) Four male &quot;Chrislams&quot;: The pillar-steady IMAM (50ish), and THREE PILGRIMS, young and excitable (late-teens). (NOTE: The Chrislams represent a union between Christianity and Islam. They have the iconography of Christians yet the physical look of Arab Muslims.) WIDE SHOT: All around them is stark and unforgiving terrain. The valley floor is relieved only by low hills to one side, spiked with earthen spires. Scorching down on everything are two suns -- one red, one yellow.</meta>
      <char name="PARIS">
         <dialogue id="s30d1">Well. Our own little slice of heaven.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s30m2">The Chrislams fall to their knees. Confusion as they try to orient themselves.</meta>
      <char name="IMAM">
         <dialogue id="s30d2">Please...which way to New Mecca? We must know the direction in order to pray.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s30m3">North? South? East? West? Nobody knows. Johns snaps open a compass, finds the needle swaying rudderlessly. The SCREAMING inside the ship finally ends.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s31">
      <sceneheader>INT. CRASH SHIP - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s31m1">As Fry holds Owens, now dead.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s32">
      <sceneheader>EXT. CRASH SHIP - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s32m1">The four Chrislams have devised a way to pray: Backs together, each faces a different compass point.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s33">
      <sceneheader>EXT. TOP OF CRASH SHIP - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s33m1">Fry climbs onto the back of the ship. Johns Paris, Zeke, Shazza, Audrey are already here.</meta>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s33d1">Big talk about a scouting party...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s33m2">Fry sees the huge smoldering scar in the ground behind the ship. One glance confirms that there are no other survivors.</meta>
      <char name="JOHNS (CONT'D)">
         <dialogue id="s33d2">...then we saw this.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="PARIS">
         <dialogue id="s33d3">Anyone else having breathing problems? Aside from me?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="AUDREY">
         <dialogue id="s33d4">Like I just ran, or something....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="SHAZZA">
         <dialogue id="s33d5">Feel one lung short. All of us.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="PARIS">
         <dialogue id="s33d6">Well, I tend toward the asthmatic. And with all this dust....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s33m7">Faces turn to Fry: They're looking to her for answers.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s33d7">It's the atmosphere. Too much pressure, not enough oxygen. Might take a few days to --</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="ZEKE">
         <dialogue id="s33d8">So what the bloody hell happened, anyways?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s33d9">Somethin' knocked us off-lane. Maybe a rogue comet. Maybe we'll never know.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="SHAZZA">
         <dialogue id="s33d10">Well, I for one, am thoroughly fucking grateful. This beast wasn't made to land like this. But cripes, you rode it down. (to others) C'mon, you lousy ingrates, only reason we're alive is a'cuzza her.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s33m11">Others CHIME AGREEMENT, laying thankful hands on Fry's shoulders. HOLD on Fry, her face betraying nothing as they anoint her their savior.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s34">
      <sceneheader>INT. MAIN CABIN - CRASH SHIP - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s34m1">Breaking out pressure suits:</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s34d1">Liquid oxygen canisters inside. Start ripping them out. Quick hits only -- try to make it last.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="AUDREY">
         <dialogue id="s34d2">Well, is someone coming for us? Or are we all just gonna die of exposure or dehydration or sunstroke or maybe even something worse? (off their looks) Hey, you don't have to worry about scaring me.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="SHAZZA">
         <dialogue id="s34d3">We're worried you'll scare us. (ushering her away) Name's &quot;Audrey,&quot; right, love? And you're goin' to Taurus Three like we were?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="AUDREY">
         <dialogue id="s34d4">Yeah, but...do we even have enough food to get there? Or will we have to resort to cannibalism?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="ZEKE">
         <dialogue id="s34d5">(to Fry) I'll see 'bout makin' this air go a bit further, cap'n. With your permission, a' course.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s34m6">Fry blinks. &quot;They actually think I'm the captain.&quot; Zeke and the others get to work. Fry finds herself staring at another problem. Riddick.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s34d6">And him?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s34d7">Big Evil?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s34d8">We just keep him locked up forever?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s34d9">Be my choice. Already escaped once from the max-slam facility on --</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s34d10">I don't need his life story. Is he really that dangerous?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s34d11">Only around humans.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s34m12">Riddick has his mouth on the hull, virtually licking the metal. Fry moves closer -- and now sees it sheeting down the hull.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s34d12">Oh, Christ....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s34m13">They're losing water. Suddenly Fry is running, snatching up an emergency light, climbing wall-rungs...</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s35">
      <sceneheader>INT. MACHINE LEVEL - CRASH SHIP - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s35m1">And crawling through dusty superstructure to reach the water cistern. She opens a crank-hatch -- and finds light invading the interior. Her face dies.</meta>
      <char name="ZEKE (V.O.)">
         <dialogue id="s35d1">(shouting) Well? Is it just the pump?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s35d2">Ask if anyone has anything in cargo! Anything to drink!</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s36">
      <sceneheader>INT. CARGO HOLD - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s36m1">Oversize DOORS RUMBLE open. Fry, Johns, and Paris climb into this dark corridor lined with cargo containers. Each container has an access door.</meta>
      <char name="PARIS">
         <dialogue id="s36d1">Mine here....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s36m2">As Paris unlocks, Johns steadies himself, suddenly light-headed.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s36d2">S'matter?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s36d3">Little swamp-flu from the Conga system. Never shook it with all this cryo-sleep.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s36m4">Paris opens his container to reveal...</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s37">
      <sceneheader>INT. PARIS' CONTAINER - CARGO HOLD - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s37m1">Tiffany chairs stacked 10 high. Bronze eagle lecterns. Oriental umbrellas. Neo-Egyptian castings.</meta>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s37d1">King Tut's tomb....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="PARIS">
         <dialogue id="s37d2">Be surprised what these will fetch in the Taurus system. Here. This Wooten here -- easy, easy. Very rare.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s37m3">They open the Wooten desk. Cubbyholed inside are dusty bottles of sherry. Vintage Port. Glenfiddich. Bicardi 151.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s37d3">This is it? Booze? That's what you have to drink?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="PARIS">
         <dialogue id="s37d4">(educating her) 200-year-old single-malt scotch is to &quot;booze&quot; as foie gras is to &quot;duck guts.&quot;</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s37d5">(cracking a bottle) A toast to whatever he just said.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="PARIS">
         <dialogue id="s37d6">I'll need a receipt for that. (to Fry) For all these.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s37d7">Top of my list.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s37m8">She joins Johns for a drink. Entering, the Chrislams watch with both envy and aversion.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s37d8">I don't suppose....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="IMAM">
         <dialogue id="s37d9">One of the Christian habits we didn't adopt -- perhaps unfortunately. We'll have to wait.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s37d10">For what? There is no water. You understand that, don't you?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="IMAM">
         <dialogue id="s37d11">All deserts have water, somewhere. God shall lead us there.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s38">
      <sceneheader>INT. MAIN CABIN - CRASH SHIP - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s38m1">START on the cutting torch, abandoned in wreckage. Staring at it is... Riddick. With his hands cuffed behind him and around a bulkhead, he can't get near it. Or can he? Near the ceiling, the bulkhead is fractured -- a slim spot where maybe chains could pass through. Riddick stands. With a GRUESOME POPPING, he dislocates both shoulders...carries his arms overhead...passes the chains through the broken spot...and brings his arms down in front of him. A body-flex POPS HIS SHOULDERS back into joint. Free, he reaches for the cutting torch.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s39">
      <sceneheader>EXT. CRASH SHIP - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s39m1">Pistol in hand, Johns runs into a BIG CLOSEUP, eyes sweeping. Nothing on the horizon. But something lies on the ground nearby. It's Riddick's mouth-bit.</meta>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s39d1">Like we needed another way to die.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s40">
      <sceneheader>INT. CARGO HOLD - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s40m1">FAST CLOSEUPS: Hands pillaging storage lockers, pulling out anything that might qualify as a &quot;weapon.&quot; It all gets hauled back and dumped into...</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s41">
      <sceneheader>INT. NAV BAY - CRASH SHIP - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s41m1">Nav-bay. Gathered, the survivors take inventory: Johns has a pistol, shotgun, baton. Zeke and Shazza offer up a pick-ax, digging tools, hunting boomerang. Imam shows a ceremonial blade. Paris straggles in with antique curios.</meta>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s41d1">What the hell are these?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="PARIS">
         <dialogue id="s41d2">Maratha crow-bill war-picks from Northern India. Very rare.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="ZEKE">
         <dialogue id="s41d3">An' this?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="PARIS">
         <dialogue id="s41d4">Blow-dart hunting stick from Papua New Guinea. Very very rare, since the tribe's extinct.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="ZEKE">
         <dialogue id="s41d5">'Cuz they couldn't hunt shit with these things, be my guess.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="PARIS">
         <dialogue id="s41d6">Well, what's the need, anyway? If he's gone, he's gone. Why should he bother us?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s41d7">First, because he can only live out there for so long -- he's gonna come back and take what we got. Second, for the sheer thrill of the kill.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s41m8">A beat. They all grab for weapons.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s42">
      <sceneheader>EXT. CRASH SHIP - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s42m1">Johns stands atop the crash ship, scanning with a scope. He fixates on... A blue glow on the horizon. &quot;What the hell is it?&quot; Zeke and Shazza modify breather units, adding straps and tubing and ball-floats. The prototype is tested on Audrey. She sucks on the mouthpiece -- and finds that it works, supplying oxygen on demand rather than in a constant flow. Chrislams convert to traditional bedouin head-gear, readying for travel. Fry finishes wrapping Owens' body. She looks to the yellow sun, low on the horizon. The red sun seems inclined to follow.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s42d1">Imam. We should leave soon. Before nightfall but while it's cooler.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="ZEKE">
         <dialogue id="s42d2">What, you're goin' off, too?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s42d3">Johns is leaving you a gun. Just do me a favor, huh? Get my crewies buried? They were good guys who died bad.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="SHAZZA">
         <dialogue id="s42d4">A'course we will.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="PILGRIM #1 (O.S.)">
         <dialogue id="s42d5">Imam...Imam....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s42m6">(NOTE: &quot;Imam&quot; is pronounced &quot;el-ee-MAM.&quot;) Fry and the others round the ship to see... A blue star flaring into view. It's rising as the other suns are setting.</meta>
      <char name="SHAZZA">
         <dialogue id="s42d6">My bloody oath....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="AUDREY">
         <dialogue id="s42d7">Three suns?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="ZEKE">
         <dialogue id="s42d8">(to Fry) So much for your nightfall.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="PARIS">
         <dialogue id="s42d9">So much for my cocktail hour.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="IMAM">
         <dialogue id="s42d10">We take this to be a good sign -- a path, a direction from God.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s42m11">Johns swings down from the top of the ship.</meta>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s42d11">A very good sign. (re: blue sun) That's Riddick's direction. You do not wanna be caught in the dark with this guy.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s42d12">Thought you found his restraints over there. Toward sunset.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s42d13">(nodding) Which means he went toward sunrise.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s43">
      <sceneheader>EXT. PLANET - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s43m1">Trekking, the Chrislams waft incense pots and CHANT FROM THE KORAN as they head toward the blue star. Johns provides shotgun escort; Fry carries Paris' second war-pick on a shoulder. Silhouetted against the alien sky, the scouting party is an odd, odd sight. Already sun-battered, Johns crafts an eye-visor out of plexi. Fry tries to wrap her head like the Chrislams. Imam helps.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s43d1">So quiet. You get used to the sounds of the ship, then....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="IMAM">
         <dialogue id="s43d2">You know who Muhammad was?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s43d3">Some prophet guy?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="IMAM">
         <dialogue id="s43d4">&quot;Some prophet guy.&quot; And a city man. But he had to travel to the desert -- where there was quiet -- to hear the words of God.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s43d5">You were on a pilgrimage? To New Mecca?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="IMAM">
         <dialogue id="s43d6">(nodding) Chrislam teaches that once in every lifetime should there be a great hajj -- a great pilgrimage. To know God, better, yes, but to know yourself as well.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s43d7">Frightening thought.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="IMAM">
         <dialogue id="s43d8">(finishes wrapping her) We're all on the same hajj now.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s43m9">Fry notices Johns scope-locked on something.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s43d9">What?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s43d10">(hands her scope) Tell me it's not a mirage.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s43m11">SCOPE POV: Beyond a distant rise, strange branches.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s43d11">Trees?</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s44">
      <sceneheader>EXT. CRASH SHIP - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s44m1">Paris has taken over as look-out atop the ship. He deals with the heat by erecting a &quot;misting&quot; umbrella: He fills a reservoir with liquor, dials up a regulator. Umbrella spars shoot bursts of cooling alcohol vapor. Paris luxuriates in it.</meta>
      <char name="ZEKE (O.S.)">
         <dialogue id="s44d1">Comfy up there?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s44m2">Zeke appears below. He loads a scrap-metal sled with tarp, cable, pick-ax.</meta>
      <char name="PARIS">
         <dialogue id="s44d2">Amazing how you can do without the essentials of life -- so long as you have the luxuries.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="ZEKE">
         <dialogue id="s44d3">Well, just keep your bloody-fuckin' eyes open. Don't want that ratbag sneakin' up on me bloody-fuckin' arse.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s44m4">He drags the sled toward the spired hills. Keeping one eye on Zeke, Paris eases into a chair, lays the war-pick across his lap, pours himself a spot of sherry. As he sips, a blade touches his throat.</meta>
      <char name="AUDREY">
         <dialogue id="s44d4">He'd probably get you right here, right under the jaw. And you'd never hear him coming. That's how good Riddick is.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s44m5">Paris eases the hunting boomerang away.</meta>
      <char name="PARIS">
         <dialogue id="s44d5">Now did you run away from your parents? Or did they run away from you?</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s45">
      <sceneheader>EXT. BONEYARD OVERLOOK - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s45m1">The scouting party approaches a rise. The trees loom just beyond.</meta>
      <char name="PILGRIMS">
         <dialogue id="s45d1">Allahu Akbar...Allahu Akbar....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s45m2">The young pilgrims break into a excited run, anticipating an oasis. But Fry hangs back, taking a harder look at the trees. They don't move in the wind. The pilgrims scramble up the rise -- and go motionless. Fry, Johns and Imam catch up to behold... The &quot;trees&quot; are actually the dorsal bones of a titanic skeleton, tinted green by lichen. Beyond is a sea of bleached animal bones. Impossibly, the bones seem to MOAN IN PAIN. All told, it's like Hell overflowed right here.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s45d2">Is this whole planet dead?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s45m3">A pilgrim questions Imam IN ARABIC.</meta>
      <char name="IMAM">
         <dialogue id="s45d3">He asks what could have killed so many great things...</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s46">
      <sceneheader>EXT. BONEYARD - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s46m1">Moving into the boneyard:</meta>
      <char name="IMAM">
         <dialogue id="s46d1">Some...communal graveyard, perhaps... like the elephants of Earth....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s46m2">Fry touches one of the towering bones. It shows cut-marks -- almost as if the bone was hacked by a sword. &quot;Graveyard? Or killing field?&quot;</meta>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s46d2">Long time ago. Whatever happened.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s47">
      <sceneheader>EXT. SKULL - BONEYARD - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s47m1">Pilgrim #1 reaches a huge skull laced with baleen-like combing. Wind hitting the comb makes a LOW HARMONIC MOANING. By moving a hand over the comb, the pilgrim can &quot;play&quot; DIRGELIKE MUSIC. Wanting to show off the trick:</meta>
      <char name="PILGRIM #1">
         <dialogue id="s47d1">Ah....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s47m2">He looks for Pilgrim #3 but can't spot him. And when he turns back to the skull -- a face is staring through the combing. But it's only...</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s48">
      <sceneheader>INT. SKULL - BONEYARD - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s48m1">Pilgrim #3, inside the skull. Johns enters and chases him out. About to leave, Johns notices... Bone-chippings piled on the ground. It could be nothing, but still... Johns double-checks shadows, probing with the muzzle of his shotgun. Satisfied, Johns exits. Now BOOM UP to reveal... Riddick. Hidden in a sinus cavity.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s49">
      <sceneheader>EXT. SKULL - BONEYARD - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s49m1">Trailing the others, Fry pauses to change out the O2 on her breather.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s50">
      <sceneheader>INT. SKULL - BONEYARD - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s50m1">Riddick drops to the ground. His arms and hands are now pierced with shards of boneyard ivory -- fashionable little body talons. Spotting a shadow on the combing, he draws closer. And sees Fry. Alone.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s51">
      <sceneheader>EXT. SKULL - BONEYARD - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s51m1">Johns doubles back to Fry. He takes a hit of scotch, offers her some.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s51d1">Probably makes it worse. Dehydrates you even more.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s51d2">Probably right.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s51m3">They drink anyway. Moving out of the sun, Fry leans up against the combing. It brings her within arm's length of...</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s52">
      <sceneheader>INT. SKULL - BONEYARD - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s52m1">Riddick. He pulls a bone-shiv, freshly chiseled.</meta>
      <char name="JOHNS (O.S.)">
         <dialogue id="s52d1">You know, I woulda played road dog for these guys. You could've stayed back. Pro'bly should've -- because, you know, if we don't find water....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s52m2">&quot;We may not make it back.&quot;</meta>
      <char name="FRY (O.S.)">
         <dialogue id="s52d2">No, no, I wanted to get away.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS (O.S.)">
         <dialogue id="s52d3">So I noticed. Never seen a &quot;captain&quot; quite so ready to leave her ship.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s52m4">Just as Riddick eases his blade toward Fry's neck...</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s53">
      <sceneheader>EXT. SKULL - BONEYARD - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s53m1">She steps away.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s53d1">Better keep moving....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s53d2">What'd Owens mean? 'Bout not touching the switch?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s53m3">Fry searches his eyes, wondering if she can trust him -- and again she leans back on the combing. We can actually see Riddick now. They could too, if they would just TURN THE FUCK AROUND!</meta>
      <char name="JOHNS (CONT'D)">
         <dialogue id="s53d3">Hey. You can tell me, Carolyn.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s53d4">Promise me. Swear to me you won't --</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s53d5">You see anybody else here? Just between you and me.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s53d6">During the landing...when things were at their worst...Owens was at his best. He's the one who wouldn't let the pilot dump the passenger cabin.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s53m7">Johns blinks, stunned. &quot;Are you shittin' me?&quot;</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s54">
      <sceneheader>INT. SKULL - BONEYARD - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s54m1">Trying again, Riddick reaches out with his shiv -- and deftly slices off some of Fry's hair. A locket. A souvenir. That's all he wanted.</meta>
      <char name="FRY (O.S.)">
         <dialogue id="s54d1">So now you know.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS (O.S.)">
         <dialogue id="s54d2">Fuck. Guess I'm more glad to be here than I thought.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s54m3">Riddick watches them move off -- then looks at the scotch bottle, left behind. It's still got one good swallow.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s55">
      <sceneheader>EXT. START OF GAUNTLET - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s55m1">Leaving the boneyard, the scouting party reaches a cleft in the hills. Ahead is a canyon.</meta>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s55d1">Hold up.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s55m2">He jumps onto a rock, puts the scope to an eye.</meta>
      <char name="JOHNS (CONT'D)">
         <dialogue id="s55d2">Didn't bite.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s55d3">What?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s55d4">Thought he might be coolin' it in the boneyard -- could either double-back to the ship or slip in behind us. So I left the bottle out as bait.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s55m5">SCOPE POV: PANNING the boneyard. FINDING the bottle. It's still got that one swallow.</meta>
      <char name="JOHNS (CONT'D)">
         <dialogue id="s55d5">But nah. Didn't bite.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s56">
      <sceneheader>EXT. BONEYARD - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s56m1">CLOSER on the bottle. Only we see that the scotch has been emptied -- and replaced with sand.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s57">
      <sceneheader>EXT. GRAVE SITE - SPIRED HILLS - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s57m1">Working under the shade of a tarp, Zeke digs a communal grave. Three wrapped corpses wait nearby. He keeps a sight-line on... The crash ship. Shazza waves. Zeke waves back.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s58">
      <sceneheader>EXT. RIBCAGE - THE GAUNTLET - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s58m1">The scouting party transits a narrowing canyon. Lined with rib bones, it makes us feel like we're in the belly of some beast. Fry squints at the ridgetops. More of those spires are visible on the canyon rims, looming like silent sentinels. &quot;What are they? Just mineral deposits?&quot;</meta>
      <char name="PILGRIM #1">
         <dialogue id="s58d1">Captain...captain....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s58m2">The Chrislams have found what appears to be a small desert plant. Leathery petals are spread wide, revealing a round stringy core. ARABIC DISCUSSION. Desert fruit? Is it edible?</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s58d2">Wait, wait, wait....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s58m3">Fry takes the &quot;plant,&quot; pushes the &quot;petals&quot; back down over the core. They all stare. It's a baseball.</meta>
      <char name="IMAM">
         <dialogue id="s58d3">We are not alone here, yes?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s58m4">They look ahead, wondering what awaits them. But Johns is looking back.</meta>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s58d4">Never thought we were.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s59">
      <sceneheader>EXT. SETTLEMENT - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s59m1">HIGH ANGLE: An old WEATHER COCK CREAKS in the wind. Fry, Johns, and the Chrislams enter FRAME far below.</meta>
      <char name="PILGRIM #1">
         <dialogue id="s59d1">Assalamoo ahlaykum!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s59m2">The GREETING ECHOES through the settlement, built from stacked shipping containers. Tattered sun-shades flap in the wind. A rusty bike lies on the ground.</meta>
      <char name="PILGRIM #2">
         <dialogue id="s59d2">Assalamoo ahlaykum!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s59d3">Long gone. Whoever they were.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s59m4">They move around a building -- and pull up short. Before them looms a moisture-recovery unit, a hulking machine in disrepair. Old jugs litter the ground.</meta>
      <char name="IMAM">
         <dialogue id="s59d4">Water...water there was here....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="PILGRIMS">
         <dialogue id="s59d5">Allahu Akbar....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="IMAM">
         <dialogue id="s59d6">(translating) &quot;God is Great,&quot; yes?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s59d7">I'm born-again.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s59m8">Fry manages a weary smile -- but soon her eyes revisit the abandoned buildings. &quot;Who were these people? Why did they leave so much behind?&quot;</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s60">
      <sceneheader>INT. MAIN ROOM - SETTLEMENT - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s60m1">Through a window, we see the Johns and the Chrislams crawling over the moisture-recovery unit, assessing repairs. PULL BACK to include Fry inside the settlement, inspecting... Refectory table. Place settings out. Years of dust. Photos on the wall: Settlers working modest gardens. Playing baseball. Posing with children.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s61">
      <sceneheader>INT. LIVING QUARTERS - SETTLEMENT - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s61m1">Fry enters a dark room.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s61d1">Lights.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s61m2">No response to her command. She pats around for old-style wall switches. Nothing. Perceiving black-out blinds on a window, she throws them open to reveal... A man standing right outside.</meta>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s61d2">(through window) Hey. Don't go too far, huh?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s61m3">Fry nods. Johns smiles, leaves. Just as her heart settles, SOMETHING CREAKS behind her. It's an orrery, a mechanical device that shows the motion of the planets around their suns. Solar powered, the orrery starts turning, CREAKING. One planet seems always to have sunlight.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s61d3">No darkness. No lights because no darkness....</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s62">
      <sceneheader>EXT. PORCH - SETTLEMENT - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s62m1">Fry reaches a porch. It looks out over the rear of the settlement and more unforgiving terrain. She starts back inside -- but something glints at the edge of her vision. Fry turns back...parts clothes on a laundry line...and sees the source of the glint. Excited hits on her breather. Fry vaults off the porch -- and starts walking as if on magnetic bearing. Soon she's running.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s63">
      <sceneheader>EXT. SETTLEMENT - DAY</sceneheader>
      <char name="FRY (V.O.)">
         <dialogue id="s63d1">Allahu Akbar! Allahu Akbar!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s63m2">Johns and the Chrislams trade looks.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s64">
      <sceneheader>EXT. SKIFF - DAY</sceneheader>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s64d1">Allahu Akbar!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s64m2">Fry stops on a groomed runway, out of breath. The others catch up. They too marvel at... The skiff, a light-duty vehicle of hybrid technology -- part bush plane, part space craft. Its fabric wings are wind-torn -- but the hull looks intact.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s65">
      <sceneheader>EXT. TOP OF CRASH SHIP - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s65m1">CLOSE on caviar being added to toast-points. A SCRABBLING SOUND stops Paris in mid-bite. He eases out of his rocker, moves to the rear edge of the ship and looks down on... A shadow ducking under him. Small rocks still trickle down a dirt rampart just climbed by...someone.</meta>
      <char name="PARIS">
         <dialogue id="s65d1">This now qualifies as the worst fun I've ever had. Stop it.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s65m2">No response.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s66">
      <sceneheader>EXT. CRASH SHIP - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s66m1">War-pick in hand, Paris eases to ground-level. He checks the perimeter, looks inside the ship. Nobody. Is he being fucked with? Again? He hopes?</meta>
      <char name="PARIS">
         <dialogue id="s66d1">Audrey? Oh, Audrey....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="AUDREY (O.S.)">
         <dialogue id="s66d2">What?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s66m3">Paris spins. The voice came from the cargo hold -- and not where he expected.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s67">
      <sceneheader>INT. CARGO HOLD - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s67m1">Blades of sunlight stream in through cracks in the hull. Paris enters to find Shazza and Audrey cutting open containers, searching for usable goods.</meta>
      <char name="PARIS">
         <dialogue id="s67d1">Tell me that was you.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="AUDREY">
         <dialogue id="s67d2">Okay, it was me. What'd I do now?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="PARIS">
         <dialogue id="s67d3">Assailing my fragile sense of security, that's what.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="SHAZZA">
         <dialogue id="s67d4">What're you goin' on about? She's been right here for the last....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s67m5">They all see it: Sun-blades are momentarily blocked by something passing outside. Someone.</meta>
      <char name="SHAZZA">
         <dialogue id="s67d5">(a quiet probe) Zeke?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s67m6">No answer. Audrey springs to the other side of hold, puts an eye to a crack there. HULL-CRACK POV: Far away, Zeke finishes digging the grave. He starts toward the ship. Audrey whirls back, mouths a silent alarm: &quot;RIDDICK!&quot; Paris goes bloodless. Shazza grabs the war-pick out of his frozen hands, moves catlike to the main doors and poises there, ready to strike. Audrey follows with the hunting boomerang. All eyes watch as... The sun-blades, winking off and on, chart Riddick's approach: We feel like we're inside a magician's sword box, watching the blades shave closer and closer to us. Suddenly he appears... And Shazza swings hard.</meta>
      <char name="AUDREY">
         <dialogue id="s67d6">No!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s67m7">Facing them is a TOTAL STRANGER -- burned, half naked, one hand still clutching the emergency-release lever of his cryo-locker. Shazza stopped one inch short of killing him.</meta>
      <char name="TOTAL STRANGER">
         <dialogue id="s67d7">I thought...my God, I thought I was the only one who....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s67m8">He lurches toward Shazza, trying to embrace her -- and sees blood and brain-bits BLAM-BLAMMING against her. His own. The stranger sinks bonelessly to the ground. FAST RACK to reveal Zeke in the background, pistol leveled. He reads Shazza's horrified face -- and understands what he's done.</meta>
      <char name="PARIS">
         <dialogue id="s67d8">Oh, Lord....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="AUDREY">
         <dialogue id="s67d9">It was just somebody else. From the crash. He was just....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="ZEKE">
         <dialogue id="s67d10">Cripes galore, I thought it was him. The murderin' ratbag. I thought he was....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s67m11">He rushes over to check the dead stranger. As he bends down, FAST RACK AGAIN to reveal Riddick in the background. He stands 20 paces off, still unseen by the others. His goggle eyes covet... Zeke's breather.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s68">
      <sceneheader>EXT. SKIFF - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s68m1">Fry exits the skiff.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s68d1">No juice, looks like it's been laid up for years. But we might be able to adapt --</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s68d2">Shut up.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s68m3">Outside, Johns has an ear cocked to the wind.</meta>
      <char name="JOHNS (CONT'D)">
         <dialogue id="s68d3">Sorry. Thought I heard something.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s68d4">Like what?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s68d5">Like my pistola.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s69">
      <sceneheader>EXT. GRAVE SITE - SPIRED HILLS - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s69m1">START on the drag-sled carrying Corpse #4-- the stranger. Zeke reaches the grave. The sun-tarp has fallen on one side, blocking the sight-line between ship and grave. Zeke starts to unload the body -- but sees something he didn't notice before: There's some kind of opening at the bottom of the grave.</meta>
      <char name="ZEKE">
         <dialogue id="s69d1">Now what the bloody hell....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s69m2">Zeke hops down into the grave. CAMERA MOVES to reveal Riddick hidden among the spires. He's been waiting for a chance just like this.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s70">
      <sceneheader>EXT. GRAVE - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s70m1">Zeke drops to all fours. Looks into the tunnel. There seems to be some kind of burrow beyond. BURROW POV: Staring back at Zeke. Zeke takes a handlight off his belt, shines it into the burrow. It's the last thing he ever does.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s71">
      <sceneheader>INT./EXT. CRASH SHIP - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s71m1">As MORE GUNSHOTS jar Paris, Audrey, Shazza.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s72">
      <sceneheader>EXT. GRAVE - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s72m1">FURIOUS CLOSEUPS: Zeke fighting for his life. PISTOL BLASTING. Something slashing at him. Blood dancing on air.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s73">
      <sceneheader>EXT. CRASH SHIP - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s73m1">Shazza sprints across hard-pack, heading for...</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s74">
      <sceneheader>EXT. GRAVE SITE - SPIRED HILLS - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s74m1">The grave. She slaps aside the tarp to find... Riddick. Bone-shiv in hand, he just stands on the other side of the grave. Shazza looks down. And SCREAMS.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s75">
      <sceneheader>EXT. SPIRED HILLS - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s75m1">CAMERA PURSUES Riddick as he lopes through the spires, running from the scene of the crime. He turns a blind corner -- and SOMETHING NEARLY BLOWS HIS HEAD OFF at close range. He hits ground. A boot steps on his neck, keeping him there.</meta>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s75d1">Same crap, different planet, huh?</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s76">
      <sceneheader>EXT. SETTLEMENT - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s76m1">Sucking on their breathers, Fry and the Chrislams make it back to the ship. They find Johns beating Riddick like a chained dog.</meta>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s76d1">...I don't play that...I don't play that so just try again. C'mon, Riddick, tell me a better lie....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s76d2">Ease up, ease up. JOHNS! Just tell me what....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s76m3">She hauls him off -- only to have Shazza start punching Riddick.</meta>
      <char name="SHAZZA">
         <dialogue id="s76d3">What'd you do with 'im? You bloody sick animal you, what'dja do with me Zeke?</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s77">
      <sceneheader>EXT. GRAVE SITE - SPIRED HILLS - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s77m1">Fry and Johns stand over the grave. It's a gory mess -- but no sign of Zeke. Johns has Riddick's confiscated shiv.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s77d1">He used that?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s77d2">Sir Shiv-a-lot. He likes to cut.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s77d3">So why isn't it all bloody?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s77d4">I assume he licked it clean.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s78">
      <sceneheader>INT. MAIN CABIN - CRASH SHIP - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s78m1">Riddick is back in chains, face pulpy from the beating, listening to SOTTO VOCE VOICES outside. Fry enters, looks at him hard.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s78d1">So where is he?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s78m2">Riddick turns away, revealing a broken goggle-lens. The eye beneath is closed: For some reason, he won't look at her.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s78d2">Tell me about the sounds. You told them you heard something right before.... (no response) If you don't talk to me, Johns'll take another crack at it -- at your skull.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s78d3">'Mean the whispers?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s78d4">What whispers?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s78d5">The ones tellin' me to go for the sweet spot -- just to the left of the spine, fourth lumbar down. The abdominal aorta. What a gusher. Had a cup on his belt, so I used it to catch a little run-off. Metallic taste to it, human blood. Coppery. But if you cut it with peppermint schnapps, that goes away. Course, that's more for winter. Summertime, I take mine straight.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s78m6">Fry stares. Riddick gets a black satisfaction from his role as Boogeyman: If fear is the only kind of respect he can get, Riddick is going to grab some with both hands.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s78d6">Why don't we try the truth now?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s78m7">A head-shaking beat, then:</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s78d7">All you people are so scared of me -- an' most days, I'd take that as a compliment -- but it ain't me you gotta worry about now.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s78d8">Show me your eyes.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s78m9">Again he turns away. She strips the goggles off. He sits with lids shut tight, anticipating the pain.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s78d9">Show me, Riddick.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s78m10">Imagine a virgin undressing in front of someone for the first time. That's how Riddick opens his eyes, startling us: No irises, just huge black-pool pupils. And from deep within, a jewel-like eyeshine. His eyes are as beautiful and unsettling as those of a starved jaguar.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s78d10">You did this? To yourself?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s78d11">Slam doctor. Well, we called him &quot;doctor.&quot;</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s78d12">Heard about it. Just never seen it.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s78d13">Fairly fuckin' ironic, wouldn't you say? Slamlight's so dim that you go and get your eyeballs taken out and shined up -- then you wind up here. Three ass-kick suns. (replacing goggles) Maybe I did do a few people. But not this one. No ma'am, not this time.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s78d14">Then where is he? He's not in the hole. We looked.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s78d15">Look deeper.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s78m16">He CLICKS HIS TONGUE at her.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s79">
      <sceneheader>EXT. CRASH SHIP - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s79m1">Chain looped over one shoulder, Fry heads back to the grave site. Johns, Imam, Shazza, and Audrey keep pace as...</meta>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s79d1">I know what happened -- he went off on the guy, buried him on the hill somewhere, and now he's trying to --</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s79d2">Let's just be sure.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s79d3">I am sure. Look, murders aside, Riddick belongs in the Asshole Hall of Fame. He loves the jaw-jackin', loves making you afraid, 'cuz that's all he has. And you're playing right into --</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s79d4">We're gonna find the body, Johns. Christ, you're a cop. Why am I tellin' you this? We gotta go down and find it.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s79d5">Well, don't ask me to.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s79d6">Thought you didn't believe his story.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s79d7">I don't. But that ground looked none too stable, and I don't want anyone --</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="AUDREY">
         <dialogue id="s79d8">If you're afraid, I'll go.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s79m9">He shoots Audrey a scowl.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s79d9">Nobody else is going down but me, okay?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s79d10">(pulling her aside) Hey. Bein' ballsy with your life now doesn't change what came before -- it's just stupid.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s79d11">What, you think I'm doin' this to prove something?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s79d12">You said it, not me. Let's just not let one bad call lead to another.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s79d13">Thanks for the tip, Johns.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s79m14">&quot;Now get outta my way.&quot;</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s80">
      <sceneheader>EXT. GRAVE - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s80m1">Chain hooked to her web belt, Fry drops into the grave. She peers into the burrow...looks back up at the halo of faces above her...then slithers out of sight.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s81">
      <sceneheader>INT. BURROW - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s81m1">Letting her eyes adjust, Fry pats around lightly. Quickly she finds Zeke's handlight, tries it. Broken.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s82">
      <sceneheader>EXT. GRAVE-SITE - SPIRED HILLS - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s82m1">CLOSE on the chain slithering through hands, playing out as Fry moves deeper underground.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s83">
      <sceneheader>INT. UPHILL TUNNEL - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s83m1">Fry makes an uphill turn. Sees a spray of light ahead. Worms forward to reach...</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s84">
      <sceneheader>INT. THE LAIR - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s84m1">Another chamber, wide and just large enough to stand in. Shafts of daylight bore down into the room. More old bones litter the floor. Fry moves into one shaft and looks up at... An earthen funnel. The inside of a spire.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s84d1">They're hollow....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="CLICK-CLICK.">
         <dialogue id="s84d2">Fry slow-turns toward the sound.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="CLICK-CLICK-CLICK.">
         <dialogue id="s84d3">There's something here, something just beyond the cusp of light. Something unfolding.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s84m4">An icy hand grips her heart. Soundlessly, Fry backtracks her chain, but... Something shadows across the exit. It stops her cold. Her hand finds something new. She angles it to the light. It's one of Zeke's boots -- with a bit of Zeke still in it.</meta>
      <char name="CLICKITY-CLICKITY-CLICKITY....">
         <dialogue id="s84d4">The whole chamber is coming alive around her, shadows unfurling, skulking the perimeter, circling.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s84m5">Something impales the boot out of her hand, reclaiming it. It was faster than a lightning-strike. A paralyzed beat before... Fry makes her move, rolling back into the shaft of daylight and springing straight up into...</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s85">
      <sceneheader>INT. SPIRE - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s85m1">The spire. Bracing against the walls, Fry tries to &quot;walk&quot; her way up -- but her chain goes taut. Did it catch on something? Or did something catch it? Fry starts pounding the earthen walls.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s85d1">Here! I'm in HERE, HERE, HERE!</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s86">
      <sceneheader>EXT. GRAVE-SITE - SPIRED HILLS - DAY</sceneheader>
      <char name="IMAM">
         <dialogue id="s86d1">Did you hear....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s86m2">They drop down and suspend their heads over the bloody grave, listening. Nothing now.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s87">
      <sceneheader>INT. SPIRE - DAY</sceneheader>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s87d1">I'm over here in the --</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s87m2">Something tugs on her chain.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s87d2">Oh, God....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s87m3">CLOSE on her feet. Kicking hard at the walls, trying to gouge out footholds. A stronger tug. Fry loses altitude, slipping closer to... The MADLY CLICKING LAIR below. She tries to jettison her belt -- but can't brace herself up and undo the belt. Suddenly... Something explodes near her head. Daylight appears, followed by faces, human faces. They're breaking through the spire with the pick-ax. Hands reach inside...</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s88">
      <sceneheader>EXT. SPIRED HILLS - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s88m1">...and birth her into daylight. Overlapping:</meta>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s88d1">We got you...it's okay, it's okay...we got you now....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="IMAM">
         <dialogue id="s88d2">The child heard you before any of us could even....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="SHAZZA">
         <dialogue id="s88d3">Did you find him? You find Zeke?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s88d4">(half insane) ...wasn't Riddick...it was...it was... goddamn, that was stupid....but wasn't Riddick. Somethin' else down there that got Zeke and nearly got --</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s88m5">Her. She flies back into the spire. Something's still got the chain. The others grab at flailing limbs. It's a tug-of-war now, human hands on one end, unseen &quot;hands&quot; on the other -- and the humans are losing. Until... Imam unsheathes his blade... And slices through Fry's belt.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s89">
      <sceneheader>INT. SPIRE - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s89m1">As the chain falls down the spire. Without Fry.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s90">
      <sceneheader>INT./EXT. CRASH SHIP - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s90m1">FAST SHOTS: Survivors packing up O2, liquor, umbrellas, the Koran -- whatever qualifies as &quot;essential&quot; on this planet. Amid the activity, Audrey pauses to look at... The spired hills.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s91">
      <sceneheader>INT. BATTERY BAY - CRASH SHIP - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s91m1">Fry and Imam pull a power cell from the ship's battery bay, THUMPING it down on the deck.</meta>
      <char name="IMAM">
         <dialogue id="s91d1">One is all?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s91d2">For now.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s92">
      <sceneheader>INT. CARGO HOLD - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s92m1">At his personal locker, Johns digs out a box of shotgun shells. He bypasses the blue-metal shells for a red-metal one. There's something special about it -- though what, we can't be sure.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s93">
      <sceneheader>INT. MAIN CABIN - CRASH SHIP - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s93m1">A shadow falls over Riddick. He doesn't look up.</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s93d1">Found somethin' worse than me, huh?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s93d2">We're movin'. And I'm just wondering if I shouldn't lighten the load right now.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s93m3">Now their eyes meet. Johns RATCHETS HIS SHOTGUN and points it at Riddick's head.</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s93d3">Woof, woof.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s93m4">The SHOTGUN EXPLODES. CAMERA PANS off of Johns to show Riddick still alive. The shotgun discharged next to his head and blew off his wrist chains.</meta>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s93d4">Want you to remember this moment, Riddick. The way it coulda gone and didn't.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s93d5">(deaf) Say that again.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s93d6">Here's the deal. You work without the chains, without the bit -- without the shivs. You help us get off this rock....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s93d7">For what? The honor of goin' back to some asshole of a cell?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s93d8">Truth is, Riddick, I'm tired of this head-up shit. I wanna be free of you as much as you wanna be free of me.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s93m9">A beat. The future rearranges in Riddick's head.</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s93d9">You'd cut me loose, Boss?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s93d10">Only if we both get outta this alive. And there may be a way.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s93m11">He offers a hand to help Riddick up, to seal the deal.</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s93d11">(staring at hand) My recommendation: Do me. Don't take the chance that I'll get shiv-happy on your wannabe ass. Ghost me, Riddick. Would if I were you.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s93d12">If you were me, I'd kill us both. C'mon, you wanna sit at the grown-up table or not?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s93m13">A beat. Riddick reaches out for the hand -- and grabs the shotgun with his off-hand. A blur of movement. Suddenly Johns is staring at the eyes of his own shotgun.</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s93d13">Want you to remember this moment.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s93m14">He pumps shotgun, spitting blue shells over Johns. He drops the emptied gun and walks away.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s94">
      <sceneheader>EXT. PLANET - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s94m1">EXTREMELY WIDE: Blue sun setting, yellow and red sun rising. The survivors trek for the settlement. Fry and Imam lug the power cell between them, but the real load is shouldered by... Riddick. Promoted from murderous monster to beast of burden, he tows a drag-sled heavy with cargo.</meta>
      <char name="PARIS">
         <dialogue id="s94d1">(to Johns) So just like that. Wave your little wand and he's one of us now.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s94d2">Didn't say that. But least this way I don't have to worry about falling asleep and not wakin' up.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="IMAM">
         <dialogue id="s94d3">Well, I feel we owe Mr. Riddick amends.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="SHAZZA">
         <dialogue id="s94d4">Oh, right. Let's all line up and beg his forgiveness. Right you are.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="IMAM">
         <dialogue id="s94d5">At least give the man some oxygen....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s94d6">He's happy just bein' vertical. Leave him be.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="AUDREY">
         <dialogue id="s94d7">So I can talk to him now?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS/SHAZZA">
         <dialogue id="s94d8">(in unison) No.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s94m9">Paris drops a wine bottle. Trailing, Riddick collects it.</meta>
      <char name="PARIS">
         <dialogue id="s94d9">Paris P. Ogilvie. Antiquities dealer, entrepreneur.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s94d10">(shaking hands) Richard B. Riddick. Escaped convict, murderer.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s94m11">Instead of returning the bottle, Riddick opens it and drinks. Paris hurries to catch up to the others.</meta>
      <char name="PARIS">
         <dialogue id="s94d11">You know, if I owned Hell and this planet...I believe I'd rent this out and live in Hell.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s95">
      <sceneheader>EXT. THE GAUNTLET - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s95m1">FRY'S POV: Of spires high above us. The group falls silent as they transit the canyon, all eyes on the spires. Fry stops short, hearing...</meta>
      <char name="CLICKITY-CLICK.">
         <dialogue id="s95d1">Neck hairs rise -- but soon the sound vanishes. The group starts moving again, faster.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="CLICKITY-CLICKITY-CLICK.">
         <dialogue id="s95d2">Are they being stalked? Nervously, Fry traces the sound back to...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s95m3">Beads dangling from the belt of Pilgrim #1. Whenever he moves, the STRINGS CLACK together.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s96">
      <sceneheader>EXT. SKIFF - DAY</sceneheader>
      <char name="PARIS">
         <dialogue id="s96d1">I mean, usually I can appreciate antiques, but, uh....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s96m2">The survivors have reached the settlement. Fry is trying to get the power cell aboard the skiff as the others walk its exterior.</meta>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s96d2">Little ratty-ass.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s96d3">Nothing we can't repair -- so long as the electrical adapts.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="SHAZZA">
         <dialogue id="s96d4">Not a star-jumper.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s96d5">Doesn't need to be. Use this to get back up to the Sol-Track Shipping Lanes, stick out a thumb. You'll get picked up. (to Fry) Right?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s96m6">Fry looks from Riddick to Johns. &quot;How did he know that?&quot;</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s96d6">Little help here?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s96m7">They muscle the power cell aboard. Riddick starts to follow, but Johns blocks. He doesn't want Riddick inside.</meta>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s96d7">Check those containers for me. See what we can patch wings with.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s97">
      <sceneheader>EXT. SETTLEMENT - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s97m1">With religious fervor, the Chrislams are repairing the moisture- recovery unit -- the machine Allah led them to.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s98">
      <sceneheader>INT. SKIFF - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s98m1">START on the battery bay. Hands are adapting the power cell to the skiffs older electrical system. Soon... Lights wink on throughout the ship.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s98d1">Okay, that should buy us a sys-check. But we'll need more cells.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s98d2">How many?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s98d3">15 6-gigs here...90 gigs total...other ship carries 20-gig cells, so...five. Five total to launch.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s98d4">25 kilos each, huh?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="SHAZZA">
         <dialogue id="s98d5">Old sand-cat outside. See if I can't get it up and chuggin'.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s98d6">Do it. And if you need an extra hand, tap our problem child out.... (looking out) Where's Riddick?</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s99">
      <sceneheader>EXT. SETTLEMENT - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s99m1">He's walking the ghost town, finding dead gardens...upended chairs and furniture...broken skylights. Behind his back... Audrey and Pilgrim #3 (the youngest Chrislam) scurry through FRAME, stalking this curious monster in their midst.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s100">
      <sceneheader>EXT. MOISTURE-RECOVERY UNIT - SETTLEMENT - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s100m1">CLOSE on the other Chrislams, faces charged with anticipation while awaiting... The first drop of water. It appears at the bottom of a pipette. Tongues fight for it. Another drop forms in its place. Now another and another. It brings CHEERS.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s101">
      <sceneheader>INT. MAIN ROOM - SETTLEMENT - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s101m1">CLOSE on Paris' hands. Getting ready to celebrate, he unwraps crystal goblets...dusts off the refectory table...and rehangs an old Christmas garland. INTERCUT WITH...</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s102">
      <sceneheader>EXT. CORING ROOM - SETTLEMENT - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s102m1">Hands digging in dirt. Covertly, Audrey and Pilgrim #3 watch Riddick digging near the entrance of a tall windowless structure. He excavates a pair of broken eyeglasses... a shattered light... and a child's tin robot, timeless. Riddick thumbs a solar panel clean. The robot's language program warbles to life:</meta>
      <char name="ROBOT">
         <dialogue id="s102d1">&quot;...to all intruders. I am the guardian of this land. I will protect my masters at all cost. Death to all intruders...&quot;</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s102m2">Riddick stands and tries the doors. Locked. He peers through a small filthy window. Is there something moving inside? Nothing now. Riddick removes some windblown trash from a doorside sign. &quot;Coring Room.&quot;</meta>
      <char name="JOHNS (O.S.)">
         <dialogue id="s102d2">Missin' the party. C'mon.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s102m3">It's Johns, keeping him on a short leash. Leaving, Riddick kicks a trash bin. Hard.</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s102d3">Missin' the party. C'mon.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s102m4">He leaves. HOLD on the trash bin a beat.</meta>
      <char name="AUDREY (O.S.)">
         <dialogue id="s102d4">Talkin' to me?</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s103">
      <sceneheader>INT. CORING ROOM - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s103m1">PILGRIM'S POV: Of Audrey exiting the trash bin and running after Riddick and Johns. Pilgrim #3 is at the window of the coring room. He's found a way inside. By the window's feeble light, he starts exploring. Just visible at the center of this room is a vertical coring drill.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s104">
      <sceneheader>INT. MAIN ROOM - SETTLEMENT - DAY</sceneheader>
      <char name="IMAM">
         <dialogue id="s104d1">...and for this, our gift of drink, we give thanks in the name of our Prophet, Muhammad, peace be upon him, and to our Lord, Jesus Christ of Nazareth, and to his father, Allah the Compassionate and the Merciful.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="PARIS">
         <dialogue id="s104d2">(to himself) The strangest religion....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s104m3">Pilgrims finish pouring cloudy water into goblets. Riddick gets the last of it -- the part with sediment. SELECTED CLOSEUPS as they drink. Nothing ever tasted finer.</meta>
      <char name="PARIS">
         <dialogue id="s104d3">Perhaps we should toast our hosts. Who were these people, anyway? Miners?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="SHAZZA">
         <dialogue id="s104d4">Looks like geologists. Advance team, moves around from rock to rock.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s104d5">Musta crapped out here, huh?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="AUDREY">
         <dialogue id="s104d6">But why did they leave their ship?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s104m7">Silence. It's a question no one has chosen to deal with yet. Imam notices one water glass unspoken for.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s105">
      <sceneheader>EXT. CORING ROOM - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s105m1">CLOSE on the &quot;Coring Room&quot; sign. An attached solar panel begins moving, orienting toward sunlight. When it catches the full brunt of the suns' rays... STORM SHUTTERS unlatch on the roof.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s106">
      <sceneheader>INT. CORING ROOM - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s106m1">Pilgrim #3 hears SHOOTING LATCHES overhead. That sound brings another sound: A strange SKITTERING. The pilgrim looks up. Is there something in the rafters?</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s107">
      <sceneheader>INT. MAIN ROOM - SETTLEMENT - DAY</sceneheader>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s107d1">(answering Audrey) Well, just a skiff. Disposable, really.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="PARIS">
         <dialogue id="s107d2">Like an emergency life-raft, right?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="SHAZZA">
         <dialogue id="s107d3">Sure. Coulda had a real drop-ship take them off-planet. Long gone.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="PARIS">
         <dialogue id="s107d4">A toast to their ghosts, then....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s107m5">Goblets rise.</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s107d5">Didn't leave, these people. Whatever got Zeke got them. They're all dead.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s107m6">It's like he just pissed in the punchbowl.</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK (CONT'D)">
         <dialogue id="s107d6">What, you don't really think they left with their clothes on the lines? Photos on the walls?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="SHAZZA">
         <dialogue id="s107d7">Maybe they had weight limits, you don't know.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s107d8">I know you don't uncrate your emergency ship unless there's a fucking emergency.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s107d9">Rag it, Riddick. Nobody wants your theories on --</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s107d10">(to Riddick) So what happened? Where are they, then?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s107m11">Fry is the only one willing to look at reality -- or at least glance its way. At the window, Imam scans outside.</meta>
      <char name="IMAM">
         <dialogue id="s107d11">Has anyone seen the young one? Ali?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s107d12">(to Fry and Imam) Has anyone checked the coring room?</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s108">
      <sceneheader>INT. CORING ROOM - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s108m1">Now the storm shutters start yawning open, spreading daylight over Pilgrim #3 and... The ceiling rafters. They're encrusted with thick nests of... something. The SKITTERING grows louder, more agitated. Sensing trouble, Pilgrim #3 hurries for a sliver of daylight in a wall -- the breach he entered through. He never gets there: Sunlight hits the first nest. It EXPLODES WITH LIFE.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s109">
      <sceneheader>INT./EXT. MAIN ROOM - SETTLEMENT - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s109m1">As Imam hears the SCREAM.</meta>
      <char name="IMAM">
         <dialogue id="s109d1">Ali....</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s110">
      <sceneheader>INT. CORING ROOM - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s110m1">CHAOTIC SHOTS: More NESTS EXPLODE into individual creatures, winged hatchlings moving like bats in a fire, talons hacking and slashing. His exit blocked, Pilgrim #3 veers into... A dark supply room. He slams the door, MUMBLES A BLESSING and waits for the storm to pass. He's been cut -- but at least he's still alive.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s111">
      <sceneheader>EXT. SETTLEMENT - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s111m1">As the survivors run for the coring room.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s112">
      <sceneheader>INT. MAIN ROOM - SETTLEMENT - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s112m1">As Riddick stays behind to drink their water.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s113">
      <sceneheader>INT. CORING ROOM - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s113m1">HINGES ARE BLASTED AWAY. The door caves in. Imam shoulders past Johns to enter and find... The empty coring room.</meta>
      <char name="IMAM">
         <dialogue id="s113d1">Ali?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s113m2">A NOISE from the supply room. Is it Ali? Just too scared to come out? Imam opens the door... And hatchlings pour out. Moving with a gang-intelligence, they circle the room in a wave, soar high into the rafters -- then plunge into the coring shaft, SQUEALS VANISHING to infinity. Shocked silence, then... Pilgrim #3 tumbles to the ground. He's been shredded into bloody kite-tails. There was a nest inside the supply room. Imam falls on him in grief. Johns and Fry inch forward to peer down... The coring shaft. It's littered with human bones. The skeletons of the settlers. Scattered about and picked clean.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s114">
      <sceneheader>EXT. SETTLEMENT - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s114m1">Against a blue sunrise, the Chrislams hold a prayer service. Paris and Audrey attend. Riddick watches from afar.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s115">
      <sceneheader>INT. CORING ROOM - DAY</sceneheader>
      <char name="SHAZZA">
         <dialogue id="s115d1">Why was the door chained up? Why the bloody hell would they lock themselves in like that?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s115d2">Not sure, but tell you what: Chrislams better not be diggin' another grave out there.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK (O.S.)">
         <dialogue id="s115d3">Other buildings weren't secure...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s115m4">They turn. Riddick enters.</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK (CONT'D)">
         <dialogue id="s115d4">...so they ran here. Heaviest doors. Thought they'd be safe inside, but... (looks down shaft) Someone forget to lock the back door.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s115m5">Shazza joins him at the shaft. Gazing on the human remains:</meta>
      <char name="SHAZZA">
         <dialogue id="s115d5">So that's what come of me Zeke. An' you saw it. You was right there.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s115m6">Riddick nods.</meta>
      <char name="SHAZZA (CONT'D)">
         <dialogue id="s115d6">You were tryin' to kill him too.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s115d7">(shrugging, &quot;not necessarily&quot;) Just wanted his O-2. (a beat) Though I notice he tried to ghost my ass. When he shot up that stranger instead.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s115m8">Shazza can't deny it. She looks at him differently now, the man she once beat while in chains. She takes off her breather.</meta>
      <char name="SHAZZA">
         <dialogue id="s115d8">Take it.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s115d9">(suspicious) What, it's broken?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="SHAZZA">
         <dialogue id="s115d10">Startin' to acclimate, anyhow. Take it.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s115m11">Riddick accepts it awkwardly, sucks down some pure O2. Johns watches the exchange closely, not much liking the idea of Riddick being promoted to oxygen-breathing human.</meta>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s115d11">(to Fry) Let's board this up and get the hell gone. They seem to stick to the dark, so if we stick to daylight, should be all --</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s115d12">60 years ago.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s115d13">Wha'?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s115m14">Coring samples line the room, laid out on counters. Fry's been scrutinizing them.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s115d14">Core-samples are dated. Last one is 60 years ago. This month.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="SHAZZA">
         <dialogue id="s115d15">Yeah? What's special about that?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s115d16">Dunno. Maybe nothing, but....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s115m17">But now Fry remembers...</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s116">
      <sceneheader>INT. LIVING QUARTERS - SETTLEMENT - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s116m1">The orrery. The year-counter clicks over to &quot;45&quot; as... Fry opens the drive box and starts turning the main gear, accelerating the orbits. CLOSE on the counter. &quot;56...57...58...59...60.&quot; They all see it: A giant ringed world eclipses the suns and plunges their planet into darkness. Persistent darkness.</meta>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s116d1">Are you fuckin' kidding me?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s116d2">Not afraid of the dark, are you?</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s117">
      <sceneheader>EXT. SETTLEMENT - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s117m1">Crossing the yard in wide strides:</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s117d1">...need those cells from the crash ship. Shit, still gotta check out the hull, patch the wings --</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s117d2">Let's wait on the power cells.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s117d3">Wait for what? Until it's so dark we can't even find our way back to --</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s117d4">We're not sure when it happens, so let's not --</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s117d5">Get the fucking cells over here, Johns. What's the discussion?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s117m6">A beat.</meta>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s117d6">Ever tell you how Riddick escaped?</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s118">
      <sceneheader>INT. SKIFF - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s118m1">Alone inside the skiff, Johns and Fry continue with more privacy.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s118d1">(jarred) He can pilot?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s118d2">Hijacked a prison transport, made a helluva good run 'fore I tracked him down.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s118d3">(with faint hope) Okay, maybe that's a good thing. Maybe I can use him to help with --</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s118d4">He also figured out how to kill the pilot, Fry.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s118m5">A mental shiver.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s118d5">You said we were going to trust him now. You said there was a deal.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s118d6">That's what I said.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s118m7">He challenges her to read his mind.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s118d7">Oh, this is a dangerous game you're playing, Johns.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s118d8">May've noticed chains don't work on this guy. Only way we're truly safe is if he believes he's goin' free. But if he stops believin' --</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s118d9">You mean, if he learns that you're gonna royally fuck him over.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS (CONT'D)">
         <dialogue id="s118d10">-- we need a fail-safe. Bring the cells over at the last possible minute -- when the wings are ready, when we know we're ready to launch.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s118m11">Fry looks at him with new eyes.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s118d11">You know, he hasn't harmed any of us. Far as I can tell, he hasn't even lied to us. Just stick to the deal, Johns. Let him go if that's what it --</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s118d12">He's a murderer. The law says he's gotta do his bid.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s118m13">Shaking her head, she looks off.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s118d13">Dancin' on razor blades here...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s118d14">I won't give him a chance to grab another ship -- or to slash another pilot's throat.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s119">
      <sceneheader>EXT. SKIFF - SETTLEMENT - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s119m1">Johns descends the gangway -- and finds Riddick erecting a field table in the shade of the skiff. He seems out of earshot. Now, anyway. As they trade looks, another flu-like shiver runs through Johns.</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s119d1">Bad sign. Shakin' like that in this heat.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s119m2">Johns moves on. The Chrislams appear, shouldering a roll of Vectran (wing-fabric material). They drop it on the table. Ready to cut bindings, Imam pats his hip for the knife that was just there.</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s119d2">(looking after Johns) I'll cut.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s119m3">He has the knife.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s120">
      <sceneheader>EXT. SETTLEMENT - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s120m1">As Shazza and Audrey repair the sand-cat.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s121">
      <sceneheader>EXT. SKIFF - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s121m1">CLOSE on the knife slicing through the Vectran. Riddick hands the trim to Pilgrim #1. CAMERA FOLLOWS as he scampers onto the skiff...balance-beams over wing-struts...and delivers the piece to Imam, who stitches the fabric like an old Berber rug-weaver. Pilgrim #1 pauses to check on... The setting blue sun. Nothing unusual. Yet.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s122">
      <sceneheader>INT. SKIFF - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s122m1">The hatch closes, seals. CLOSE on a monitor. A &quot;HULL INTEGRITY TEST&quot; is underway. Fry scans rising pressure gauges.</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK (O.S.)">
         <dialogue id="s122d1">Looks like we're a few shy....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s122m2">Fry whirls. Riddick is aboard, staring at the depleted battery bay. And he has Imam's blade.</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK (CONT'D)">
         <dialogue id="s122d2">Power cells.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s122d3">They're coming.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s122d4">Strange, not doin' a run-up on the main drive yet. (half-beat) Strange unless he told you the particulars of my escape.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s122d5">I got the quick-and-ugly version.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s122d6">An' now you're worried about a repeat of history?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s122d7">Entered our minds.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s122d8">I asked what you thought.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s122d9">You scare me, Riddick. That's what you wanna hear, isn't it? There, I admit it, Can I get back to work now?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s122m10">She finds the courage to turn her back on him. Riddick moves closer -- and takes a beat to scan the controls. The cabin pressure builds.</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s122d10">Think Johns is an do-right man? You think I can trust him to cut me loose?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s122m11">A beat. Does Riddick already know? Is he testing her?</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s122d11">Why, what'd you hear?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s122d12">Well, guess if it was trickeration he'd just do me, huh? Then again...I am worth twice as much alive. (reading her face) Didn't know? Johns ain't a cop. Oh, he's got that shiny badge an' all, but nah -- he's just a merc and I'm just a payday. That's why he won't kill me. The creed is greed.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s122m13">It knocks her off stride, but...</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s122d13">Save it, Riddick. We aren't gonna turn on each other -- no matter how hard you try.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s122m14">Riddick moves right up behind her.</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s122d14">I don't truly know what's gonna happen when the lights go out, Carolyn -- but I do know that once the dyin' starts, this little psycho family of ours is gonna rip itself apart. So you better find out the truth. Come nightfall, you better know exactly who's standing behind you.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s122m15">A monitor chirps the news: &quot;HULL INTEGRITY --100%.&quot; EXHALING GASSES, the hatch opens automatically.</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s122d15">Oh, ask him 'bout those shakes. And ask why your crew-pal had to scream like that 'fore he died.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s123">
      <sceneheader>INT. PRIVATE ROOM - SETTLEMENT - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s123m1">CLOSEUPS: Hands select a red-metal shotgun shell from a box... pull the shell open...remove a glass ampule hidden inside...drop the ampule into a injection syringe. The syringe touches an eager arm vein.</meta>
      <char name="FRY (O.S.)">
         <dialogue id="s123d1">Who are you? Really?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s123m2">Shirt off, Johns looks up. She's in the doorway.</meta>
      <char name="FRY (CONT'D)">
         <dialogue id="s123d2">You're not a real cop, are you? Just some mercenary who goes around talkin' about the law like --</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s123d3">I never said I was.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s123d4">Never said you were a hype, either.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s123m5">She moves closer. Rummages through his stuff brazenly. Finds a shitload of red shells with the hidden ampules.</meta>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s123d5">You have a little caffeine in the morning, I have a little morphine. So what?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s123d6">And here you got two mornings every day. Wow, were you born lucky?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s123d7">Not a problem unless you're gonna make --</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s123d8">(lashing) You made it a problem when you let Owens die like that. When you had enough drugs to knock out a fucking mule-team.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s123d9">Owens was already dead. His brain just hadn't caught on to that fact.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s123d10">Anything else we should know about you, Johns? Christ, here I am lettin' you play games with our lives when --</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s123m11">He catches her hands -- and moves them around his body, forcing her into an embrace. We understand why when we see a CLOSEUP of her hands: They find a jagged purple scar beside his spine.</meta>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s123d11">My first run-in with Riddick. Went for the sweet-spot and missed. They had to leave a piece of the shiv in there. I can feel it, sometimes, pressing against the cord. (giving her hands back) So maybe the care and feeding of my nerve-endings is my business.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s123d12">You coulda helped. And you didn't.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s123m13">O.S., we hear the Chrislams JABBERING ARABIC and calling for &quot;Captain, Captain....&quot;</meta>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s123d13">Yeah, well, look to thine own ass first. Right, &quot;captain&quot;?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s123m14">It cuts deep.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s124">
      <sceneheader>EXT. SETTLEMENT - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s124m1">Fry and Johns move outside. The others have gathered, all eyes gang-locked on... An arch in the sky. Luminous, ominous, it grows from the horizon.</meta>
      <char name="PARIS">
         <dialogue id="s124d1">What do my eyes see?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s124d2">It's starting....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s124m3">They watch hypnotically as the arch rises, inching toward the two suns. Shazza shakes out of the trance first.</meta>
      <char name="SHAZZA">
         <dialogue id="s124d3">(to Fry) If we need anything from the crash ship -- I suggest we kick on. That sand-cat's solar.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s125">
      <sceneheader>EXT. SETTLEMENT - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s125m1">MULTIPLE SHOTS: Shazza cranking the sand-cat...hands snatching up lights, water, ropes...Chrislams piling aboard the sand-cat.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s125d1">LET'S GET THOSE CELLS!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s125m2">Sand-cat moving...Riddick jumping onto the rear bed....Paris and Audrey running, catching up.</meta>
      <char name="SHAZZA">
         <dialogue id="s125d2">We stay together! C'mon!</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s126">
      <sceneheader>INT. PRIVATE ROOM - SETTLEMENT - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s126m1">Johns doubles back, grabs his shotgun shells, swings out the door...</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s127">
      <sceneheader>EXT. INCINERATOR - SETTLEMENT - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s127m1">...and catches up to the sand-cat. Riddick reels him aboard.</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s127d1">Don't wanna miss this.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="AUDREY">
         <dialogue id="s127d2">Lookit. Lookit!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s127m3">They turn back to see the rim of a giant planet. It's cresting over the horizon. The luminous arch is the planet's rings.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s128">
      <sceneheader>EXT. RIBCAGE - THE GAUNTLET - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s128m1">The sand-cat storms through the canyon. As it passes through the massive ribcage... The ROLL CAGE SMASHES OUT some low-bridge bones.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s129">
      <sceneheader>EXT. CRASH SHIP - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s129m1">The sand-cat reaches the crash ship. Bodies leap off. Paris steals a look at... The rising planet. It threatens to blot out suns, sky, universe.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s130">
      <sceneheader>INT. BATTERY BAY - CRASH SHIP - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s130m1">Johns yanks the first power cell and starts dragging it over the deck. Riddick yanks a second cell and, carrying it on his shoulder, passes Johns with a suck-my-ass grin. Johns shoulders his cell and stumbles after.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s131">
      <sceneheader>EXT. CRASH SHIP - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s131m1">Shazza wheels the sand-cat around, getting clearance between it and the ship. The Chrislams lash a scrap-metal sled to the sand-cat. Riddick drops the first cell onto the sled, Johns the second. They're racing the eclipse and each other.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s132">
      <sceneheader>EXT. SKY - DAY TO DUSK</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s132m1">As the rings of the planet eclipse the yellow sun.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s133">
      <sceneheader>EXT. CRASH SHIP - DUSK</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s133m1">It's like God just closed a blind: Daylight dims. The change in light brings a GROWING HIGH-PITCHED SOUND.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s133d1">Don't stop, don't stop....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s133m2">But Paris can't help himself. He squints to see...</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s134">
      <sceneheader>EXT. SPIRED HILLS - DUSK</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s134m1">The spires. THE SOUND seems to come from there.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s135">
      <sceneheader>EXT. SKY - DUSK</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s135m1">As the rings eclipse the red sun.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s136">
      <sceneheader>EXT. CRASH SHIP - DEEP DUSK</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s136m1">A second darkness sweeps over the survivors. Now they all stop, beholding...</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s137">
      <sceneheader>EXT. SPIRED HILLS - DEEP DUSK</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s137m1">Something pouring from the spire-tops. Backlit by coronal light, it first seems to be smoke or ash -- but soon we realize these are living things, HATCHLINGS SQUEALING IN DELIGHT over their first nightfall.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s138">
      <sceneheader>EXT. CRASH SHIP - DEEP DUSK</sceneheader>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s138d1">Jesus, how many can there....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s138m2">They keep coming, filling the sky with thick waves. Mercifully, the hatchlings seem to be moving away. But now one wave cleaves from another -- and does a quick about-face.</meta>
      <char name="PARIS">
         <dialogue id="s138d2">Just a suggestion, but perhaps we should flee.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s138d3">Cargo hold, everyone in the cargo hold. lesgo, lesgo, lesgo.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s138m4">They run. Reach the cargo hold. Turn back to see... Riddick and Shazza still coming. Hearing the SQUEALING WAVE descending on them... Riddick and Shazza hit to the dirt. Hatchlings torrent just inches overhead. CLOSE on Shazza. Horrified. Hard to breathe. Like being underwater. CLOSE on Riddick. He watches in awe, no more frightened that a kid lying on his back looking up at the stars. Experimenting, he eases a bone-shiv into the hatchlings. Instantly it's whittled down to nothing. It's like a river of razor blades. The hatchling keep coming. Shazza whips a panicky look at the cargo hold. Can she make it? Should she even try?</meta>
      <char name="AUDREY">
         <dialogue id="s138d4">Tell her to stay there. Stay down. SHAZZA, JUST STAY DOWN!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s138m5">Shazza starts worming toward the cargo hold. Suddenly the hatchings vanish. A beat. Is it safe? Shazza gets to her feet...</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s138d5">No, no, NO, NO, NO....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s138m6">...and the wave is back, enveloping Shazza.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s139">
      <sceneheader>INT./EXT. CARGO HOLD - DEEP DUSK</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s139m1">Standing in the mouth of the cargo container, the others get a last glimpse of Shazza as she flies by the doors, caught up in the funnel-cloud of hatchlings. Then she's simply gone.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s140">
      <sceneheader>EXT. CRASH SHIP - DEEP DUSK</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s140m1">Still on the ground, Riddick checks left and right like someone about to cross a busy street. Now he gets up, smacks his hands clean, strolls for the hold. Behind him... A rising GANG-CLICKING. CLOSE on Fry. She knows the sound better than anyone.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s141">
      <sceneheader>EXT. SPIRED HILLS - DEEP DUSK</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s141m1">The spires are crumbling, torn down from within.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s142">
      <sceneheader>EXT. CRASH SHIP - DEEP DUSK</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s142m1">Reaching the cargo hold, Riddick turns around for one last look. PUSH IN as he sheds goggles -- and looks at the world with his jaguar eyes. RIDDICK'S POV: In degraded image, we see the predators -- adult hatchlings -- emerge from the spires. They're large, mammalian, hammer-headed. They CLICK with echo-location, sounding out the world they haven't inhabited in 60 years.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s142d1">What is it? What's happening?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s142m2">RIDDICK'S POV: The predators launch from the hills, gliding, SOUNDING, searching.</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s142d2">Like I said. Ain't me you gotta worry about.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s143">
      <sceneheader>EXT. SKY - DEEP DUSK TO NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s143m1">The rim of the planet overtakes both suns. The world goes dark.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s144">
      <sceneheader>INT. CARGO HOLD - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s144m1">Vault-like DOORS BOOM CLOSED. The survivors are locked inside the only secure part of the ship. Somehow they've been reduced to neanderthals huddling in their cave, listening to the howls of the sabertooths.</meta>
      <char name="AUDREY">
         <dialogue id="s144d1">What if...what if she's still out there... still alive....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s144d2">Well, I don't want to jump to conclusions here...but 'member that boneyard? These just might be the fuckers that killed every other living thing on this planet, okay? Chances of Shazza knockin' on that door anytime soon are just about zero squared.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s144d3">(agreeing) I saw the cut-marks on the bones. Wasn't a natural die-off.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="IMAM">
         <dialogue id="s144d4">Quiet, please. Everyone.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s144m5">Imam is listening at the cargo door. The others pile up alongside, ears tuned like radar. CLICKING SWEEPS PAST outside.</meta>
      <char name="AUDREY">
         <dialogue id="s144d5">(whispering) Why do they do that? Make that sound?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="IMAM">
         <dialogue id="s144d6">Perhaps the way they see. With sound, reflecting back.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s144d7">(realizing) Echo-location. That's what it is....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s144m8">Now MORE CLICKING -- behind them. Lights whip around to find... Nothing. Only the door of an open container about halfway down the tunnel-like hold. A volley of looks. &quot;How the fuck could one get in here?&quot;</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s144d8">Breach in the hull. I dunno.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s144m9">More CLICKING. Johns realizes they expect him to check it out.</meta>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s144d9">I'd rather piss glass.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s144d10">Well, you got the big gauge.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s144d11">Wanna rag your fat mouth?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="AUDREY">
         <dialogue id="s144d12">Maybe it's just their beads again. Imam, are you still --</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="IMAM">
         <dialogue id="s144d13">No, no, no, I do not believe --</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s144d14">C'mon, man, you're drivin' everybody bugfuck with those things. Why don't you just lose the goddamn....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s144m15">More CLICKING -- along with the sound of TOPPLING CARGO.</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s144d15">Big beads.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s144m16">Butching up, Johns sucks on his breather and shimmies toward... The open container. Leading with his shotgun, he FIRES blindly around the door. Something SQUEALS -- then silence. Johns eases his head and a light around the door to spot... Hatchlings on the ground, blasted into dog food.</meta>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s144d16">(to others) Okay. We're okay. Just some small ones that musta --</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s144m17">Something WHOOSHES for his head, swinging like a scythe. It catches his shotgun, DISCHARGING IT, giving us... A flash-image of an adult predator. Up close. In one thin second, Johns is back with the others.</meta>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s144d17">Very big beads.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="PARIS">
         <dialogue id="s144d18">Not staying in here another....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s144m19">He goes for the main-door lever, ready to flee into the night. Fry lunges for him.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s144d19">Christ, you don't know what's out there!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="PARIS">
         <dialogue id="s144d20">I know what's in here!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="IMAM">
         <dialogue id="s144d21">Everybody come, this way and we should be safe. Hurry, please....</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s145">
      <sceneheader>INT. FIRST CONTAINER - CARGO HOLD - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s145m1">Imam shepherds them into a container. The door slams closed. At first, only the sound of MOUTHS SUCKING BREATHERS. Then a</meta>
      <char name="SCRATCHING.">
         <dialogue id="s145d1">Johns fumbles with a cutting torch. Gets it burning. Adjusts the gasses to illuminate...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s145m2">The door. Scythe-like blades are probing joints. Suddenly HEAVY BLOWS drive everyone back.</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s145d2">(to Johns) Can you do sumpin' else with that? 'Sides holding it in my fucking face?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s145m3">Taking the hint, Johns starts cutting the common wall between containers. It's a race between the sparks of his cutter and the blades of the predators.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s146">
      <sceneheader>INT. SECOND CONTAINER - CARGO HOLD - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s146m1">An burn-outline appears in the common wall. Johns kicks out the escape hatch. Audrey speed-crawls through first as...</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s147">
      <sceneheader>INT. FIRST CONTAINER - CARGO HOLD - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s147m1">Predators shred into the container right behind them, CLICKING, sweeping, hunting.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s148">
      <sceneheader>INT. THIRD/FOURTH CONTAINERS - CARGO HOLD - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s148m1">SERIES OF SHOTS: Again and again, they burn a new escape hatch just as the predators break into the container being vacated, always entering darkness.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s149">
      <sceneheader>INT. FIFTH CONTAINER - CARGO HOLD - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s149m1">Inside their fifth container now, Johns torches away. Fry and Paris use cargo to block the entrance hole -- then block the cargo with their bodies. Riddick adds his weight -- until he notices pepper-shot in the cargo. Suspecting the worst, he leaves the others behind...</meta>
      <char name="PARIS">
         <dialogue id="s149d1">Hello, hello?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s149m2">...and moves to the front of the container where darkness prevails. Something SQUISHES underfoot. He slips off goggles. RIDDICK'S POV: Of dead hatchlings on the floor. This is the open container, the one where Johns found predators. Sensing energy, Riddick lifts his face. RIDDICK'S POV: Of an adolescent predator. It squats atop cargo, eating a hatchling. A heavy bone-blade crowns its skull. Sensing Riddick, it sweeps the area with INQUISITIVE CLICKS. PREDATOR POV: Of Riddick. (NOTE: The PREDATOR POV is a crude image that gives impression without detail. We're &quot;seeing&quot; what the predator hears with echo-location. Think of a sonagram that strobes and wraps its subject in 3-D space.) Oblivious, the others kick out the new escape hatch. Audrey, Fry, and Johns worm through. Imam and Pilgrim #2 hang back. &quot;Where's Riddick?&quot; He's in a stare-down with a predator. Searching, Pilgrim #2 rounds a corner -- and finds his head caught in a vice-like grip.</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s149d2">Don't. Move.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s149m3">RIDDICK'S POV: As a second predator appears above them. This one reaches down with its scythe blade... And gently probes the two men. It wants know what they're made of. CLOSE on the pilgrim's shoes. Over-running with piss. More blades descend, moving over them like surgical instruments. One test-slices Riddick's shirt.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s150">
      <sceneheader>INT. SIXTH CONTAINER - CARGO HOLD - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s150m1">In the next container, Fry waits anxiously. Hissing through the escape hatch:</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s150d1">Imam? Where are they?</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s151">
      <sceneheader>INT. FIFTH CONTAINER - CARGO HOLD - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s151m1">CLOSE on a predator's scythe blade. It test-slices the pilgrim's skin. Blood wells up. All CLICKING CEASES.</meta>
      <char name="IMAM (O.S.)">
         <dialogue id="s151d1">Hasan?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY (O.S.)">
         <dialogue id="s151d2">Riddick?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s151m3">TIGHT on the pilgrim -- more scared now that the clicking has stopped. Losing his nerve, he bolts.</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s151d3">No....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s151m4">The predators are on him, just blurs in the dark. DEATH-SCREAM. RIDDICK'S POV: A third predator appears above him. Making his move, Riddick darts around cargo and heads for the escape hatch as... Fry's light catches him square in the face. Blinded, Riddick HOWLS and stumbles forward. Fry's light leaps deeper to hit... The predator right behind him. With a similar reaction, the beast HOWLS and flails back. HOLD on Fry for a time-stopped moment. What stopped it? Was it really her? Suddenly a SHOTGUN EXPLODES beside her head. Jacked up, Johns is BLASTING shadows.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s151d4">Stop it, stop it, STOP IT!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s151d5">'Sokay, 'sokay. I killed it.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s151m6">They give him a look. &quot;Sure you did.&quot; Suddenly a CARCASS SLAMS to the floor, sending everyone jumping back in a perfect splash- pattern. &quot;Christ, he did kill one.&quot; Fry reclaims her dropped light and beams it on the carcass. Wherever the light strikes it, the flesh chars and steams.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s151d6">There....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="PARIS">
         <dialogue id="s151d7">Like the light is scalding it.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s151d8">It hurts them. Light actually hurts them....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s151m9">VULTURE SOUNDS from the two O.S. adolescents, fighting over the scraps of the pilgrim.</meta>
      <char name="IMAM">
         <dialogue id="s151d9">Is that...Hasan?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s151m10">Riddick nods.</meta>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s151d10">We'll burn a candle for him later. C'mon.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s152">
      <sceneheader>INT. SIXTH CONTAINER - CARGO HOLD - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s152m1">Cargo has been shoved against the door and walls. The survivors gather around Fry's handlight. Audrey -- tough little Audrey -- has been reduced to a shivering lump of mush.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s152d1">...one cutting torch...one handlight here, two more in the cabin...I think two more....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="PARIS">
         <dialogue id="s152d2">Spirits. Anything over 45 proof burns well.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s152d3">How many bottles?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="PARIS">
         <dialogue id="s152d4">Not sure. Ten?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s152d5">Those umbrellas, the ones that mist. Would they burn? (reading his face) If you got a receipt?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="PARIS">
         <dialogue id="s152d6">Possibly.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s152d7">Awright. So maybe we'll have enough light.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s152d8">Enough for what?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s152m9">Now she challenges him to be the mind-reader.</meta>
      <char name="JOHNS (CONT'D)">
         <dialogue id="s152d9">Oh, lady. If you're in your right mind, I pray you go insane.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s152d10">(to others) We can stick to the plan. If we get four cells back to the skiff, we're off this rock.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="PARIS">
         <dialogue id="s152d11">I hate to kill a beautiful theory with an ugly fact, but that sand-cat won't run at night.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s152d12">We'll have to carry the cells...drag them...whatever it takes.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s152m13">Troubled faces. Is it just our imagination? Or is the light on the floor growing dimmer?</meta>
      <char name="AUDREY">
         <dialogue id="s152d13">You mean...tonight? With all those things still out there?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="PARIS">
         <dialogue id="s152d14">Oh, sure. Why not? Sounds like a hoot.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s152d15">Back it up. How long can this last? Few minutes? Couple hours?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s152m16">No one knows for sure.</meta>
      <char name="IMAM">
         <dialogue id="s152d16">I had the impression...from the model... that the two planets were moving as one. That there would be...a lasting darkness.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s152d17">Those suns gotta come back sometime. And if these animals really are phobic about light, we just sit tight till then.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s152d18">I'm sure that's what someone else said. Locked inside that coring room.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s152m19">A persuasive thought. Eyes swing back to Audrey.</meta>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s152d19">Look, we gotta think about everyone now -- the kid especially. How scared is she gonna be out there?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s152d20">Oh, don't use her like that, for a smoke screen.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s152d21">Smoke screen for what?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s152d22">For your own fear.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s152d23">(eyes narrowing) Hey. Why don't you rag your hole for two seconds and let someone else come up with a plan that doesn't involve MASS SUICIDE?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s152m24">Two seconds pass.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s152d24">How much you weigh, Johns?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s152d25">What the hell's it matter?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s152d26">How much?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s152d27">79 kilos.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s152d28">Because you're 79 kilos of gutless white meat, and that's why you can't come up with a better plan.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s152m29">He makes a move for her. Riddick blocks. Johns' shotgun bumps the underside of Riddick's chin.</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s152d29">Think about that reward, Johns.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s152d30">I'm willing to take a cut in pay.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s152d31">How 'bout a cut in your gut?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s152m32">Johns looks down. CAMERA DROPS to reveal the shiv Riddick holds, poised for evisceration.</meta>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s152d32">Oh, Trash Baby, you're gonna regret this.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="IMAM">
         <dialogue id="s152d33">Please...this solves nothing...please....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s152m34">Johns backs off first. The light grows dimmer.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s152d34">(to Audrey) They're afraid of our light. That means we don't have to be so afraid of them.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="IMAM">
         <dialogue id="s152d35">And you're certain you can find the way back? Even in the dark?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s152d36">No, I'm not. But he can.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s152m37">She's pointing, of course, to Riddick.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s153">
      <sceneheader>EXT. PLANET - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s153m1">The eclipsing planet dominates half the sky. In whatever coronal light remains, we see clouds forming.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s154">
      <sceneheader>EXT. CRASH SHIP - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s154m1">Cargo doors crack open. Mixed for maximum flame, the cutter is pushed outside and swept around. Fry appears behind it. Moving like hostages, the survivors cross open ground, trying not to heed the PRIMAL SOUNDS beyond their light. Soon they reach... The main cabin. Blackness inside.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s154d1">Riddick.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s154m2">He lifts his goggles. RIDDICK'S POV: Checking the cabin. Finding a lot of wreckage but no life.</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s154d2">Looks clear.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s154m3">Johns shoulders ahead and crawls in first. Just as he stands up inside... A PREDATOR BUZZSAWS over his head, fleeing the cabin, taking off into the night.</meta>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s154d3">Fuck me. You said &quot;clear.&quot;</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s154d4">Said &quot;looks clear.&quot;</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s154d5">Well, what's it look like now?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s154d6">(rechecking) Looks clear.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s154d7">Just get the goddamn lights on....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s154m8">They scramble aboard. Riddick TONGUE-CLICKS behind Johns. He isn't amused.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s155">
      <sceneheader>INT. MAIN CABIN - CRASH SHIP - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s155m1">PREP MONTAGE: We see the survivors powering up cabin lights... yanking three more cells from the battery bay...threading nylon cord through Paris' misting umbrellas, filling the reservoirs with high-octane liquor...swapping out O2 canisters.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s156">
      <sceneheader>INT. MAIN CABIN - CRASH SHIP - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s156m1">Reloading his shotgun, Johns finds himself shaking again. He unpockets a shell -- a red morphine shell -- and gives it a lover's look. Behind him...</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s156d1">Ready, Johns.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s156m2">He palms the shell.</meta>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s156d2">He'll lead you over the first cliff. You know that, don't you?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s156d3">We're just burnin' light here.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s156d4">You give him the cells and the ship -- and he will leave you. He will leave you all out there to die.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s156d5">I don't get it, Johns. What is so goddamn valuable in your life that you're worried about losing? Huh? Is there anything at all? Besides your next hype? (no response) Got no right to be so scared. Neither one of us.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s157">
      <sceneheader>INT. BATTERY BAY - CRASH SHIP - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s157m1">As hands yank the last power cell.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s158">
      <sceneheader>INT. MAIN CABIN - CRASH SHIP - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s158m1">Cabin lights die. Still brooding, Johns finishes loading his shotgun in the dark.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s159">
      <sceneheader>EXT. CRASH SHIP - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s159m1">CLOSE on a burning wick. Alcohol mist shoots across the flame to create... A FIREBALL. Two umbrella torches, fabric already burned away, BELCH FIREBALLS into the night. By this light and more, we see... Imam chained into the first harness of the drag-sled. Beside him, Johns fumbles with a second harness. Hands help him into the chains. The hands belong to... Riddick. Both men recognize the irony of the prisoner helping his captor into chains.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s159d1">(to all) Keep the light going. That's all we have to do to live through this. Just keep your light burning.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s159m2">Riddick loops a handlight over his neck, places it to shine light down his back. A beacon.</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s159d2">(to Fry) Be runnin' about 10 paces ahead. I want light on my back -- but not in my eyes. And check your cuts. These things know our blood now.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s159m3">CLOSE on Audrey. Overhearing, she goes stone-faced.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s159d3">Riddick...was thinkin' we should make some kind of deal. Just in case, you know, this actually --</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s159d4">(shaking head) Had it with deals.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s159d5">But I just wanted to say --</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s159d6">Nobody's gonna turn a murderer loose. I fuckin' knew better.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s159m7">It worries Fry. &quot;If he doesn't expect to go free....&quot;</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK (CONT'D)">
         <dialogue id="s159d7">Been a long time since anyone's trusted me. That's somethin' right there.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s159d8">We can, can't we? Trust you?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s159d9">Actually... (completely genuine) That's what I been askin' myself.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s159m10">He walks away. HOLD on Fry -- wondering if she hasn't made a terrible, terrible mistake.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s160">
      <sceneheader>EXT. NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s160m1">The drag-sled begins moving. SERIES OF TRACKING SHOTS: Riddick running point, goggles off, eyes flashing. Johns and Imam pulling the drag-sled like malamutes, handlights sweeping. Pilgrims #1 at the first side- guard position, Fry and Audrey at the second, each position carrying an umbrella torch, FIREBALLS BLAZING. Paris stumbling along at rear-point, sweeping the cutter back and forth, every shadow a threat. They are a train of light. CLOSE on the sled. Holding four power cells and eight bottles of booze. CLOSE on Fry. Looking down. Noting sand-cat tracks underfoot.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s161">
      <sceneheader>EXT. NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s161m1">Below us run the survivors. CRANE UP AND AWAY so that their lights become insignificant...so that we include, in FOREGROUND, the silhouettes of gliding predators. They're following from above, awaiting their chance.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s162">
      <sceneheader>EXT. NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s162m1">FRY'S POV: Of the ground. The sand-cat tracks have vanished.</meta>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s162d1">So you noticed too?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s162d2">Riddick. Riddick.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s162m3">The procession grinds to a halt. Everyone sucks hard on breathers as they muster inside the light.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s162d3">Where are the sand-cat tracks? Why aren't we still following them?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s162d4">Saw something I didn't like.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s162d5">Such as.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s162d6">Hard to tell, sometimes...even for me... but looked like a bunch of those big boys chewin' each other's gonads off. Thought we'd swing wide. Okay by you?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s162m7">Paris looks over his shoulder. &quot;We went around what?&quot; Nearby CLICKING breaks up the confrontation.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s162d7">Let's move. (to Audrey) Just a detour. He'll get us there.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="PARIS">
         <dialogue id="s162d8">Can we switch?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s162d9">What, switch what?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="PARIS">
         <dialogue id="s162d10">I think I twisted my ankle running backwards like that. And I'm not sure I can.... (off their stares) Okay, that's a lie. I just don't want to be alone back there anymore. If you could just give me a few minutes up front here --</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s162d11">She's the pilot, she should stay close to the cells.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="PARIS">
         <dialogue id="s162d12">Oh, so I'm disposable?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s162d13">I'll switch, I'll switch! Christ, just get this train moving!</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s163">
      <sceneheader>EXT. NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s163m1">They trundle on, Fry the new tail-gunner. At side guard, Paris relaxes a bit -- even though the CLICKING never seems far from earshot. A weak FIREBALL SPEWS from his torch. He checks the reservoir. Almost empty.</meta>
      <char name="PARIS">
         <dialogue id="s163d1">Light, please, need light here....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s163m2">Still moving, Johns and Imam train lights on Paris while he refuels. For a brief moment, Audrey strays from the light. PREDATOR'S POV: Dive-bombing the girl. A HIGH-VELOCITY CLICKING: It's like an incoming missile. Imam lunges at the last nanosecond... And flattens Audrey to the ground. Scythe blades swing... CHINKING the harness-chains on Imam's back. Johns whirls, BLASTS. Light-beams leap around. But the predator is long gone.</meta>
      <char name="IMAM">
         <dialogue id="s163d2">(trembling) Please...have we been cut? Can someone tell me if....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s163m3">He finds his dropped light, thumbs the switch again and again. Broken. In the confusion, Paris has been left in the dark. Something slashes him from behind. It's like the night has claws.</meta>
      <char name="PARIS">
         <dialogue id="s163d3">Oh, sweet Jesus....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s163m4">The bottle drops. The blood flows. The CLICKING STOPS.</meta>
      <char name="PARIS">
         <dialogue id="s163d4">Oh, sweet Jesus, WILL YOU GET ME SOME LIGHT OVER HERE!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s163m5">Faces whip around. But before their lights can rescue him... Paris is gone, snatched away by a swooping blur. Light-beams jump fitfully, vainly. RIDDICK'S POV: Of predators feasting on Paris. Carrying a youngling on its back, a female predator arrives late and can't find a place at the trough. With shocking apathy, it whips the youngling off its back and begins devouring it. Other predators start in-fighting, killing themselves for food. POV PANS to a pair of predators, closer, SOUNDING out new prey. POV PANS AGAIN to include the object of their desire. Audrey. CLOSE on Riddick. Trying to figure it out. CLOSE on Audrey. Listening to the HORRIFIC FEEDING SOUNDS. Oblivious to all the attention she's getting.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s163d5">What do you see? Riddick?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s163d6">Hunger. I see 60 years of hunger.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s164">
      <sceneheader>EXT. SKY - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s164m1">As clouds mass.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s165">
      <sceneheader>EXT. NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s165m1">Into a rising wind, the survivors range on. Audrey now carries Paris' torch, refueled and COUGHING FIREBALLS at regular intervals. Fry seems to be handling rear-point fairly well, until... The cutter sputters and dies. She ditches it and takes the torch from Audrey.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s165d1">Bottle-count.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="AUDREY">
         <dialogue id="s165d2">Four fulls, one half. That mean we're halfway there? I hope?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s165m3">Good question. They've just been blindly following... The light on Riddick's back.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s165d3">Can we pick up the pace?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s165m4">Working like a mule, Johns growls to himself. &quot;If you think you can do better....&quot; Abruptly he slaps an arm across Imam's chest, spotting... A sled-track. In front of them. Fry hears a SHOTGUN RATCHET. She spins to see... Johns out of his chains. Moving forward. Jamming the shotgun into the back of Riddick's neck.</meta>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s165d4">We aren't completely stupid.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s165d5">Stay in the light! Everybody! Stay in the fucking --</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="IMAM">
         <dialogue id="s165d6">We crossed our own tracks.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s165d7">He's running us 'round in circles. Look for yourself. Look!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s165d8">Riddick? What the hell are you --</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s165d9">Listen.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s165m10">Imagine a hundred Geiger-counters next to a truckload of plutonium. That's the SOUND that rides the wind now.</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s165d10">Canyon ahead. I circled once to buy some time to think.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s165d11">Think about what?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s165d12">About how to kill us and still get these cells to the skiff. Goddamnit, we're just doin' the heavy lifting for this prick!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s165d13">(answering Fry) About the girl.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s165d14">What about her?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s165d15">What it's gonna be like when we hit that canyon. With her bleeding.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s165d16">What're you jaw-jackin' about? Girl's not cut.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s165d17">(agreeing) No. She's not.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s165m18">It hits Fry like a two-by-four. She looks at Audrey.</meta>
      <char name="AUDREY">
         <dialogue id="s165d18">(confessing) I didn't want you to leave me there... back at the ship...that's why I didn't say anything....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s165d19">No, we'd never....Oh, God, honey, you shoulda told me sooner.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s165d20">(finally getting it) Aw, this can't be happening to me....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s165d21">They been nose-open for her ever since we left. They go off blood.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="IMAM">
         <dialogue id="s165d22">Well...we must keep her close, then. Here, she'll be safe if we put her between --</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s165d23">(scanning) There is no &quot;safe.&quot;</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s165m24">An epic beat. The wind gusts...the FLAMES CHATTER...their ears fill with CANYON SOUNDS.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s165d24">It's not gonna work. We gotta go back.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s165m25">Johns brays.</meta>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s165d25">Hey, you're the one who got me out here, turned me into a goddamn sled dog. An' now you 'spect me to go back like a whipped dog?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s165d26">I was wrong. I admit it. My bad, okay? Now let's just go back to the ship.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s165d27">I dunno. Nice breeze, wide open spaces -- you know, I'm startin' to enjoy myself out here.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s165d28">Are you fucking high again? Just listen to --</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s165d29">No, no, you're right, Fry. What's to be afraid of? My life is a steamin' pile of meaningless toadshit anyhow. So I say mush on! Canyon's only couple hundred meters, after that we're in Skiff City! So why don't you just butch up, stuff a cork in that kid, and get --</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="IMAM">
         <dialogue id="s165d30">She's the captain, we should listen to --</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s165d31">Listen to her? Her? When she was willing to sacrifice us all?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s165m32">A beat. Eyes turn to Fry. She wants to protest -- but can't.</meta>
      <char name="AUDREY">
         <dialogue id="s165d32">What's he talkin' about?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s165d33">During the crash, she --</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s165d34">(a warning growl) This does not help us, Johns.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s165d35">-- she tried to blow the whole fucking passenger cabin, tried to kill us --</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s165d36">Just shut up, okay?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s165d37">-- tried to kill us in our sleep. Paris had it right -- we are disposable. We're just walking ghosts to her.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s165d38">Would you RAG YOUR STUPID HOLE!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s165m39">She rushes him, ready to rip his eyes out. He shunts her aside.</meta>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s165d39">We're not alive because of her -- we're alive in spite of her.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s165m40">He swung below the belt -- and connected. Fry's chin quakes, her knees fail. The undertow of events finally pulls her down.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s165d40">We cannot go through there....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s165d41">(lording) How much you weigh right now, Fry? Huh?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="IMAM">
         <dialogue id="s165d42">(pushing him back) Fine, fine, you've made your point. We can all be so scared as you.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s165m43">Johns snatches a light away from Imam.</meta>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s165d43">(to all) Verdict's in. The light moves forward.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s166">
      <sceneheader>EXT. BONEYARD - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s166m1">They trudge on, slower now, building reserves for the canyon-run. At rear-point, Fry follows like a broken rudder. Pilgrim #1 now draws the sled with Imam. And up ahead...</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s167">
      <sceneheader>EXT. BONEYARD - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s167m1">Johns falls in step with Riddick.</meta>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s167d1">Ain't all of us gonna make it.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s167d2">Just realized that, huh?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s167m3">CLICKING nearby. Johns BLASTS the night, driving the sound away -- and reminding everyone of who carries the Big Gauge.</meta>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s167d3">Six of us left. If we could get through that canyon and lose just one, that'd be quite a fucking feat, huh? A good thing, right?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s167d4">Not if I'm the one.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s167d5">What if you're one of five?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s167m6">Riddick stares. &quot;I'm listening.&quot;</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s168">
      <sceneheader>EXT. BONEYARD - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <char name="AUDREY">
         <dialogue id="s168d1">What're they doin' up there?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="IMAM">
         <dialogue id="s168d2">Talking about the canyon, I suppose. How to get us through.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s168m3">Overhearing, Fry looks. It's odd to see Johns and Riddick walking side by side, like equals. Like partners.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s169">
      <sceneheader>EXT. BONEYARD - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s169d1">Look, it's hellified stuff -- but no different than those battlefield doctors when they have to decide who lives and who dies. It's called &quot;triage,&quot; okay?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s169d2">Kept calling it &quot;murder&quot; when I did it.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s169d3">Either way, figure it's something you can grab onto.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s169d4">(doping it out) Sacrifice play. Hack up one body, leave it at start of the canyon. Like a bucket of chum.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s169d5">Trawl with it. There's a cable on the sled. We can drag the body behind us.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s169d6">Nice embellishment.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s169d7">Don't wanna feed these land-sharks -- just keep 'em off our scent.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s169d8">(looking back) So which one caught your eye?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s169d9">Don' look, don' look, don' look....</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s170">
      <sceneheader>EXT. BONEYARD - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s170m1">Fry spots Riddick's look -- and Johns' non-look.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s170d1">Imam. Slow down.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="IMAM">
         <dialogue id="s170d2">What?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s170d3">Don't stop, just slow down.  Little more space 'tween us and them.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="IMAM">
         <dialogue id="s170d4">I would rather we all stay--</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s170d5">Do what I say. Please.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s171">
      <sceneheader>EXT. BONEYARD - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s171d1">What's her name, anyway?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s171d2">What do you care?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s171m3">Riddick shrugs. &quot;I don't.&quot;</meta>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s171d3">Then let's not name the Thanksgiving turkey, okay? I assume you still got a shiv.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s171d4">What, you 'spect me to do it?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s171d5">What's one more to you? Like this is the one that sends you to Hell?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s171d6">Oh, you're a piece of art, Johns. They oughtta hang you in a museum somewhere. Or forget the museum -- maybe they should just hang you.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s172">
      <sceneheader>EXT. BONEYARD - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s172m1">As Fry and the others keep slowing.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s173">
      <sceneheader>EXT. BONEYARD - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s173d1">Awright. You do the girl, I'll keep the others off your back.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s173m2">Riddick stops. Reconsiders.</meta>
      <char name="JOHNS (CONT'D)">
         <dialogue id="s173d2">Aw, don't tell me you're growin' scruples.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s173d3">(shakes head) Just wonderin' if we don't need a bigger piece of chum.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JOHNS">
         <dialogue id="s173d4">Like who, Mr. Chrislam?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s173m5">EXTREMELY TIGHT on both men: In their eyes, we see the new partnership splintering apart: &quot;Like Mr. Johns.&quot; Riddick makes a play for the shotgun. It BLASTS skyward.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s174">
      <sceneheader>EXT. BONEYARD - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s174m1">As the fight erupts:</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s174d1">Bring the light!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="AUDREY">
         <dialogue id="s174d2">What're they doing? What're we --</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s174d3">Leave the sled, let's go, go, go!</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s175">
      <sceneheader>EXT. BONEYARD - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s175m1">FIGHT SCENE: Johns' light hits the ground, creating an arena of illumination. FAST CLICKING nearby. Still struggling, Riddick and Johns somehow manage to gang-aim the shotgun and BLAST THE</meta>
      <char name="CLICKING AWAY.">
         <dialogue id="s175d1">The shotgun goes free. Johns lunges for it, but Riddick kicks it into the night. And then pulls his shiv.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s175d2">Gotta stay in the light, Johns. That's the only rule.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s175m3">Johns circles inside the light. Fucking with him, Riddick starts poking and jabbing, backing him up against the wail of dark. Johns stumbles over something. A bone. A club. Riddick finds his own bone-club, and now they go at it like two cavemen. Riddick beats on Johns' club-hand, breaking fingers, forcing him to drop the bone. Just trying to get away now, Johns makes a desperate lunge for the light, but... Riddick shivs open his back.</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s175d3">Remember that moment?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s175m4">Gushing blood, Johns starts crawling pathetically with the light. Riddick dogs him.</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s175d4">Shoulda never took the chains off, Johns. You were one brave fuck, before. Now look at you. Oh, yeah, you were Billy Bad-ass with your gauge...with your chains....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s175m5">Johns finds the shotgun. &quot;And I'm still Billy Bad-ass.&quot; He sweeps it around with the light, ready to kill... Blackness. Where'd Riddick go? CLICKING behind Johns. He whirls to see... Something big coming for him. Johns BLASTS IT back into the night, dropping the light as he does. Eyes in the back of his head, he whirls again and takes aim on... Another bull-rushing predator. Johns triggers a bad round. Crazed, he ratchets and levels the shotgun for another try. He's too late. BIG CLOSEUP as the ejected shell rolls to a stop. It's red. Johns loaded a morphine shell in the dark. RIDDICK'S POV: With Johns skewered by the armpits, the predator lifts him off the ground and &quot;stares&quot; with a deceptively gentle</meta>
      <char name="CLICKING-COOING SOUND.">
         <dialogue id="s175d5">PREDATOR'S POV: Of Johns' final expression.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s175m6">RIDDICK'S POV: The predator rears back its head -- then slams forward, hitting Johns with the full force of its skull-blade, splitting him in two.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s176">
      <sceneheader>EXT. NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s176m1">Fry, Imam, Audrey, Pilgrim #1. They're running, stumbling, trying to backtrack the sled marks. Checking for pursuit, Fry looks over her shoulder... And crashes into Riddick. He was just standing in the dark, waiting for them.</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s176d1">Back to the ship, huh?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s176d2">Get out of our way.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s176d3">So everybody huddles together till the lights burn out? Until you can't see what's eating you? That the big plan?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="IMAM">
         <dialogue id="s176d4">Where's Mr. Johns?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s176d5">Which half?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="IMAM">
         <dialogue id="s176d6">You mean....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s176m7">Conflicted, they all look back. Audrey starts to puddle up.</meta>
      <char name="AUDREY">
         <dialogue id="s176d7">Gonna lose everybody out here....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s176d8">He died fast. And if we got any choice, that's the way we should all go out. (to Audrey, softly) Don't you cry for Johns. Don't you dare.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s177">
      <sceneheader>EXT. CANYON RIM - THE GAUNTLET - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s177m1">BLACK SCREEN. We hear the canyon in full cry now -- CLICKING... BATTLING BONE-BLADES...MATING CRIES...the RENDING OF FLESH and SNAPPING OF TENDON. Far below, twin flames appear as the survivors reach the gauntlet. Predators perch in FOREGROUND, just hulking silhouettes &quot;watching&quot; from a canyon rim.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s178">
      <sceneheader>EXT. START OF GAUNTLET - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s178m1">They are but five: Fry, Riddick, Audrey, Imam, and Pilgrim #1. CLOSE on each face as they listen to the CANYON. There must be countless predators ahead.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s178d1">How many you see?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s178d2">One or two.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s178d3">Audrey?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="AUDREY">
         <dialogue id="s178d4">Three full bottles. But almost time to refill.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s178d5">Doesn't seem like enough to turn back on, does it?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s178d6">Only see one way. Turn the sled over and drag it like that, girl down low. Light up everything we got -- and run through like dogs on fire.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s178m7">A beat.</meta>
      <char name="IMAM">
         <dialogue id="s178d7">(understanding) The sled as a shield....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s178d8">And what about the cells?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s178d9">I'll take those.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s178m10">She looks at him hard.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s178d10">We're just here to carry your light, aren't we? Just the torch-bearers.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s178d11">Let's drop back an' boot up.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s179">
      <sceneheader>EXT. BONEYARD - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s179m1">START on the power cells. They're been lashed together into one queue. Working amid the giant bones, Riddick crafts a new harness from the old straps. Close behind him, Imam is MUTTERING IN ARABIC.</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s179d1">What're you doin'?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="IMAM">
         <dialogue id="s179d2">Blessing you like the others. (off his look) It's painless.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s179d3">And pointless.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="IMAM">
         <dialogue id="s179d4">(a beat) I see. Well, even if you don't believe in God, it doesn't mean He won't be --</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s179d5">You don't see.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s179m6">Riddick shrugs into the harness, snugs it down.</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK (CONT'D)">
         <dialogue id="s179d6">'Cuz you don't spend half your life in lock-down with a horse-bit in your mouth and not believe. And you surely don't start out in a liquor store trash bin with an umbilical cord wrapped around your neck and not believe. Oh, absolutely I believe in God. And I absolutely hate the fucker.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="IMAM">
         <dialogue id="s179d7">He will be with us. Nonetheless.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s179d8">Give my blessing to the girl. She needs a spare.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s180">
      <sceneheader>EXT. START OF GAUNTLET - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s180m1">The torches. Maxed out. Burning non-stop. Fry and Imam. Sled chains on. Lapping up O2. Each holding a torch. Pilgrim #1. Clutching a handlight. Audrey. Rolling under her sled-shield, becoming the turtle in a metal carapace. Riddick. Goggles on. He has no desire to see what horrors will surround them. There's just one path, anyway: Straight through.</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s180d1">As fast as you can.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s180d2">You sure you can keep --</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s180d3">As fast as you can.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s181">
      <sceneheader>EXT. THE GAUNTLET - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s181m1">SLEW OF SHOTS: Fry and Imam on the move, dragging the shield fast. Audrey speed-crawling beneath. Pilgrim #1 tripping along behind the shield. And Riddick behind them all, face already tortured, pulling 200 pounds of stubborn-mule cargo -- yet somehow keeping pace. The torch flames, stretched by the wind, flank them in fire.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s182">
      <sceneheader>EXT. CANYON RIM - THE GAUNTLET - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s182m1">As predators launch from the rim.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s183">
      <sceneheader>EXT. THE GAUNTLET - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s183m1">First come the hatchlings, streaming right into their faces -- then veering away at the last second, repulsed by light. Next come FERAL SOUNDS overhead.</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s183d1">Don't look.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s183m2">Thin blue liquid spatters them.</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s183d2">Do not look up.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s183m3">More spattering. Fry looks up -- and stumbles when she beholds... A ceiling of predators. At the cusp of light, they dive and weave and dart, slashing each other in a rabid desire to SOUND OUT the humans below. It's like looking into a bucket of angry eels.</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s183d3">Keep going, keep going, keep going, keep going!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s183m4">His voice whips them like the Devil's coxswain. Chastened, Fry keeps her eyes down and speed up. More blue blood showers down -- followed by entrails dropping out of the sky. Could this be Hell itself?</meta>
      <char name="IMAM">
         <dialogue id="s183d4">(a muttered mantra) &quot;So dark the clouds around my way I cannot see, But through the darkness I believe God leadeth me. I gladly place my hand in His when all is dim, And, closing my weary eyes, lean hard on him....&quot;</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s183m5">Now WHOLE CORPSES ARE CRASHING DOWN around them, victims of in-fighting. Fry and Imam start slaloming through the ghastly mess. Pilgrim #1 passes too close to a corpse: A blade slices his leg, drawing blood. He keeps his mouth shut.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s184">
      <sceneheader>EXT. CHOKE-POINT - THE GAUNTLET - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s184m1">The passage narrows into a choke-point. Fry sees it first.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s184d1">Riddick? RIDDICK?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s184m2">Ahead, a clot of dead predators blocks the canyon.</meta>
      <char name="AUDREY">
         <dialogue id="s184d2">What? What is it?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s184d3">It's a fucking staircase! Go over it! GO OVER IT!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s184m4">Steeling themselves, they start climbing. But Audrey, on all fours, has to discover the corpses with her hands. Then, taking exception at being walked on... One &quot;corpse&quot; snaps at her. Audrey recoils sideways... And tumbles down the mound of corpses. She's exposed. PREDATORS' POV: Rapid-fire images of Audrey. Flashes from 10 different predators.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s184d4">Audrey!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s184m5">Audrey shakes out of it and scrambles for the shield just as... A predator kamikazes onto the shield, its bone-blades piercing the metal... And nearly skewering Audrey beneath. Caught in torchlight, steaming, the PREDATOR HOWLS as it tries to rip free of the shield. Beneath, Audrey hangs on and takes a thrashing. The predator tears clear, spins, pounces blindly at... Riddick, standing at light's edge. Stunningly, he catches the beast under its scythe blades, blunting the attack. The predator CLICKS MADLY at him. PREDATOR'S POV: Of Riddick's face. The predator rears back its head, ready to bisect Riddick with its skull-blade. Switchblade fast, Riddick drops a hand... ...yanks his shiv... ...and sweeps it over the belly of the beast. HOWLING, the predator falls, disemboweled. REACTION SHOTS of Fry and Imam. Stunned.</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s184d5">Didn't know who he was fuckin' with.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s184m6">They regroup. Imam's head swivels back and forth: They're one person short.</meta>
      <char name="IMAM">
         <dialogue id="s184d6">Suleiman!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s184d7">Get the girl back under. Keep going.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="IMAM">
         <dialogue id="s184d8">SULEIMAN!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s184d9">KEEP GOING OR I WILL!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s184m10">Suddenly Pilgrim #1 reappears, thrust back into the light by unseen forces. He's still alive -- but shouldn't be. He makes a feeble attempt to grab onto Imam, to anyone, but he's gone again before they can even react, jerked out of the light. Out of existence.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s185">
      <sceneheader>EXT. THE GAUNTLET - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s185m1">They flail on. And now, finally...finally.... The canyon widens, opening up like some door to Heaven. The WORST SOUNDS fall behind. We can see it in their sweat-sheened faces: The faintest hope that maybe they've survived the Seventh Circle of Hell. But then... The TORCHES SPIT AND SPUTTER. Audrey hears PATTERING on the metal shield. Blood falls anew. One torch dies -- yet somehow comes back to life. Imam upturns a hand, checking the liquid for color. But this blood has no hue.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s185d1">Oh, no. No, no, no....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="IMAM">
         <dialogue id="s185d2">Rain.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s186">
      <sceneheader>EXT. THE GAUNTLET - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s186m1">RAIN MONTAGE: Water rilling, running, flowing over rocks and ground.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s187">
      <sceneheader>EXT. THE GAUNTLET - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s187m1">Caught in a downpour, the survivors slog to a stop. One torch goes out -- and won't relight.</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s187d1">So where the hell's God now, huh? (no answer from Imam) I'll tell you where! He's up there PISSING ON ME!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s187d2">Riddick? How close?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s187m3">Riddick sheds goggles to look ahead. We don't know what he sees -- nor what he's thinking.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s187d3">Tell me the settlement is right there! RIDDICK, PLEASE!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s187d4">We can't make it.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s187m5">HOLD on Fry's anguished face, rendered in dying torchlight. Somewhere behind, the AWFUL SOUNDS RETURN.</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s187d5">Here...hide here....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s187m6">He's found a crevice in the canyon wall.</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s187d6">Inside...inside....</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s188">
      <sceneheader>EXT. CREVICE - THE GAUNTLET - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s188m1">They crawl into the fissure. The second torch dies behind them.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s189">
      <sceneheader>EXT. THE GAUNTLET - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s189m1">There's just one light left now -- the one Riddick wears on his back. By its glow, we watch him lift the shield, muscle it over to the crevice...</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s190">
      <sceneheader>EXT. CREVICE - THE GAUNTLET - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s190m1">...and slide it over the opening. A black beat.</meta>
      <char name="AUDREY">
         <dialogue id="s190d1">(a beat) Why's he still out there?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s190m2">Fry's not sure. Is he protecting them? Or entombing them?</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s191">
      <sceneheader>EXT. MUDDY RISE - THE GAUNTLET - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s191m1">Working like Sisyphus, Riddick hauls the cells up a muddy rise. He stops at the top, peers through the rain. RIDDICK'S POV: Of the settlement. Riddick disappears over the rise. The four cells follow, slithering through the mud like a serpent's tail.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s192">
      <sceneheader>EXT. CREVICE - THE GAUNTLET - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <char name="AUDREY">
         <dialogue id="s192d1">He's not coming back, is he?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s192m2">Fry checks Imam's face. Did Riddick say anything to you?&quot; Imam wags his head. A bleak beat -- before Fry realizes she can see his face.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s192d2">There's light in here.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s192m3">It's a soft glow from above. Imam climbs higher to discover small blue-white lights clinging to rocks. He plucks a few.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s192d3">What are they?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s192m4">CLOSE on the lights in Imam's palm. They writhe with life.</meta>
      <char name="IMAM">
         <dialogue id="s192d4">Larva....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="AUDREY">
         <dialogue id="s192d5">Glow worms....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s192d6">(mind racing) How many bottles we got? Empty ones?</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s193">
      <sceneheader>INT. SKIFF - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s193m1">Riddick boards the dark craft. Connects the power cells to the battery bay. Watches the ship come to life.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s194">
      <sceneheader>EXT. CREVICE - THE GAUNTLET - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s194m1">CLOSE on a liquor bottle. It's half full of glow-worms.</meta>
      <char name="AUDREY">
         <dialogue id="s194d1">More, more, we need more....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s194m2">They climb higher. Little by little, the bottle brightens their world.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s195">
      <sceneheader>EXT. SKIFF - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s195m1">Drenched in light, Riddick stands in the hatchway of the skiff, looking out into dark rain. Is he struggling with a decision? Or just savoring the safe harbor? Then very deliberately... Riddick smashes his handlight on the hull. He steps inside and closes the hatch behind him.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s196">
      <sceneheader>EXT. MUDDY RISE - THE GAUNTLET - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s196m1">Something claws its way up the rise. Standing, we see that it's Fry, a bottle of glow-worms strung around her neck. Ahead she spies... The settlement. Silhouetted by engine-light.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s197">
      <sceneheader>EXT. SKIFF - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s197m1">As the skiffs ENGINES WARM UP.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s198">
      <sceneheader>INT. SKIFF - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s198m1">As Riddick dabbles with flight controls.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s199">
      <sceneheader>EXT. SETTLEMENT - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s199m1">As Fry, running, splashes past buildings.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s200">
      <sceneheader>EXT. CREVICE - THE GAUNTLET - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s200m1">Audrey and Imam huddle around a bottle of glow-worms: This is all they could harvest. Presently SCRABBLING SOUNDS on the shield. Imam eases one eye to a small hole in the shield. He can't see much until... A blade rushes through the hole. Imam recoils hard, snatches up the glow-worm light to see... More predator blades exploring the edges of the shield. The light drives them away. For now.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s201">
      <sceneheader>INT. SKIFF - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s201m1">Riddick dims interior lights, activates exterior lights. He's actually startled by the sight of... Fry. Standing in the skiffs headbeams. Daring him to run her over. Eye-lock. Riddick opens the hatch.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s202">
      <sceneheader>EXT. SKIFF - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s202m1">They meet at opposite ends of the gangway -- Fry in the rain, Riddick in the light.</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s202d1">Strong survival instinct. Admire that in a woman.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s202d2">You're not leaving. Not until we go back for the others.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s202m3">He laughs at that.</meta>
      <char name="FRY (CONT'D)">
         <dialogue id="s202d3">I promised them we'd go back with more light. And that's exactly what we're gonna do..</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s202d4">Think you've mistaken me for somebody who gives a fuck.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s202d5">What, you're afraid?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s202d6">Confusin' me with Johns now -- fear was his monkey. I only deal in life and death. All that stuff in between? Some shade of grey my eyes don't see.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s202d7">I trusted you, Riddick. Goddamn, I trusted that some part of you wanted to rejoin the human race.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s202d8">Truthfully? I wouldn't know how.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s202m9">Fry realizes it's impossible to shame a shameless man. With desperation edging her voice:</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s202d9">Then wait for me. I'll go back myself. Just give me more light for them.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s202m10">He tosses her a light. The broken one.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s202d10">Just come with me!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s202d11">Got a better idea. Come with me.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s202m12">Fry's mouth moves but nothing comes out.</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK (CONT'D)">
         <dialogue id="s202d12">They're already dead. Get on board.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s202d13">You're fuckin' with me. I know you are.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s202d14">'Course I am -- but doesn't mean I won't leave you here. If you believe anything about me, better be that.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s202d15">No, you see, I promised them...I have to...I have to go and....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s202m16">She's bleeding resolve. Riddick can see it -- can smell it -- and he keeps slashing away.</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s202d16">Step aboard, Carolyn.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s202d17">(tortured) I can't....I can't....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s202d18">(approaching, extending a hand) Here. Make it easy on you.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s202d19">Don't do this to me....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s202d20">Just give me your hand.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s202d21">But they...they could still be....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s202d22">No one's gonna blame you. C'mon. Take my hand and save yourself, Carolyn.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s202m23">A beat. She takes his hand -- and jerks him down the gangway. They sprawl through mud. She gets a knee on his neck.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s202d23">I will not give up on them! I Will not leave anyone on this rock with those fucking things, even if it means --</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s202m24">In a blur, Riddick rolls and slaps a shiv on her neck. Is history repeating itself? Riddick's face, though, is strangely calm. Curious. Even gentle.</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s202d24">You'd die for them?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s202d25">I would try for them.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s202d26">You barely know them.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s202d27">But I'm human. I know you view that as a weakness, but I'm sorry -- I do feel fear, theirs too. Goddamnit, Riddick -- yes. I would die for them.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s203">
      <sceneheader>EXT. CREVICE - THE GAUNTLET - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s203m1">MORE SCRABBLING at the shield. Imam cocks his blade back, ready to do battle with... Fry. She heaves the shield aside. Behind her, Riddick.</meta>
      <char name="AUDREY">
         <dialogue id="s203d1">(big-eyed) You came for us....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s203d2">Yeah, yeah -- we're all fuckin' amazed. Anyone not ready for this?</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s204">
      <sceneheader>EXT. THE GAUNTLET - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s204m1">Protected by the meager light of two glow-worm bottles, the four remaining survivors head out.</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s204d1">Tighter, tighter....</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s205">
      <sceneheader>EXT. MUDDY RISE - THE GAUNTLET - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s205d1">Stop.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s205m2">They pile up awkwardly. Fry listens hard. Only RAINFALL.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s205d2">I don't hear --</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s205m3">He covers her mouth. RIDDICK'S POV: Water has pooled at the base of the muddy rise. A predator drinks there.</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s205d3">(on his breath) Doesn't see us...wait for it to leave....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s205m4">RIDDICK'S POV: Another predator lands to drink. Then another. Their backs are to us, but the pool is turning into a major gathering place. Soon they all can hear CLICKING above the RAIN. Their nightmare is far from over.</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s205d4">Get behind me.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s205m5">RIDDICK'S POV: Of a half-dozen predators shifting places at the pool. A slim gap appears.</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s205d5">When I go, we go. Full-throttle.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s205m6">CLOSE on their hands, gripping each other.</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s205d6">Ready...ready....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s205m7">RIDDICK'S POV: The gap between predators widens into a passage. A gauntlet within a gauntlet. Riddick runs. Linked like paper dolls, the others follow blindly. RIDDICK'S POV: Of a predator turning to &quot;stare&quot; over its shoulder. PREDATOR'S POV: Of Riddick bearing down fast. The survivors hit the water like lawn mowers on legs, crashing through, scattering water and predators alike, managing to reach... The muddy rise. Audrey loses her grip on the others... And starts back-sliding. She CRIES OUT, turning the head of... Riddick. He catches Audrey as her legs hit the pool. He muscles her back up the rise and heaves her over the top, sending her slip-sliding down the other side.</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s205d7">You know the way!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s205m8">Not waiting for him, Fry and Imam disappear over the rise. RIDDICK'S POV: Of the predators. Regrouping. Crawling up the rise at us.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s206">
      <sceneheader>EXT. NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s206m1">Fry, Imam, and Audrey run hard, glow-worm lights bouncing wildly. RIDDICK'S POV: Chasing them. PREDATOR'S POV: Chasing Riddick.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s207">
      <sceneheader>EXT. SETTLEMENT - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s207m1">Fry, Imam, and Audrey reach the settlement. They spill around a corner and see... The light of the skiff.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s208">
      <sceneheader>EXT. SETTLEMENT - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s208m1">RIDDICK'S POV: Ahead of us, we see Fry, Imam, and Audrey vanishing around the corner. BREATHING LIKE A RACEHORSE, we follow in their steps, storming around the same corner. Suddenly a predator is right there, right in our face. PREDATOR'S POV: Of Riddick skidding to a stop. He snaps a look up. RIDDICK'S POV: Of another predator perched gargoyle-like on the building. It SPEED-CLICKS at us. PREDATOR'S POV: Of Riddick slowly pulling two shivs. Bracing himself. Ready to blade it out.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s209">
      <sceneheader>EXT. SKIFF - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s209m1">Imam and Audrey stagger aboard. Safe in the light of the headbeams, Fry turns back, panting, waiting. Waiting.</meta>
      <char name="IMAM">
         <dialogue id="s209d1">Captain....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s209m2">He wants her to board the skiff. Fry gives it another beat, eyes sweeping the dark rain. And just when we think it's over for Riddick -- TERRIBLE SCREAMS are heard from both man and predator: There's a helluva fight going on out there. Close out there. Fry snatches the glow-worms off Imam's neck... And plunges into the darkness, homing in on the SOUNDS until... A blade flashes in her face. She ducks and spots... Riddick. Bloody, muddy, he's down on his knees, still trying to fight off the shadow-beasts that swirl and slash all around him. Around them both.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s209d2">It's me, it's me, it's me!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s209m3">She gets the light around his neck. Now we see his face clearly -- and see a very human expression there: Fear. Fry grabs his armpits and tries to pull him up.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s209d3">C'mon, Riddick -- said I'd die for them, not you.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s209m4">He gets his feet under him. Gripping each other, they start moving, turning like dancers in a macabre waltz, hoping the predators can't fix on Riddick's blood.</meta>
      <char name="FRY">
         <dialogue id="s209d4">Just 10 steps...keep turning, keep turning...that's right...others're already 'board, waitin' for us right now...five steps...c'mon, almost there, Riddick... almost there...we're almost --</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s209m5">Something jolts them. ALL CLICKING STOPS. EXTREME CLOSEUPS: Searching each other's eyes. Someone just got slashed from behind, slashed bad. But who?</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s209d5">Not for me....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s209m6">In an eyeblink she's gone, ripped from his arms. There was no scream. No cry. No final words. Just... Blackness.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s210">
      <sceneheader>EXT. PLANET'S ORBIT - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s210m1">Out of the blackness, a spot of fire races toward us. It resolves into the skiff, fabric wings burning off as it hits escape velocity.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s211">
      <sceneheader>INT. SKIFF - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s211m1">CLOSE on a bloody hand. It toggles through nav-charts, plots a rendezvous with &quot;Sol-Track 17B&quot; shipping lane. In the cockpit, Riddick finds Audrey beside him. She stares hypnotically at the stars ahead.</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s211d1">Probably okay to talk to me now.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="AUDREY">
         <dialogue id="s211d2">Not sure where to go. I was just runnin' away when this whole thing started. (a beat) Where you goin'?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s211d3">Not sure. I was just runnin' away when this whole thing....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s211m4">Interior smiles. Stars sweep the windscreen as the skiff makes a course-correction. One very bright star comes into view.</meta>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s211d4">Might interest you....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s211m5">Imam moves forward. Seeing, his face lifts.</meta>
      <char name="IMAM">
         <dialogue id="s211d5">New Mecca....</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="RIDDICK">
         <dialogue id="s211d6">Think a soul could get lost there? With all those pilgrim-types?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="IMAM">
         <dialogue id="s211d7">It's more a place where souls are found, Mr. Riddick.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s211m8">As Riddick ponders the possibilities, we CUT TO...</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s212">
      <sceneheader>EXT. PLANET'S ORBIT - NEW DAWN</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s212m1">The first sun flares out from behind the eclipsing planet. Its light feels cleansing. Renewing. Life-giving.</meta>
      <char name="FADE OUT">
         <dialogue id="s212d1"/>
      </char>
   </scene>
</movie>
