<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<movie>
   <info>American Psycho
Writers : Matthew Markwalder
Genres : DramaHorrorThriller</info>
   <scene id="s0">
      <sceneheader>MOVIEBEGINNING</sceneheader>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s1">
      <sceneheader>INT. PASTELS RESTAURANT- NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s1m1">An insanely expensive restaurant on the Upper East Side. The decor is a mixture of chi-chi and rustic, with swagged silk curtains, handwritten menus and pale pink tablecloths decorated with arrangements of moss, twigs and hideous exotic flowers. The clientele is young, wealthy and confident, dressed in the height of late-eighties style: pouffy Lacroix dresses, slinky Alaïa, Armani power suits. CLOSE-UP on a WAITER reading out the specials.</meta>
      <char name="WAITER">
         <dialogue id="s1d1">With goat cheese profiteroles and I also have an arugula Caesar salad. For entrées tonight I have a swordfish meatloaf with onion marmalade, a rare-roasted partridge breast in raspberry coulis with a sorrel timbale...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s1m2">Huge white porcelain plates descend on very pale pink linen table cloths. Each of the entrees is a rectangle about four inches square and look exactly alike. CLOSE-UP on various diners as we hear fragments of conversation. &quot;Is that Charlie Sheen over there?&quot; &quot;Excuse me? I ordered cactus pear sorbet.&quot;</meta>
      <char name="WAITER">
         <dialogue id="s1d2">And grilled free-range rabbit with herbed French fries. Our pasta tonight is a squid ravioli in a lemon grass broth...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s1m3">CLOSE-UP on porcelain plates containing elaborate perpendicular desserts descending on another table. PATRICK BATEMAN, TIMOTHY PRICE, CRAIG MCDERMOTT and DAVID VAN PATTEN are at a table set for four. They are all wearing expensively cut suits and suspenders and have slicked-back hair. Van Patten wears horn-rimmed glasses. The camera moves in on Bateman as his narration begins:</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN (V.O.)">
         <dialogue id="s1d3">We're sitting in Pastels, this nouvelle Northern California place on the Upper East Side.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s1m4">The Waiter sets down plates containing tiny, elaborately decorated starters. As he does so we hear Bateman's description of each of the men at the table.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN (V.O.)">
         <dialogue id="s1d4">You'll notice that my friends and I all look and behave in a remarkably similar fashion, but there are subtle differences between us. McDermott is the biggest asshole. Van Patten is the yes man. Price is the most wired. I'm the best looking. We all have light tans. Right now I'm in a bad mood because this is not a good table, and Van Patten keeps asking dumb, obvious questions about how to dress .</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="VAN PATTEN">
         <dialogue id="s1d5">What are the rules for a sweater vest?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s1m6">McDERMOTT What do you mean?</meta>
      <char name="PRICE">
         <dialogue id="s1d6">Yes. Clarify.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s1m7">McDERMOTT Well, is it strictly informal-</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s1d7">Or can it be worn with a suit?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s1m8">McDERMOTT (Smiling) Exactly</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s1d8">With discreet pinstripes you should wear a subdued blue or charcoal gray vest. A plaid suit would cal I for a bolder vest.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s1m9">McDERMOTT But avoid matching the vest's pattern with your socks or tie. Wearing argyle socks with an argyle vest will look too studied.</meta>
      <char name="VAN PATTEN">
         <dialogue id="s1d9">You think so?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="PRICE">
         <dialogue id="s1d10">You'll look like you consciously worked for the look.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="VAN PATTEN">
         <dialogue id="s1d11">Good point. Excuse me, gentlemen.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s1m12">Van Patten leaves the table. As he does so, a busboy discreetly removes their largely untouched plates.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s1d12">Van Patten looks puffy. Has he stopped working out?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="PRICE">
         <dialogue id="s1d13">It looks that way, doesn't it?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s1m14">McDERMOTT (Staring at retreating waiter) Did he just take our plates away?</meta>
      <char name="PRICE">
         <dialogue id="s1d14">He took them away because the portions are so small he probably thought we were finished. God, I hate this place. This is a chicks' restaurant. Why aren't we at Dorsia?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s1m15">McDERMOTT Because Bateman won't give the maitre d' head. (He guffaws) Bateman throws a swizzle stick at him. McDermott scans the room, settling on a handsome young man with slicked-back hair and horn-rimmed glasses. McDERMOTT Is that Reed Robinson over there?</meta>
      <char name="PRICE">
         <dialogue id="s1d15">Are you freebasing or what? That's not Robinson.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s1m16">McDERMOTT Who is it then?</meta>
      <char name="PRICE">
         <dialogue id="s1d16">That's Paul Owen.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s1d17">That's not Paul Owen. Paul Owen's on the other side of the room. Over there.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s1m18">He points to another handsome young man with slicked-back hair and horn-rimmed glasses. McDERMOTT Who is he with?</meta>
      <char name="PRICE">
         <dialogue id="s1d18">(Distracted by the waitress's cleavage as she bends over to uncork a bottle of wine  the waitress glares at him) Some weasel from Kicker Peabody.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s1m19">Van Patten returns.</meta>
      <char name="VAN PATTEN">
         <dialogue id="s1d19">They don't have a good bathroom to do coke in.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s1m20">McDERMOTT Are you sure that's Paul Owen over there?</meta>
      <char name="PRICE">
         <dialogue id="s1d20">Yes. McDufus, I am.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s1m21">McDERMOTT He's handling the Fisher account.</meta>
      <char name="PRICE">
         <dialogue id="s1d21">Lucky bastard.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s1m22">McDERMOTT Lucky Jew bastard.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s1d22">Oh Jesus, McDermott, what does that have to do with anything?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s1m23">McDERMOTT Listen. I've seen the bastard sitting in his office on the phone with CEOs, spinning a fucking menorah. The bastard brought a Hanukkah bush into the office last December.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s1d23">You spin a dreidel, McDermott, not a menorah. You spin a dreidel.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s1m24">McDERMOTT Oh my God. Bateman, do you want me to fry you up some fucking potato pancakes? Some latkes?</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s1d24">No. Just cool it with the anti-Semitic remarks.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s1m25">McDERMOTT Oh I forgot. Bateman's dating someone from the ACLU. Price leans over and pats Bateman on the back.</meta>
      <char name="PRICE">
         <dialogue id="s1d25">The voice of reason. The boy next door. And speaking of reasonable...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s1m26">He shows McDermott the bill for the meal. McDERMOTT Only $470.</meta>
      <char name="VAN PATTEN">
         <dialogue id="s1d26">(Without irony) Not bad.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s1m27">The others murmur agreement. Four platinum Amex cards slap down on the table.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s2">
      <sceneheader>INT. LIMOUSINE - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s2m1">lighting up a cigar. McDERMOTT Last week I picked up this Vassar chick-</meta>
      <char name="VAN PATTEN">
         <dialogue id="s2d1">Oh God, I was there. I don't need to hear this story again.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s2m2">McDERMOTT But I never told you what happened afterwards. So okay, I pick up this Vassar chick at Tunnel-hot number, big tits, great legs, this chick was a little hardbody-and so I buy her a couple of champagne kirs and she's in the city on spring break and she's practically blowing me in the Chandelier Room and so I take her back to my place-</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s2d2">Whoa, wait. May I ask where Pamela is during all this?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s2m3">McDERMOTT Oh fuck you. I want a blowjob, Bate-man. I want a chick who's gonna let me-</meta>
      <char name="VAN PATTEN">
         <dialogue id="s2d3">(Putting his hands over his ears) I don't want to hear this. He's going to say something disgusting.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s2m4">McDERMOTT You prude. Listen, we're not gonna invest in a co-op together or jet down to Saint Bart's. I just want some chick whose face I can sit on for thirty, forty minutes. Price throws a cigar at McDermott, who catches it. McDERMOTT Anyway, so we're back at my place and listen to this. She's had enough champagne by now to get a fucking rhino tipsy, and get this-</meta>
      <char name="VAN PATTEN">
         <dialogue id="s2d4">She let you fuck her without a condom?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s2m5">McDERMOTT This is a Vassar girl. She's not from Queens. She would only-are you ready? (Dramatic pause) She would only give me a handjob, and get this...she kept her glove on. The men sit in shocked, horrified silence. ALL IN UNISON Never date a Vassar girl.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s3">
      <sceneheader>EXT. TUNNEL NIGHTCLUB - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s3m1">The limo pulls up to the sidewalk outside the Tunnel. McDermott holds the door open for a passing HOMELESS MAN, who looks confused. McDERMOTT I suppose he doesn't want the car. Price, ask him if he takes American Express.</meta>
      <char name="PRICE">
         <dialogue id="s3d1">(Offering card) You take Amex, dude?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s3m2">The man stumbles away. The club DOORMAN, seeing the limousine, unhooks the velvet rope and welcomes them inside.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s4">
      <sceneheader>INT. LADIES ROOM, TUNNEL - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s4m1">Brilliant white light, a bemused elderly female attendant in a black-and-white maid's uniform trying to give out paper towels. MUSIC thuds through an open doorway. Trashed-looking girls stare into mirrors repairing their eye make-up or sit on the counter chatting to friends. There are almost as many men as women in the room. Couples stand in line, twitching as they wait to do coke. As soon as one bathroom door opens, a couple lurches out rubbing their noses while another couple rushes past them and slams the door.</meta>
      <char name="PRICE">
         <dialogue id="s4d1">There's this theory out now that if you can catch the AIDS virus through having sex with someone who is infected, then you can also catch anything-Alzheimer's, muscular dystrophy, hemophilia, leukemia, diabetes, dyslexia, for Christ's sake-you can get dyslexia from pussy-</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s4d2">I'm not sure, guy, but I don't think dyslexia is a virus.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="PRICE">
         <dialogue id="s4d3">Oh, who knows? They don't know that. Prove it.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s4m4">Price and Bateman finally get a stall and rush in. Price is sweating.</meta>
      <char name="PRICE">
         <dialogue id="s4d4">I'm shaking. You open it.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s4m5">Bateman opens a tiny packet of coke.</meta>
      <char name="PRICE">
         <dialogue id="s4d5">Jeez. That's not a helluva lot, is it?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s4d6">Maybe it's just the light.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="PRICE">
         <dialogue id="s4d7">Is he fucking selling it by the milligram? (He dips the corner of his Amex card in the packet and takes a snort) Oh my God...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s4d8">What?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="PRICE">
         <dialogue id="s4d9">It's a fucking milligram of Sweet'n Low!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s4m10">Bateman dips his Amex in the envelope and snorts.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s4d10">It's definitely weak but I have a feeling if we do enough of it we'll be okay.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="PRICE">
         <dialogue id="s4d11">I want to get high off this; Bateman, not sprinkle it on my fucking All-Bran.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s4m12">The GUY IN STALL next door yells at them in an effeminate voice:</meta>
      <char name="GUY IN STALL">
         <dialogue id="s4d12">Could you keep it down, I'm trying to do drugs!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s4m13">Price pounds his fist against the stall.</meta>
      <char name="PRICE">
         <dialogue id="s4d13">(screaming) SHUT UP!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s4d14">Calm down. Let's do it anyway</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="PRICE">
         <dialogue id="s4d15">I guess you're right... (Raising his voice) THAT IS, IF THE FAGGOT IN THE NEXT STALL THINKS IT'S OKAY!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="GUY IN STALL">
         <dialogue id="s4d16">Fuck you!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="PRICE">
         <dialogue id="s4d17">(Trying to climb up against the aluminum divider) No, FUCK YOU!! (He collapses, panting against the stall door) Sorry, dude. Steroids...Okay, let's do it.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s4d18">That's the spirit.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s4m19">They both dig their platinum Amex cards into the envelope of white powder, shoveling it up their noses, then sticking their fingers in to catch the residue and rubbing it into their gums.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s5">
      <sceneheader>INT. NIGHTCLUB - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s5m1">Bateman saunters toward the bar as &quot;Pump Up the Volume&quot; plays in the background. BATEMAN (to BARGIRL) Two Stoli on the rocks. He hands her two drink tickets.</meta>
      <char name="BARGIRL">
         <dialogue id="s5d1">It's after eleven. Those aren't good anymore. It's a cash bar. That'll be twenty-five dollars.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s5m2">Bateman pulls out an expensive-looking wallet and hands her a $50. She turns her back and searches the cash register for change. BATEMAN You are a fucking ugly bitch I want to stab to death and then play around with your blood. The music muffles his voice. She turns around. He is smiling at her. She gives him his change impassively.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s6">
      <sceneheader>INT. BATEMAN'S APARTMENT- MORNING</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s6m1">Tableaux of Bateman's apartment in the early morning light. A huge white living room with floor-to-ceiling windows looking out over Manhattan, decorated in expensive, minimalist high style: bleached oak floors, a huge white sofa, a large Baselitz painting (hung upside down) and much expensive electronic equipment. The room is impeccably neat, and oddly impersonal - as if it had sprung straight from the pages of a design magazine.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN (V.0.)">
         <dialogue id="s6d1">My name is Patrick Bateman. I am twenty-six years old. I live in the American Garden Buildings on West Eighty-First Street, on the eleventh floor Tom Cruise lives in the penthouse.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s6m2">Bateman walks into his bathroom, urinates while trying to see his reflection in a poster for Les Miserables above his toilet.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s6d2">(V.0.) I believe in taking care of myself, in a balanced diet, in a rigorous exercise routine. In the morning, if my face is a little puffy, I'll put on an ice pack while doing my stomach crunches. I can do a thousand now.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s6m3">Bateman ties a plastic ice pack around his face. Bateman does his morning stretching exercises in the living room wearing the ice pack.</meta>
      <meta id="s6m4">CUT TO: A mirror-lined bathroom. Bateman is luxuriating in the shower steam, scrubbing his body, admiring his muscles.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN (V.O.)">
         <dialogue id="s6d4">After I remove the icepack, I use a deep pore-cleanser lotion. In the shower, I use a water-activated gel cleanser, then a honey-almond body scrub, and on the face an exfoliating gel scrub.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s6m5">Bateman stands in front of a massive marble sink applying a gel facial masque.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN (V.O.)">
         <dialogue id="s6d5">Then I apply an herb mint facial masque which I leave on for ten minutes while I prepare the rest of my routine.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s6m6">Bateman opens the door of a mirrored cabinet, which is stocked with immaculate rows of skin care products. He begins selecting bottles jars and brushes, laying them in readiness on the marble counter.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN (V.O.)">
         <dialogue id="s6d6">I always use an after-shave lotion with little or no alcohol because alcohol dries your face out and makes you look older. Then moisturizer, then an anti-aging eye balm, followed by a final moisturizing &quot;protective&quot; lotion...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s6m7">Bateman stares into the mirror. The masque has dried, giving his face a strange distorted look as if it has been wrapped in plastic. He begins slowly peeling the gel masque off his face.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN (V.O.)">
         <dialogue id="s6d7">There is an idea of a Patrick Bateman, some kind of abstraction, hut there is no real me, only an entity, something illusory, and though I can hide my cold gaze and you can shake my hand and feel flesh gripping you and maybe you can even sense our lifestyles are probably comparable: I simply am not there.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s7">
      <sceneheader>INT. BATEMAN BEDROOM - MORNING</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s7m1">Another huge white room, equally minimal: a futon, rumpled white sheets, a bedside lamp with a halogen bulb, and a large expensive painting (Eric Fischl or David Salle) chosen by Bateman's interior decorator. Dressed in silk boxer shorts, Bateman stands in front of a huge walk-in closet, filled with rows of expensive shirts, shoes and designer suits, organized according to color and tone.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN (V.O.)">
         <dialogue id="s7d1">It is hard for me to make sense on any given level. My self is fabricated, an aberration. My personality is sketchy and unformed, my heartlessness goes deep and is persistent.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s7m2">Fully dressed in Armani, Bateman stands in front of a full-length mirror in the middle of his vast bedroom, adjusting his cuff-links.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN (V.0.)">
         <dialogue id="s7d2">My conscience, my pity, my hopes disappeared a long time ago, if they ever did exist.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s7m3">He gives a last look at the mirror and likes what he sees. He gives his reflection a smile.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s8">
      <sceneheader>INT. OFFICES OF PIERCE &amp; PIERCE - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s8m1">As Bateman walks down the corridor, he passes another MAN who looks just like him.</meta>
      <char name="MAN">
         <dialogue id="s8d1">Morning, Hamilton. Nice tan.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s8m2">Bateman walks past the desk of JEAN, his secretary, pulling his Walkman from around his neck. Jean is attractive, wholesome, earnest. She smiles shyly. She loves him.</meta>
      <char name="JEAN">
         <dialogue id="s8d2">Late?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s8d3">Aerobics class. Sorry. Any messages?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JEAN">
         <dialogue id="s8d4">Ricky Hendricks has to cancel today. He didn't say what he was canceling or why.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s8d5">I occasionally box with Ricky at the Harvard Club. Anyone else?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JEAN">
         <dialogue id="s8d6">And...Spencer wants to meet you for a drink at Fluties Pier 17.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s8d7">When?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JEAN">
         <dialogue id="s8d8">After six.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s8d9">Negative. Cancel it.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s8m10">Jean follows him into his office.</meta>
      <char name="JEAN">
         <dialogue id="s8d10">Oh? And what should I say?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s8d11">Just...say...no.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JEAN">
         <dialogue id="s8d12">Just say no?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s8m13">Jean stands at his desk, waiting for instructions.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s8d13">Okay, Jean. I need reservations for three at Camols at twelve-thirty, and if not there, try Crayons. All right?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JEAN">
         <dialogue id="s8d14">(Playfully) Yes, sir.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s8m15">She turns to leave.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s8d15">Oh wait. And I need reservations for two at Arcadia at eight tonight.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s8m16">Jean turns around.</meta>
      <char name="JEAN">
         <dialogue id="s8d16">Oh, something. . romantic?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s8d17">No, silly. Forget it. I'll make them. Thanks.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JEAN">
         <dialogue id="s8d18">I'll do it.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s8d19">No. No. Be a doll and just get me a Perrier, okay?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JEAN">
         <dialogue id="s8d20">You look nice today.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s8m21">Jean exits. Bateman straightens some magazines in his office, lifts a painting off the wall and puts it back at a slightly different angle. He fiddles with some pencils in a beer stein. He puts on some MUSIC and flips through a Sports Illustrated. He buzzes Jean. She comes in a moment later with the Perrier and a file.</meta>
      <char name="JEAN">
         <dialogue id="s8d21">Yes?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s8d22">Is that the Ransom file? Thanks. Don't wear that outfit again.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JEAN">
         <dialogue id="s8d23">Ummm...what? I didn't hear you.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s8d24">I said &quot;Do not wear that outfit again.&quot; Wear a dress. A skirt or something.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s8m25">Jean stands there, then looks down at herself.</meta>
      <char name="JEAN">
         <dialogue id="s8d25">(Smiling bravely) You don't like this, I take it?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s8d26">Come on, you're prettier than that.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JEAN">
         <dialogue id="s8d27">(Sarcastically) Thanks, Patrick.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s8m28">The phone RINGS and Jean turns to leave.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s8d28">I'm not here. And high heels. I like high heels.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s8m29">As Jean leaves, Bateman clicks on the TV set in one corner of the room and starts watching Jeopardy!</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s9">
      <sceneheader>INT. TAXI - EVENING</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s9m1">EVELYN WILLIAMS, Patrick Bateman's fiancée, is making notes with a gold Cross pen and sipping a bottle of mineral water. Evelyn is blonde, classically beautiful, expensively educated, and utterly pleased with herself. She usually addresses Patrick as if he were a small child.</meta>
      <char name="EVELYN">
         <dialogue id="s9d1">I'd want a zydeco band, Patrick. That's what I'd want, a zydeco band. Or mariachi. Or reggae. Something ethnic to shock Daddy Oh, I can't decide...And lots of chocolate truffles. Godiva. And oysters on the halfshell.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s9m2">CLOSE-UP on Bateman, who is wearing a Walkman and staring out the window.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN (V.O.)">
         <dialogue id="s9d2">I'm trying to listen to the new George Michael tape but Evelyn-my supposed fiancée-keeps buzzing in my ear.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s9m3">Evelyn continues to make notes.</meta>
      <char name="EVELYN">
         <dialogue id="s9d3">Marzipan. Pink tents. Hundreds, thousands of roses. Photographers. Annie Leibovitz. We'll get Annie Leibovitz. And we'll hire someone to videotape. Patrick, we should do it.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s9d4">(Removing his Walkman) Do...what.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="EVELYN">
         <dialogue id="s9d5">Get married. Have a wedding.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s9d6">Evelyn?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="EVELYN">
         <dialogue id="s9d7">Yes, darling?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s9d8">Is your Evian spiked?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="EVELYN">
         <dialogue id="s9d9">We should do it.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s9d10">No-I can't take the time off work.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="EVELYN">
         <dialogue id="s9d11">Your father practically owns the company. You can do anything you like, silly.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s9d12">I don't want to talk about it.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="EVELYN">
         <dialogue id="s9d13">Well, you hate that job anyway. Why don't you just quit? You don't have to work.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s9d14">Because I...want...to...fit...in.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s9m15">The taxi bumps to a halt.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s10">
      <sceneheader>INT. ESPACE RESTAURANT- NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s10m1">A cavernous garage, harshly spot-lit, decorated in self-conscious brutalist chic. Iron girders, walls of waxed plaster featuring exposed rusted pipes, a huge Schnabel smashed-plate painting on one wall. The tables and chairs are made of extremely uncomfortable bolted steel.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN (V.O.)">
         <dialogue id="s10d1">I'm on the verge of tears by the time we arrive at Espace since I'm positive we won't have a decent table, but we do, and relief washes over me in an awesome wave.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s10m2">Tm Price and two downtown types, STASH and VANDEN, are already seated. Vanden is about twenty, pretty and sullen, with green streaks in her black hair. Stash is pale, with ragged black hair and bad skin. They are all trying to read large stainless steel menus that look like minimalist art.</meta>
      <char name="PRICE">
         <dialogue id="s10d2">The menu's in braille.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s10m3">He gets up to greet them, giving Evelyn a suspiciously long kiss.</meta>
      <char name="PRICE">
         <dialogue id="s10d3">I have to talk to you.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s10m4">He drags her away, half giggling and protesting.</meta>
      <char name="EVELYN">
         <dialogue id="s10d4">(Over her shoulder) Pat, this is my cousin Vanden and her boyfriend Stash. He's an artist.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s10d5">(After smiling at his own reflection in the mirror and checking his hair) Hi. Pat Bateman.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s10m6">Vanden takes his hand reluctantly, says nothing.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s10d6">Let me guess-you live in the East Village?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s10m7">Pause.</meta>
      <char name="STASH">
         <dialogue id="s10d7">SoHo.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s10m8">COURTNEY RAWLINSON and LUIS CARRUTHERS arrive at the table. Courtney is blonde, classically beautiful and from precisely the same social background as Evelyn, but she is considerably more fragile and neurotic. Luis is half-English, half-Argentinean, slightly overweight (a rarity in this crowd), puppyish and eager to please. He wears the same type of designer clothes as Price and Bateman, but with foppish tendencies: velvet jackets, bow-ties, boldly patterned vests. They exchange air kisses. As soon as Luis turns his back, Bateman sneaks a kiss on Courtney's neck.</meta>
      <char name="COURTNEY">
         <dialogue id="s10d8">(Whispering) Stop it!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s10m9">Stash and Vanden watch them in silence.</meta>
      <meta id="s10m10">LATER: Price is whispering in Evelyn's ear. Everyone else is quietly eating, except Bateman, who is drinking and watching Evelyn and Price.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN (V.O.)">
         <dialogue id="s10d10">I am fairly sure that Timothy and Evelyn are having an affair. Timothy is the only interesting person I know. Courtney is almost perfect looking. She s usually operating on one or more psychiatric drugs. Tonight I believe it's Xanax. More disturbing than her drug use, though, is the fact that she's engaged to Luis Carruthers, the biggest dufus in the business.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s10m11">Courtney rouses herself from her drug haze.</meta>
      <char name="COURTNEY">
         <dialogue id="s10d11">Tell me. Stash...do you think SoHo is becoming to...commercial?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="CARRUTHERS">
         <dialogue id="s10d12">Yes, I read that.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="PRICE">
         <dialogue id="s10d13">Oh, who gives a rat's ass?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="VANDEN">
         <dialogue id="s10d14">Hey. That affects us.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="PRICE">
         <dialogue id="s10d15">(Wired on coke) Oh ho ho. That affects us? What about the massacres in Sri Lanka, honey? Doesn't that affect us, too? I mean don't you know anything about Sri Lanka? About how the Sikhs are killing like tons of Israelis there? Doesn't that affect us?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s10d16">Oh come on. Price. There are a lot more important problems than Sri Lanka to worry about. Sure our foreign policy is important, but there are more pressing problems at hand.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="PRICE">
         <dialogue id="s10d17">Like what?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s10d18">Well, we have to end apartheid for one. And slow down the nuclear arms race, stop terrorism and world hunger. But we can't ignore our social needs. either We have to stop people from abusing the welfare system. We have to provide food and shelter for the homeless and oppose racial discrimination and promote civil rights while also promoting equal rights for women but change the abortion laws to protect the right to life yet still somehow maintain women's freedom of choice.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s10m19">The table stares at Bateman uncomfortably.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s10d19">We also have to control the influx of illegal immigrants. We have to encourage a return to traditional moral values and curb graphic sex and violence on TV, in movies, in pop music, everywhere. Most importantly we have to promote general social concern and less materialism in young people.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s10m20">Price chokes on his drink. Everyone is silent and mystified.</meta>
      <char name="CARRUTHERS">
         <dialogue id="s10d20">Patrick, how thought-provoking.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s11">
      <sceneheader>INT. EVELYN'S BEDROOM - LATER THE SAME EVENING</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s11m1">Bateman and Evelyn are lying on her bed watching television.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s11d1">Why don t you just go for Price?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="EVELYN">
         <dialogue id="s11d2">Oh God, Patrick. Why Price? Price?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s11d3">He's rich.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="EVELYN">
         <dialogue id="s11d4">Everybody's rich.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s11d5">He's good-looking.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="EVELYN">
         <dialogue id="s11d6">Everybody's good-looking, Patrick.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s11d7">He has a great body</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="EVELYN">
         <dialogue id="s11d8">Everybody has a great body now.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s11m9">Bateman unbuttons his shirt and makes advances to get Evelyn to have sex with him. She ignores him, watching the Home Shopping Channel with the remote in her hand. Finally, he straddles her, penis close to her face. She tries to look around him at the TV, then takes notice.</meta>
      <char name="EVELYN">
         <dialogue id="s11d9">What do you want to do with that, floss with it?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s11m10">Bateman flops back down beside her and stares at the television.</meta>
      <char name="EVELYN">
         <dialogue id="s11d10">Are you using minoxidil?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s11d11">No. I'm not. Why should I ?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="EVELYN">
         <dialogue id="s11d12">Your hairline looks like it's receding.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s11d13">It's not.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s12">
      <sceneheader>EXT. STREET - LATER THAT NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s12m1">It is 3 a.m. Bateman is standing at an ATM, listening to the comforting sound of fresh bills thudding out of the machine. Bateman turns around and watches a solitary young woman walk past him. He collects his money, placing it carefully in his wallet, and then walks toward her, whistling. He catches up to her as she pauses at a red light.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s12d1">Hello.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s12m2">The woman looks suspicious for a moment and then, seeing his smile, smiles back.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s13">
      <sceneheader>INT. DRY CLEANERS - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s13m1">Bateman, dressed in an Armani suit with an unlit cigar between his teeth is standing in a dry cleaners, arguing with the Chinese woman behind the counter.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s13d1">Listen, wait. You're not...shhh wait... you're not giving me valid reasons.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s13m2">The woman continues to speak to him in another language, grabbing at the sleeve of the jacket.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s13d2">What are you trying to say to me?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s13m3">Her husband has taken Bateman's horribly bloodstained sheets out of the bag and is staring at them.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s13d3">Bleach-ee? Are you trying to say bleach-ee? Bleach-ee. Oh my God.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s13m4">She keeps pointing to the jacket and talking.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s13d4">(Talking over her) Two things. One. You can't bleach a Soprani. Out of the question. Two. (Louder) Two. I can only get these sheets in Santa Fe. These are very expensive sheets and I really need them clean.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s13m5">She keeps talking and Bateman leans into her.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s13d5">If you don't shut your fucking mouth I will kill you, are you understanding me?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s13m6">She talks faster.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s13d6">Now listen-I have a very important lunch meeting (Checks Rolex) at Hubert's in thirty minutes, and I need those ...no wait, twenty minutes. I have a lunch meeting at Hubert's in twenty minutes with Ronald Harrison and I need those sheets cleaned by this afternoon.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s13m7">She keeps talking. BATEMAN Listen. I cannot understand you. Bateman starts laughing, slaps his hand down on the counter.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s13d7">This is crazy. You're a fool. I can't cope with this.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s13m8">Bateman is on the verge of tears.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s13d8">Stupid bitchee! Understand? Oh Christ!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s13m9">Someone enters the store behind him. It's VICTORIA, late-twenties, attractive but a little overweight, wearing a tailored business suit with white sneakers and sports socks.</meta>
      <char name="VICTORIA">
         <dialogue id="s13d9">Patrick?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s13m10">She takes off her sunglasses.</meta>
      <char name="VICTORIA">
         <dialogue id="s13d10">Hi, Patrick. I thought that was you.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s13d11">Hello (Mumbles un incomprehensible name)</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s13m12">Awkward pause.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s13d12">Well.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="VICTORIA">
         <dialogue id="s13d13">Isn't it ridiculous? Coming all the way up here, but you know. They really are the best.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s13d14">Then why can't they get these stains out? I mean can you talk to these people or something? I'm not getting anywhere.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s13m15">Victoria moves toward the sheet that the old man is holding up. She touches it and the woman behind the counter begins talking again.</meta>
      <char name="VICTORIA">
         <dialogue id="s13d15">Oh my, I see. What are those? Oh my.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s13d16">Um, well...it s cranberry juice. Cranapple.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s13m17">VICTORiA (Skeptically) Really?</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s13d17">Well, I mean, um, it s really...Bosco. You know, like... like a Dove Bar. It's a Dove Bar...Hershey's Syrup?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="VICTORIA">
         <dialogue id="s13d18">(As if sharing a secret joke) Oh yeah. Oh I get it. Fun with chocolate.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s13d19">Listen, if you could talk to them (He yanks the sheet out of the man's hand) I would really appreciate it. I'm really late. I have a lunch appointment at Hubert's in fifteen minutes.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s13m20">Bateman turns to leave.</meta>
      <char name="VICTORIA">
         <dialogue id="s13d20">Hubert's? Oh really? It moved uptown, right?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s13d21">Yeah, well, oh boy, listen, I've got to go. Thank you, uh... Victoria?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="VICTORIA">
         <dialogue id="s13d22">Maybe we could have lunch one day next week? You know, I'm downtown near Wall Street quite often.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s13d23">Oh, I don't know, Victoria. I'm at work all the time.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="VICTORIA">
         <dialogue id="s13d24">Well, what about, oh, you know, maybe a Saturday?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s13d25">(Checking his watch) Next Saturday?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="VICTORIA">
         <dialogue id="s13d26">(Shrugging) Yeah.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s13d27">Oh, can't, I'm afraid. Matinée of Les Miserables. Listen, I've really got to go. I'll-Oh...Christ...I'll call you.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="VICTORIA">
         <dialogue id="s13d28">Okay. Do.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s13m29">Bateman glares at the woman behind the counter and rushes out the door. Victoria stares after him as we hear the sound of the bell on the closing door.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s14">
      <sceneheader>INT. BATEMAN'S APARTMENT - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s14m1">Bateman is sitting on the sofa watching a video, talking to Courtney on a portable phone. He's holding a video box in one hand, perusing the title: Inside Lydia's Ass. Offscreen we hear the sounds of the porn movie as he talks.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s14d1">Listen, what are you doing tonight?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="COURTNEY">
         <dialogue id="s14d2">What? Oh, I'm...busy.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s14d3">Listen, you're dating Luis, he's in Arizona. You're fucking me, and we haven't made plans. What could you possibly be up to tonight?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="COURTNEY">
         <dialogue id="s14d4">Stop it. I'm...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s14d5">On a lot of lithium?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="COURTNEY">
         <dialogue id="s14d6">Waiting for Luis to call me. He said he'd call tonight. Oh don't be difficult, Patrick.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s14d7">You should come have dinner with me.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="COURTNEY">
         <dialogue id="s14d8">But-when?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s14d9">Am I confused or were we talking about tonight?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="COURTNEY">
         <dialogue id="s14d10">Ummm . . yeah. Luis is calling me tonight. I need to be home for that.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s14d11">Pumpkin?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="COURTNEY">
         <dialogue id="s14d12">Yes?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s14d13">Pumpkin you're dating an asshole.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="COURTNEY">
         <dialogue id="s14d14">Uh huh.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s14d15">Pumpkin you're dating the biggest dickweed in New York.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="COURTNEY">
         <dialogue id="s14d16">I know. Stop it.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s14d17">Pumpkin, you're dating a tumbling, tumbling dickweed.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="COURTNEY">
         <dialogue id="s14d18">Patrick don't call me pumpkin anymore, okay? I have to go.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s14d19">Courtney? Dinner?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="COURTNEY">
         <dialogue id="s14d20">I can't.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s14d21">I'm thinking Dorsia.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="COURTNEY">
         <dialogue id="s14d22">Dorsia's nice.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s14d23">Nice?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="COURTNEY">
         <dialogue id="s14d24">You like it there, don't you?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s14d25">The question is do you like it, Courtney? And will you blow off a fucking phone call from your sad excuse for a boyfriend to eat there tonight.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="COURTNEY">
         <dialogue id="s14d26">Okay. Yeah. What time?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s14d27">Eight?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="COURTNEY">
         <dialogue id="s14d28">Pick me up?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s14d29">Sounds like I'll have to. Don't fall asleep, okay? Wear something fabulous. Dorsia, remember?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s14m30">Bateman hangs up, opens up the Zagat's guide and dials the number for Dorsia with trembling fingers. It's busy and so he puts it on speakerphone, constant redial. He waits with his head in his hands, sweating with anxiety, until there is finally an answer.</meta>
      <char name="MAITRE D'">
         <dialogue id="s14d30">Dorsia. Please hold.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s14m31">He is on hold for a long time, getting very tense.</meta>
      <char name="MAITRE D'">
         <dialogue id="s14d31">Dorsia.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s14d32">(Both of his eyes are closed) Umm...yes...I know it's a little late but is it possible to reserve a table for two at eight or eight-thirty perhaps?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s14m33">Long pause. The Maitre D' starts giggling quietly and then more loudly until the laughter is almost hysterical and he hangs up the phone.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s15">
      <sceneheader>INT. TAXI- NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s15m1">Bateman and Courtney are in the back of a cab. Courtney is heavily medicated.</meta>
      <char name="COURTNEY">
         <dialogue id="s15d1">A facial at Elizabeth Arden, which was really relaxing, then to the Pottery Bam where I bought this silver muffin dish. (She starts to pass out)</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s15d2">Is that Donald Trump's car?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="COURTNEY">
         <dialogue id="s15d3">(Thickly) Oh God, Patrick. Shut up.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s15d4">You know, Courtney, you should take some more lithium. Or have a Diet Coke. Some caffeine might get you out of this slump.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="COURTNEY">
         <dialogue id="s15d5">I just want to have a child. Just...two... perfect...children... (Her voice trails as she descends back into a drug haze)</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s15m6">The cab draws up outside a restaurant. The awning reads &quot;Barcadia.&quot;</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s16">
      <sceneheader>INT. BARCADIA - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s16m1">An insanely expensive nouvelle Italian restaurant all polished natural brick, spotless white tablecloths, minimalist flower arrangements, discreet lighting. A waiter has come to take their drink orders.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s16d1">J&amp;B.; Straight.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="COURTNEY">
         <dialogue id="s16d2">Champagne on the rocks. Oh-could I have that with a twist? She starts to sink back in her chair and Bateman leans over and pulls her back up.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="COURTNEY">
         <dialogue id="s16d3">Are we here?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s16d4">Yes.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="COURTNEY">
         <dialogue id="s16d5">This is Dorsia?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s16d6">(Examining a menu that says &quot;Barcadia&quot; in large script) Yes, dear.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s16m7">Courtney almost falls asleep while looking at her menu, and starts to slide off of her chair. Bateman grabs her by both shoulders and props her up.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s16d7">Courtney, you're going to have the peanut butter soup with smoked duck and mashed squash. New York magazine called it a 'playful but mysterious little dish.&quot; You'll love it. And then...the red snapper with violets and pine nuts. I think that'll follow nicely.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="COURTNEY">
         <dialogue id="s16d8">Mmmm...thanks, Patrick.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s16m9">She falls asleep at the table.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s17">
      <sceneheader>INT. COURTNEY'S BEDROOM - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s17m1">top of her, reaching for a condom in the ashtray. He tears it open with his teeth, puts it on.</meta>
      <char name="COURTNEY">
         <dialogue id="s17d1">(Dazed on lithium) I want you to fuck me.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s17m2">Bateman gets on top of her, starts to fuck her.</meta>
      <char name="COURTNEY">
         <dialogue id="s17d2">Luis is a despicable twit.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s17d3">Yes, Luis is a despicable twit. I hate him.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s17m4">He keeps fucking her.</meta>
      <char name="COURTNEY">
         <dialogue id="s17d4">No, you idiot. I said &quot;Is it a receptacle tip?&quot; Not, is Luis a despicable twit. Is it a receptacle tip? Get off me.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s17d5">Is it a what?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="COURTNEY">
         <dialogue id="s17d6">Pull out.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s17d7">I'm ignoring you.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="COURTNEY">
         <dialogue id="s17d8">(screaming) Pull out, goddamnit!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s17d9">(Slowing down but not stopping) What do you want, Courtney?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s17m10">She pushes him away from her.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s17d10">It's a plain end. I think.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="COURTNEY">
         <dialogue id="s17d11">Turn the light on.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s17m12">She tries to sit up.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s17d12">Oh Jesus. I'm going home.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="COURTNEY">
         <dialogue id="s17d13">Patrick. Turn on the Light. He turns on the light.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s17d14">It's a plain end, see? So?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="COURTNEY">
         <dialogue id="s17d15">Take it off.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s17d16">Why?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="COURTNEY">
         <dialogue id="s17d17">Because you have to leave half an inch at the tip  (She covers herself with her comforter) to catch the force of the ejaculate!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s17d18">I'm getting out of here. Where's your lithium?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s17m19">Courtney throws a pillow over her head and starts crying.</meta>
      <char name="COURTNEY">
         <dialogue id="s17d19">(Screaming) Do you think you're turning me on by having unsafe sex?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s17m20">Bateman pulls the pillow off her and slaps her face.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s17d20">Oh Christ, this really isn't worth it. And see, Courtney, it's there for what? Huh? Tell us. (He slaps her again lightly) Why is it pulled down half an inch? So it can catch the force of the ejaculate!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="COURTNEY">
         <dialogue id="s17d21">(Choking crying) Well, it's not a turn-on for me. I have a promotion coming to me. I don't want to get AIDS.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s17m22">Bateman grabs her head and makes her look at the condom.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s17d22">See? Happy? You dumb bitch? Are you happy, you dumb bitch?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="COURTNEY">
         <dialogue id="s17d23">Oh God, just get it over with.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s17m24">He fucks her quickly until he has a mediocre orgasm and falls down next to her. They lie side by side with their bodies not touching, eyes open, staring at the ceiling.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s18">
      <sceneheader>INT. CONFERENCE ROOM, PIERCE &amp; PIERCE - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s18m1">Bateman and Luis Carruthers are seated at a long table in the conference room at Pierce &amp; Pierce, which looks out onto a spectacular view of Manhattan.</meta>
      <char name="CARRUTHERS">
         <dialogue id="s18d1">Patrick, thanks so much for looking after Courtney. Dorsia, how impressive! How on earth did you get a reservation there?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s18d2">Lucky, I guess.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="CARRUTHERS">
         <dialogue id="s18d3">That's a wonderful jacket. Let me guess, Valentino Couture?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s18d4">Uh huh.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="CARRUTHERS">
         <dialogue id="s18d5">(Reaching out to touch it) It looks so soft.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s18d6">(Catching Luis hand) Your compliment was sufficient Luis.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s18m7">Carruthers is distracted by a question from the colleague on his left.Paul Owen enters, carrying the Wall St. Journal under his arm. He is handsome, supremely confident and self-satisfied; he sees himself as a leader among men.</meta>
      <char name="OWEN">
         <dialogue id="s18d7">(To Bateman) Hello, Halberstam. Nice tie. How the hell are you?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s18d8">I've been great. And you?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s18m9">Their conversation fades down as we hear Bateman's thoughts.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN (V.O.)">
         <dialogue id="s18d9">Owen has mistaken me for this dickhead Marcus Halberstam. It seems logical because Marcus also works at P&amp;P; and in fact does the same exact thing I do and he also has a penchant for Valentino suits and Oliver Peoples glasses. Marcus and I even go to the same barber, although I have a slightly better haircut.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s18m10">During this voiceover the CAMERA WANDERS over to MARCUS HALBERSTAM, who is conferring with a colleague in the opposite corner of the room. He bears a superficial resemblance to Bateman.</meta>
      <char name="OWEN">
         <dialogue id="s18d10">How's the Ransom account going, Marcus?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s18d11">(Nervous) It's...it's...all right.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="OWEN">
         <dialogue id="s18d12">Really? That's interesting. (He stares at Bateman, smiling) Not great?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s18d13">Oh well, you know.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="OWEN">
         <dialogue id="s18d14">And how's Cecilia? She's a great girl.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s18d15">Oh yes. I'm very lucky.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s18m16">McDermott and Price enter. McDERMOTT Hey. Owen! Congratulations on the Fisher account.</meta>
      <char name="OWEN">
         <dialogue id="s18d16">Thank you, Baxter.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="PRICE">
         <dialogue id="s18d17">Listen, Paul. Squash?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="OWEN">
         <dialogue id="s18d18">Call me. (Hands him a business card)</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="PRICE">
         <dialogue id="s18d19">How about Friday?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="OWEN">
         <dialogue id="s18d20">No can do. Got a res at eight-thirty at Dorsia. Great sea urchin ceviche. There is a stunned silence as he walks away and sits in a corner of the room, ostentatiously studying papers.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s18m21">CLOSE-UP on Bateman's face, cold with hatred.</meta>
      <char name="PRICE">
         <dialogue id="s18d21">(Whispering) Jesus. Dorsia? On a Friday night? How'd he swing that?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s18m22">McDERMOTT (Whispering) I think he's lying. Bateman takes out his wallet and pulls out a card.</meta>
      <char name="PRICE">
         <dialogue id="s18d22">(Suddenly enthused) What's that, a gram?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s18d23">New card. What do you think?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s18m24">McDermott lifts it up and examines the lettering carefully. McDERMOTT Whoa. Very nice. Take a look. He hands it to Van Patten.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s18d24">Picked them up from the printers yesterday</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="VAN PATTEN">
         <dialogue id="s18d25">Good coloring.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s18d26">That's bone. And the lettering is something called Silian Rail.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s18m27">McDERMOTT (Envious) Silian Rail?</meta>
      <char name="VAN PATTEN">
         <dialogue id="s18d27">It is very cool, Bateman. But that's nothing.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s18m28">He pulls a card out of his wallet and slaps it on the table.</meta>
      <char name="VAN PATTEN">
         <dialogue id="s18d28">Look at this.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s18m29">They all lean forward to inspect it.</meta>
      <char name="PRICE">
         <dialogue id="s18d29">That's really nice.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s18m30">Bateman clenches his fists beneath the table, trying to control his anxiety.</meta>
      <char name="VAN PATTEN">
         <dialogue id="s18d30">Eggshell with Romalian type. (Turning to Bateman) What do you think?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s18d31">(Barely able to breath, his voice a croak) Nice.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="PRICE">
         <dialogue id="s18d32">(Holding the card up to the light) Jesus. This is really super. How'd a nitwit like you get so tasteful?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s18m33">Bateman stares at his own card and then enviously at McDermott's.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN (V.O.)">
         <dialogue id="s18d33">I can't believe that Price prefers McDermott's card to mine.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="PRICE">
         <dialogue id="s18d34">But wait. You ain't seen nothin' yet.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s18m35">He holds up his own card.</meta>
      <char name="PRICE">
         <dialogue id="s18d35">Raised lettering, pale nimbus white...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s18d36">(Choking with anxiety) Impressive. Very nice. Let's see Paul Owen's card.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s18m37">Price pulls a card from an inside coat pocket and holds it up for their inspection: &quot;PAUL OWEN, PIERCE &amp; PIERCE, MERGERS AND ACQUISITIONS.&quot; Bateman swallows, speechless. The sound in the room dies down and all we hear is a faint heartbeat as Bateman stares at the magnificent card.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN (V.O.)">
         <dialogue id="s18d37">Look at that subtle off-white coloring. The tasteful thickness of it. Oh my God, it even has a watermark...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s18m38">His hand shaking, Bateman lifts up the card and stares at it until it fills the screen. He lets it fall. The SOUND RETURNS TO NORMAL. CARRUTHERS Is something wrong? Patrick...you're sweating.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s19">
      <sceneheader>EXT. STREET- EVENING</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s19m1">The financial district. The streets are eerily deserted. Bateman stands at an ATM, enjoying the reassuring sound of $500 in fresh bills thudding from the machine. As he turns to leave, he notices someone across the street. A HOMELESS MAN is lying in a doorway on top of an open grate, surrounded by bags of garbage and a shopping cart. A cardboard sign is attached to the front of the cart: I AM HOMELESS AND HUNGRY PLEASE HELP ME. A small, thin dog lies next to him. He is black, dressed in a stained, torn, lime-green polyester pants suit with jeans worn over the pants.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s19d1">(Offering his hand) Hello. Pat Bateman.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s19m2">The Homeless Man stares at Bateman, struggling to sit up.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s19d2">You want some money?. Some...food?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s19m3">The Homeless Man nods and starts to cry. Bateman reaches into his pocket and pulls out a $I 0 bill, then changes his mind and holds out a $5 instead.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s19d3">Is this what you need?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s19m4">The Homeless Man nods, looks away, wipes his nose.</meta>
      <char name="HOMELESS MAN">
         <dialogue id="s19d4">I'm so hungry.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s19d5">It's cold out, too, isn't it?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="HOMELESS MAN">
         <dialogue id="s19d6">I'm so hungry.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s19d7">(Holding the bill just out of the man's reach) Why don't you get a job? If you're so hungry, why don't you get a job?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="HOMELESS MAN">
         <dialogue id="s19d8">(Shivering and sobbing) I lost my job...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s19d9">Why? Were you drinking? Is that why you lost it? Insider trading? Just joking. No, really-were you drinking on the job?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s19m10">HOMELESS MAN I was fired. I was laid off.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s19d10">Gee, uh, that's too bad.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="HOMELESS MAN">
         <dialogue id="s19d11">I'm so hungry.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s19m12">The dog starts to whimper.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s19d12">Why don't you get another one? Why don't , you get another job?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="HOMELESS MAN">
         <dialogue id="s19d13">I'm not...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s19d14">You're not what? Qualified for anything else?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="HOMELESS MAN">
         <dialogue id="s19d15">I'm hungry</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s19d16">I know that, I know that. Jeez, you're like a broken record. I'm trying to help you.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="HOMELESS MAN">
         <dialogue id="s19d17">I'm hungry.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s19d18">Listen, do you think it's fair to take money from people who do have jobs? From people who do work?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="HOMELESS MAN">
         <dialogue id="s19d19">What am I gonna do?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s19d20">Listen, what's your name?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="HOMELESS MAN">
         <dialogue id="s19d21">Al.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s19d22">Speak up. Come on.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="HOMELESS MAN">
         <dialogue id="s19d23">Al.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s19d24">Get a goddamn job, Al. You've got a negative attitude. That's what's stopping you. You've got to get your act together. I'll help you.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="HOMELESS MAN">
         <dialogue id="s19d25">You re so kind, mister. You're kind. You're a kind man. I can tell.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s19d26">(Petting the dog) Shhhh...it's okay.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="HOMELESS MAN">
         <dialogue id="s19d27">(Grabbing Bateman's wrist) Please...I don know what to do. I'm so cold.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s19d28">(Stroking his face, whispering) Do ,you know how bad you smell? The stench, my God.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="HOMELESS MAN">
         <dialogue id="s19d29">I can't...I can't find a shelter</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s19d30">You reek. You reek of...shit. Do you know that? (Shouting) Goddammit, Al-look at me and stop crying like some kind of faggot. Al...I'm sorry.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s19m31">Bateman carefully puts the money back in his wallet.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s19d31">It's just that...I don't know I don't have anything in common with you.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s19m32">He opens his briefcase and pulls out a long thin knife with a serrated edge. He pushes up the sleeve of his jacket to protect it.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s19d32">Do you know what a fucking loser ,you are?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s19m33">HOMELESS MAN'S POV as Bateman lunges at him with the knife. EXTREME WIDE SHOT of the street. Bateman's shadowed figure is hunched over the Homeless Man, stabbing him in the stomach. The dog barks wildly and Bateman stomps on it until it is silent. LOW ANGLE shot of Bateman as he throws a quarter on the ground.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s19d33">There's a quarter. Go buy some gum.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s19m34">Bateman walks calmly into the empty caverns of Wall Street. Cars drift past, their headlights momentarily illuminating the body left twitching on the ground.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s20">
      <sceneheader>INT. BEAUTY SALON - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s20m1">CLOSE-UP on Bateman's face and torso. His eyes are closed as a woman's hands rub cream into his face.</meta>
      <char name="FACIALIST">
         <dialogue id="s20d1">What beautiful skin you have, Mr Bateman. So fine, so smooth...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s20m2">His eyes open to look up at the facialist and then he closes them again.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN (V.O.)">
         <dialogue id="s20d2">I have all the characteristics of a human being- flesh, blood, skin, hair-but not a single clear, identifiable emotion except for greed ,und disgust. Something horrible is happening inside me and I don't know why.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s20m4">CUT TO: Bateman sitting in a chair, looking down at the MANICURIST who is giving him a pedicure. She is cutting his nails with tiny sharp scissors. He stares at them longingly.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN (V.O.)">
         <dialogue id="s20d4">My nightly bloodlust has overflowed into my days. I feel lethal, on the verge of frenzy.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s20m6">CUT TO: Bateman lying irradiated by ultraviolet light on a tanning bed, wearing goggles.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN (V.O.)">
         <dialogue id="s20d6">I think my mask of sanity is about to slip.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s21">
      <sceneheader>INT. TEXARKANA RESTAURANT - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s21m1">An insanely expensive nouvelle Tex-Mex restaurant, with an ironic Southwestern decor: Santa Fe colors, Navajo blankets, naive cowboy art, rawhide banquettes. Bateman bursts in the door, late, and approaches the MAITRE D'.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s21d1">Marcus Halberstam. For two at eight?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="MAITRE D'">
         <dialogue id="s21d2">Your friend has already been seated. Follow me, Mr. Halberstam.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s21m3">Paul Owen is seated at a table underneath an enormous pair of ram's horns. He is arguing with the WAITER.</meta>
      <char name="OWEN">
         <dialogue id="s21d3">No, I want to know. I came here for the cilantro crawfish gumbo, which is after all the only excuse one could have for being in this restaurant, which is by the way, almost completely empty. Am I to believe that all ten people in this restaurant have eaten your entire supply of cilantro crawfish gumbo?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="WAITER">
         <dialogue id="s21d4">I'm very sorry sir. There was a fire in the kitchen earlier today, and-</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s21d5">J&amp;B;, straight. And a Dixie beer.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="WAITER">
         <dialogue id="s21d6">Would you like to hear-</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="OWEN">
         <dialogue id="s21d7">Double Absolut martini.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="WAITER">
         <dialogue id="s21d8">Yes, sir. Would you like to hear the specials?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s21d9">Not if you want to keep your spleen.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s21m10">The Waiter leaves.</meta>
      <char name="OWEN">
         <dialogue id="s21d10">This is a real beehive of, uh, activity, Halberstam.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s21m11">This place is hot, very hot.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s21d11">Listen, the mud soup and the charcoal arugula are outrageous here.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="OWEN">
         <dialogue id="s21d12">Yeah, well, you're late.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s21d13">Hey, I'm a child of divorce. Give me a break (Studying the menu; he's in a surprisingly good mood) Hmmm, I see they've omitted the pork loin with lime jello.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="OWEN">
         <dialogue id="s21d14">We should've gone to Dorsia. I could've gotten us a table.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s21d15">Nobody goes there anymore.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s21m16">There is a long disgruntled silence.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s21d16">Is that Ivana Trump over there? (Laughs) Jeez Patrick I mean Marcus, what are you thinking? Why would Ivana be at Texarkana?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s21m17">Another pause.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s21d17">So, wasn't Rothschild originally handling the Fisher account? How did you get it?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="OWEN">
         <dialogue id="s21d18">I could tell you that, Halberstam, but then I'd have to kill you.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s21m19">He guffaws. Bateman laughs politely.</meta>
      <char name="LATER:">
         <dialogue id="s21d19">Paul Owen is very drunk. BATEMAN cold sober.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s21d20">I like to dissect girls. Did you know I'm utterly insane?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s21m21">Owen continues laughing and motions to the waiter for another drink.</meta>
      <char name="OWEN">
         <dialogue id="s21d21">Great tan, Marcus. Really impressive. Where do you tan?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s21m22">BATEMAN Salon.</meta>
      <char name="OWEN">
         <dialogue id="s21d22">I've got a tanning bed at home. You should look into it.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s21m23">Bateman nods, agitated.</meta>
      <char name="OWEN">
         <dialogue id="s21d23">And Cecelia, how is she? Where is she tonight?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s21d24">Cecelia is, well...you know (Cecelia. I think she's having dinner with...Evelyn Williams.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="OWEN">
         <dialogue id="s21d25">Evelyn. Great ass. Goes out with that loser Patrick Bateman. What a dork.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s21d26">Another Martini, Paul?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s21m27">Owen nods drunkenly.</meta>
      <meta id="s21m28">LATER: The end of the meal. Owen is squeezing a lime onto the table, missing his beer, incredibly drunk. The check is laid down.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s21d28">(Talking to Owen like a child) Paul, give me your Amex card. Good boy. Bateman slaps the card down, looks at the check.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s21d29">Two-hundred-and-fifty. Very reasonable. Let's leave a big tip, shall we? My place hr a nightcap?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="OWEN">
         <dialogue id="s21d30">No, man. I'm gonna bail.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s21d31">Come on, you dumb son of a bitch. (Helping him into his jacket) I've got a preview of the Barneys catalogue and a bottle of Absolut waiting for us.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s22">
      <sceneheader>INT. BATEMAN'S APARTMENT - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s22m1">newspaper. Owen is slumped drunkenly in a white Eames chair, a glass in his hand. Bateman is looking through his CDs.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s22d1">You like Huey Lewis and the News?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="OWEN">
         <dialogue id="s22d2">They're okay.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s22d3">Their early work was a little too New Wave for my taste. But then Sports came out in 1983, I think they really came into their own, commercially and artistically.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s22m4">Bateman walks to his bathroom, taking a large ax out of the shower. He takes two Valium.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s22d4">(Said partly from the bathroom) The whole album has a clear, crisp sound and a new sheen of consummate professionalism that gives the songs a big boost. Bateman comes back out and leans the ax against the wall. He walks to the foyer and puts on a raincoat, watching Owen from behind ail the time.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s22d5">He's been compared to ELvis Costello but I think Huey has a more bitter, cynical sense of humor.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s22m6">Owen is absent-mindedly leafing through the Barneys catalogue.</meta>
      <char name="OWEN">
         <dialogue id="s22d6">Hey, Halberstam?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s22d7">Yes, Owen?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="OWEN">
         <dialogue id="s22d8">Why are there copies of the Style section all over the place? Do you have a dog? A chow or something?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s22d9">No, Owen.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="OWEN">
         <dialogue id="s22d10">(Confused) Is that a raincoat?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s22d11">Yes, it is.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s22m12">Bateman moves to the CD player. He takes a CD out of its case and slides it in the machine.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s22d12">In 1987 Huey released this, Fore!, their most accomplished album. I think I heir undisputed masterpiece is &quot;HiP To Be Square,&quot; a song so catchy that most people probably don't listen to the lyrics. But they should because it's not just about the pleasures of conformity and the importance of trends. It's al~ a personal statement about the band itself.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s22m13">Bateman puts on &quot;Hip To Be Square.&quot; BATEMAN crosses the room and picks up the ax. We follow BATEMAN from behind as he walks up to Owen, the ax raised over his head.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s22d13">Hey, Paul?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s22m14">As Owen turns around, FROM OWEN'S POV we see Bateman swing the ax toward his face. Blood sprays onto the white raincoat. FROM BEHIND OWEN, we see BATEMAN as he yanks the ax out. Owen drops to the floor. His body falls out of the frame. We stay on his legs twitching mechanically. Blood pulses onto the newspaper-covered floor.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s22d14">(Raising the ax and screaming) Try getting a reservation at Dorsia now, you fucking stupid bastard!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s22m15">LOW ANGLE ON BATEMAN as he beats Owen with the back of the ax. OFFSCREEN, the sound of the ax hitting Owen.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s22d15">(Panting) Fucking bastard...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s22m16">Bateman takes his raincoat off, still panting. He folds the coat carefully in half, bloody side in, and drapes it neatly over the back of a chair. He sits back on the white sofa and surveys the scene. He checks his Rolex and lights a cigar. OFFSCREEN, Paul Owen's last faint sighs are heard.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s23">
      <sceneheader>INT. LOBBY - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s23m1">BATEMAN drags a large, blood-soaked sleeping bag through the lobby, past the bored doorman, who looks up from the Post for a moment.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s24">
      <sceneheader>EXT. STREET - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s24m1">BATEMAN is trying to hail a cab. Owen's body is at his feet. Luis Carruthers and a Japanese girl walk up to him.</meta>
      <char name="CARRUTHERS">
         <dialogue id="s24d1">Patrick? Is that you?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s24d2">No, Luis. It's not me. You're mistaken.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="CARRUTHERS">
         <dialogue id="s24d3">This is Gwendolyn Ichiban. This is my very good friend Patrick Bateman. Where are you going? We're going to Nell's. Gwendolyn's father's buying it. (Looking down at the body) Where did you get your overnight bag?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s24d4">Commes des Garcon.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s24m5">A cab stops. BATEMAN opens the door and manages to get Owen's body into the backseat. Bateman gets into the cab.</meta>
      <char name="CARRUTHERS">
         <dialogue id="s24d5">Call me please, Patrick.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s24d6">Jesus lives, Luis.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s25">
      <sceneheader>INT. BATEMAN'S HELL'S KITCHEN APARTMENT - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s25m1">A bare room, lit by one light bulb. The walls are blank except for a Les Miserables poster. There is one ratty chair. Bateman pours lime over Paul Owen's body, which is lying in a bathtub. He plays Huey Lewis, smokes a cigar, watches the body dissolve.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s26">
      <sceneheader>INT. PAUL OWEN'S APARTMENT - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s26m1">Bateman is letting himself into the apartment. It is very similar to Bateman's, but even more minimalist. The walls are white-pigmented concrete with a large minimalist painting on the wall. One wall is covered in a trendy, large-scale scientific drawing above a long, black leather couch.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s26d1">Where to send the bastard? Dallas? Pans?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s26m2">He throws some clothes into a suitcase, randomly grabbing toiletries and shoving them in.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s26d2">Singapore? London. I'll send the asshole to London.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s26m3">He puts some music on to help muffle his voice, then leans over the answering machine. He does a passable imitation of Owen's speech.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s26d3">Hi, this is Paul. I've been called away to London for a few days. Meredith, I'll call you when I get back. Hasta la vista, baby.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s27">
      <sceneheader>INT. BATEMAN'S OFFICE - MORNING</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s27m1">Bateman is sitting at his desk, with the latest copy of Sports Illustrated in front of him and his Walkman playing Kenny G. We hear the MUSIC until Jean enters and he takes the Walkman off.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d1">(Faintly irritable) What is it?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JEAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d2">Patrick?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d3">(Condescendingly) Ye-es, Je-an?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JEAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d4">Patrick, a Mr. Donald KIMBALL is here to see you.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d5">Who?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JEAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d6">Detective Donald KIMBALL?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s27m7">Silence. Bateman stares out the window, then down at the drawing of a headless woman he's been doodling on the back cover of Sports Illustrated.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d7">Tell him I'm at lunch.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JEAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d8">(whispering) Patrick, I think he knows you're here. It's only ten-thirty.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s27m9">Silence.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d9">Send him in, I guess. As she exits, he picks up the cordless phone and pretends to talk to someone at the other end.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d10">Now, John, you've got to wear clothes in proportion to your physique. There are definite do's and don'ts, good buddy, of wearing a bold-striped shirt. A hold-striped shirt calls for solid-colored or discreetly patterned suits and ties...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s27m11">The door to the office opens and he waves in DETECTIVE DONALD KIMBALL. KIMBALL is surprisingly young - about Bateman's age - and good-looking, dressed in a crumpled linen Armani suit of the type Bateman and his friends might wear. Kimball sits down and crosses his legs with a self-assurance that makes Bateman so nervous he forgets to carry on with his fake conversation. Kimball looks up at him curiously, noticing the silence.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d11">(Realizing that Kimball is staring at him) Right. And yes...always tip the stylist fifteen percent.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s27m12">Bateman shrugs at the detective, rolling his eyes in exasperation. KIMBALL nods understandingly.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d12">Listen, John, I've got to go. T Boone Pickens just walked in... (He laughs inanely) Just joking... (Pause) No don't tip the owner of the salon. Okay, John, right, got it. (He hangs up the phone and pushes the antenna in) Sorry about that.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d13">No, I'm sorry. I should've made an appointment. (Gesturing toward the phone) Was that anything important?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d14">Oh that? Just mulling over business problems. Examining opportunities...Exchanging rumors... Spreading gossip.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s27m15">They laugh politely.</meta>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d15">(Holding out his hand) Hi. I'm Donald KIMBALL</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d16">(Shaking firmly) Hi. Pat Bateman. Nice to meet you.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d17">I'm sorry to barge in on you like this. but I was supposed to talk to Luis Carruthers and he wasn't in and...well, you're here, so...I know how busy you guys can get.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s27m18">KIMBALL stares at the three open copies of Sports Illustrated and the Sony Walkman lying on Bateman's desk. Bateman sees the look and sweeps the magazines into the top drawer along with the Walkman, which is still running.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d18">(Forcing himself to sound friendly and relaxed) So, what's the topic of discussion?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d19">I've been hired by Meredith Powell to investigate the disappearance of Paul Owen.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d20">You're not with the FBI or anything, are you?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d21">Nothing like that. I'm just a private investigator.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d22">Ah, I see...Yes. Paul's disappearance...Yes.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d23">So it's nothing that official. I just have some basic questions. About Paul Owen. About yourself-</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d24">Coffee?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d25">No. I'm okay.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d26">Perrier? San Pellegrino?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d27">No, I'm okay.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s27m28">KIMBALL takes out a small black notepad and the same gold Cross pen that Bateman and his friends all use. Bateman buzzes Jean.</meta>
      <char name="JEAN (O.S.)">
         <dialogue id="s27d28">Patrick?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d29">Can you bring Mr...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d30">KIMBALL.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d31">Mr. Kimball a bottle of San Pelle-</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d32">Oh no, I'm okay.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d33">It's no problem</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s27m34">Bateman watches intently as KIMBALL writes something down in his notebook, then crosses something out. Jean enters and places the bottle of San Pellegrino and a Steuben etched glass on the table, shooting a concerned glance at Bateman. He glares at her. KIMBALL smiles and nods at Jean as she leaves.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d34">Well, what's the topic of discussion?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d35">The disappearance of Paul Owen.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d36">Oh right. Well, I haven't heard anything about the disappearance or anything... (Trying to laugh) Not on &quot;Page Six&quot; at least.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d37">I think his family wants this kept quiet.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d38">Understandable. (Staring at the untouched bottle of San Pellegrino) Lime?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d39">No, really. I'm okay.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d40">You sure? I can always get you a lime.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s27m41">A pause.</meta>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d41">Just some preliminary questions that I need for my own files, okay?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d42">Shoot.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d43">How old are you?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d44">Twenty-six. I'll be twenty-seven in October.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d45">(Scribbling in his notebook) Where did you go to school?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d46">Harvard. The Harvard Business School.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d47">Your address?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d48">Fifty-five West Eighty-First Street. The American Gardens Building.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d49">(Looking up, impressed) Nice. Very nice.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d50">(Flattered) Thanks.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s27m51">A pause as KIMBALL studies his notebook. Bateman closes his eyes, as if in pain.</meta>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d51">Pardon me, but are you okay?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d52">Who do you ask?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d53">You seem...nervous.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s27m54">Bateman reaches into his desk drawer and brings out a bottle of aspirin.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d54">Nuprin?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s27m55">KIMBALL Uh...no, thanks. Kimball takes out a pack of Marlboro's and lays it on the desk.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d55">Bad habit.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d56">I know. I'm sorry.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s27m57">A pause, as Bateman stares at the cigarettes.</meta>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d57">Would you rather I not smoke?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d58">No, I guess it's okay.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d59">You sure?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d60">No problem. (Buzzing Jean)</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JEAN (O.S.)">
         <dialogue id="s27d61">Yes, Patrick?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d62">Bring us an ashtray for Mr. KIMBALL, please. She whisks in with a crystal ashtray as they sit in silence.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d63">What can you tell me about Paul Owen?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d64">Well...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s27m65">He coughs, shakes two Nuprin into his hand and swallows them dry.</meta>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d65">How well did you know him?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d66">I'm...at a loss. He was part of that whole...Yale thing, you know.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d67">Yale thing?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s27m68">A pause.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d68">Yeah...Yale thing.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d69">What do you mean...Yale thing?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s27m70">A pause.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d70">Well, I think for one that he was probably a closet homosexual. Who did a lot of cocaine...that Yale thing.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s27m71">A silence during which the sound of the air conditioner becomes deafening.</meta>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d71">So...there's nothing you can tell me about Paul Owen?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d72">He led what I suppose was an orderly life. He... ate a balanced diet.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d73">What kind of man was he? Besides... (He hesitates tries to smile) the information you've just given.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d74">I hope I'm not being cross-examined here.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d75">Do you feel that way?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d76">No. Not really.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d77">(As he writes without looking up) Where did Paul hang out?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d78">Hang...out?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d79">Yeah. You know...hang out.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d80">Let me think. The Newport. Harry's. Fluties. Endochine. Nell's. Comell Club. The New York Yacht Club. The regular places.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d81">He had a yacht?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d82">No, he just hung out there.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d83">And where did he go to school?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s27m84">A slight pause.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d84">Don't you know this?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d85">I just wanted to know if you know.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d86">Before Yale? If I remember correctly, Saint Paul's... Listen, I just...I just want to help.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d87">I understand.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s27m88">He makes another note.</meta>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d88">Anything else you can tell me about Owen?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d89">We were both seven in 1969.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d90">(Smiles) So was I.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d91">Do you have any witnesses or fingerprints?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d92">Well, there's a message on his answering machine saying he went to London.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d93">Well, maybe he did, huh?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d94">His girlfriend doesn't think so.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d95">But...has anyone seen him in London?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d96">Actually, yes.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d97">Hmmm.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d98">Well, I've had a hard time getting an actual verification. A Stephen Hughes says he saw him at a restaurant there, but I checked it out and what happened is, he mistook a Hubert Ainsworth for Paul, so...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d99">Oh.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d100">Was he involved at all , do you think, in occultism or Satan worship?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d101">What?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d102">I know it sounds like a lame question, but in New Jersey I know this sounds like a lame question, but last month-I don't know if you've heard about this, but a young stockbroker was recently arrested and charged with murdering a young Chicano girl and performing voodoo rituals with various body parts-</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d103">Yikes! No. Paul wasn't into that. He followed a balanced diet and-</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d104">Yeah, I know, and was into that whole Yale thing.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s27m105">A pause - the longest so far.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d105">Have you consulted a psychic?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d106">No.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d107">Had his apartment been burglarized?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d108">No, it actually hadn't. Toiletries were missing. A suit was gone. So was some luggage. That's it.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d109">I mean no one's dealing with the homicide squad yet or anything, right?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d110">No, not yet. As I said, we're not sure. But... basically no one has seen or heard anything.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d111">That's so typical, isn't it?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d112">It's just strange. (He stares out the window, lost in thought) One day someone's walking around, going to work, alive, and then...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d113">Nothing.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d114">People just...disappear.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d115">The earth just opens up and swallows people. (He checks his Rolex)</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d116">Eerie. Really eerie.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s27m117">Silence.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d117">(Standing up) You'll have to excuse me. I have a lunch meeting with Cliff Huxtable at Four Seasons in twenty minutes.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d118">Isn't the Four Seasons a little far uptown? I mean aren't you going to be late?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d119">Uh, no. There's one...down here.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d120">Oh really? I didn't know that.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s27m121">Bateman leads him to the door.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d121">Yes. It's very good.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s27m122">KIMBALL turns to face him.</meta>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d122">Listen, if anything occurs to you, any information at all...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s27d123">Absolutely, I'm 100% with you.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s27d124">Great, and thanks for your, uh, time, Mr. Bateman.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s27m125">Bateman closes the door firmly on KIMBALL. He closes his eyes and leans against the door, sweating.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s28">
      <sceneheader>INT. BATEMAN'S APARTMENT - AFTERNOON</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s28m1">A perfectly lit kitchen still-life - a bottle of Evian, a white porcelain plate on which sits a sliced kiwi, some perfect green grapes, a few berries. OFFSCREEN, the SOUND OF SCREAMS AND A CHAINSAW can be heard from the living room. The living room: Bateman is maniacally doing abdominal crunches as the television plays a video of Texas Chainsaw Massacre. There is a pile of horror videos on his coffee table, next to a copy of GQ.</meta>
      <meta id="s28m2">LATER: Bateman is sitting in his armchair, phone book in hand, jerking off. He is squealing into the phone and breathing.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s28d2">You like that, slut?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s28m3">The person on the other end clearly hangs up. CLOSE-UP on his fingers dialing the phone.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s28d3">You want to know what I'm wearing? Sixty-dollar boxer shorts by Ralph Lauren, a hundred-and-fifty-dollar white cotton T-shirt by Commes des Garcons. (He snorts like a pig) My Rolex cost-</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s28m4">Another hang-up. He dials again.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s28d4">(Whipering) I'm a corporate raider. I orchestrate hostile takeovers. What do you think of that? (Makes disgusting sucking noises and grunts) Huh, bitch?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="GIRL (O.S.)">
         <dialogue id="s28d5">Dad, is that you?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s28m6">Bateman hangs up, frustrated.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s29">
      <sceneheader>EXT. STREET/INT. LIMOUSINE - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s29m1">Bateman cruises around in the limo. It pulls up alongside CHRISTIE, a pretty blonde hooker in shorts and leather jacket. Bateman opens his window to speak to her.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s29d1">I haven't seen you around here.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="CHRISTIE">
         <dialogue id="s29d2">You just haven't been looking.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s29d3">Would you like to see my apartment?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s29m4">Bateman flips on the light inside the limo. He's wearing a tuxedo.</meta>
      <char name="CHRISTIE">
         <dialogue id="s29d4">(looking away to some dark corner) I'm not supposed to.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s29m5">Bateman is holding out a $100 bill, which Christie now notices, then takes.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s29d5">Do you want to come to my apartment or not?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="CHRISTIE">
         <dialogue id="s29d6">I'm not supposed to. (She pockets the bill) But I can make an exception.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s29d7">Do you take American Express?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s29m8">Christie is still looking out behind her.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s29d8">Do you take American Express?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s29m9">Christie looks at him like he's crazy.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s29d9">I'm joking. Come on, get in.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s29m10">As they drive uptown, Bateman dials the cell-phone. He reads off a credit card number.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s29d10">I'd like a girl, early twenties, blonde, who does couples. Couples. Fifty-five West Eighty-First, the American Gardens Building. Apartment 7C. And I really can't stress blonde enough. Blonde.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s29m11">He hangs up. BATEMAN I'm Paul. My name is Paul 0wen, have you'got that? You are Christie. You are to respond only to Christie. Is that clear?</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s30">
      <sceneheader>INT. BATEMAN'S APARTMENT - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s30m1">Christie is in the bathtub, Bateman is pouring in white milky bath oil.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s30d1">That's a very fine Chardonnay you're drinking.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s30m2">Long pause, in which Christie is luxuriating in the tub and Bateman is casually touching her breast.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s30d2">I want you to clean your vagina.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s30m3">Christie reaches for a washcloth.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s30d3">No. From behind. Get on your knees.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s30m4">Christie shrugs.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s30d4">I want to watch. You have a very nice body.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s30m5">The doorman RINGS. Bateman answers.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s30d5">Thank you. Send her up. Christie, get out and dry off, choose a robe-not the Bijan and come and meet me and our guest in the living room for drinks.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s30m6">Bateman answers the door.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s30d6">You've arrived! How lovely, let me take your coat. I'm Paul. How good of you to come.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s30m7">The escort girl looks somewhat bewildered. Bateman takes her coat and inspects her body and face.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s30d7">Not quite blonde, are you? More dirty blonde. I'm going to call you Sabrina. I'm Paul Owen.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s30m8">Bateman escorts her into the living room and brings her a glass of wine. Christie enters, sitting next to Sabrina on the couch, and Bateman sits across from them. There is a long silence.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s30d8">So, don't you want to know what I do?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s30m9">The two girls look at each other with uncomfortable smiles. Christie shrugs.</meta>
      <char name="CHRISTIE">
         <dialogue id="s30d9">No.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="SABRINA">
         <dialogue id="s30d10">(Smiling) No, not really.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s30m11">Bateman is visibly irritated, recrosses his legs.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s30d11">Well, I work on Wall Street. At Pierce &amp; Pierce. (Long pause) Have you heard of it?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s30m12">Another long pause. They shake their heads. Christie stands up and goes over to the CD collection.</meta>
      <char name="CHRISTIE">
         <dialogue id="s30d12">You have a really nice place here...Paul. How much did you pay for it?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s30d13">Actually, that's none of your business, Christie, hut I can assure you it certainly wasn't cheap.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s30m14">Bateman leaves to refill his wine glass and Sabrina takes a pack of cigarettes out of her purse. Bateman returns, carrying a tray of chocolates.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s30d14">No, no smoking. Not in here.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s30m15">He walks over to Christie.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s30d15">Varda truffle?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s30m16">Christie stares at the plate and shakes her head. Sabrina takes one.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s30d16">I don't want you to get drunk, but that's a very fine Chardonnay you're not drinking.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s30m17">Bateman goes over to his CDs and scans his vast collection. He takes one out and examines it.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s30d17">Do you like Phil Collins? I've been a big Genesis fan ever since the release of their 1980 album, Duke. Before that I really didn't understand any of their work. It was too artsy, too intellectual. It was on Duke where Phil Collins' presence became more apparent. He puts aside the CD and takes out another one.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s30d18">I think &quot;Invisible Touch&quot; is the group's undisputed masterpiece.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s30m19">He puts on the song and gestures for them to follow him into the bedroom.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s30d19">It's an epic meditation on intangibility, at the same time it deepens and enriches the meaning of the preceding three albums. Christie, take off the robe.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s30m20">Bateman puts out a lace teddy. He motions to Christie to put it on.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s30d20">Listen to the brilliant ensemble playing of Banks, Collins and Rutherford. You can practically hear every nuance of every instrument. Sabrina, remove your dress.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s30m21">Bateman starts to undress.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s30d21">In terms of lyrical craftsmanship and sheer songwriting, this album hits a new peak of professionalism. Sabrina, why don't you dance a little?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s30m22">Sabrina dances awkwardly. Christie sits on the bed.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s30d22">Take the lyrics to &quot;Land of Confusion.&quot; In this song, Phil Collins addresses the problem of abusive political authority.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s30m23">Bateman knots a silk scarf around Christie's neck - rather menacingly - then helps her into some suede gloves.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s30d23">&quot;In Too Deep&quot; is the most moving pop song of the 1980s about monogamy and commitment. The song is extremely uplifting. Their lyrics are as positive and affirmative as anything I've heard in rock.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s30m24">He turns on the video camera.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s30d24">Christie, get down on your knees, so Sabrina can see your asshole.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s30m25">Bateman looks through the viewfinder.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s30d25">Phill Collins solo efforts seem to be more commercial and therefore more satisfying in a narrower way, especially songs like &quot;In the Air Tonight&quot; and &quot;Against All Odds.&quot; Sabrina, don't just stare at it. Eat it.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s30m26">He walks over to the sound system in his bedroom and slides in the CD.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s30d26">But I also think that Phill Collins works better within the confines of the group than as a solo artist-and I stress the word artist. This is &quot;Sussudio,&quot; a great, great song, a personal favorite.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s30m27">SEX MONTAGE CUT TO &quot;Sussudio.&quot; We see this in WIDE SHOT, or through the LENS OF THE VIDEO CAMERA.</meta>
      <meta id="s30m28">CUT TO: Bateman asleep in his bed with Christie and Sabrina on either side of him. Sabrina accidentally touches his wrist. Bateman's eyes open.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s30d28">Don't touch the Rolex.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s30m29">Bateman gets up from his bed and goes over to his armoire. He opens the drawer in which are a nail gun, a coat hanger, a rusty butter knife and a half-smoked cigar. He turns around to see Christie and Sabrina both starting to get up and get dressed. He takes the coat hanger.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s30d29">We're not through yet...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s30m31">CUT TO: Bateman ushering them out the door impatiently. They are both sobbing, badly bruised and bleeding. Bateman has a deep scratch on his hand and one on his shoulder. In the b.g. Phil Collins' &quot;In the Air Tonight&quot; is playing.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s31">
      <sceneheader>INT. YALE CLUB  DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s31m1">McDermott, Van Patten and Bateman are having drinks. Price walks by with a gorgeous girl and gives them the finger.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s31d1">What an asshole.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s31m2">McDERMOTT Why is Laurie Kennedy dating Price? He's a fucking drug addict. No self-control.</meta>
      <char name="VAN PATTEN">
         <dialogue id="s31d2">But Laurie Kennedy is a total hardbody. What do you think, Bateman?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s31d3">I know her. I knew her.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s31m4">McDERMOTT Why do you say it like that? Why does he say it like that?</meta>
      <char name="VAN PATTEN">
         <dialogue id="s31d4">Because he dated her.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s31d5">How did you guess?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="VAN PATTEN">
         <dialogue id="s31d6">Girls dig Bateman. He's CQ. You're total CQ, Bateman.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s31d7">Thanks, guy, but...she's got a lousy personality.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s31m8">McDERMOTT So what? It's all looks. Laurie Kennedy is a babe. Don't even pretend you were interested for any other reason.</meta>
      <char name="VAN PATTEN">
         <dialogue id="s31d8">If they have a good personality, then something is very wrong.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s31m9">McDERMOTT If they have a good personality and they are not great looking-who fucking cares?</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s31d9">Well, let's just say hypothetically, okay? What if they have a good personality? (He smiles giving up) I know, I know-</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="ALL IN UNISON">
         <dialogue id="s31d10">There are no girls with good personalities! (They laugh and high-five each other)</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="VAN PATTEN">
         <dialogue id="s31d11">A good personality consists of a chick with a little hardbody who will satisfy all sexual demands without being too slutty about things and who will essentially keep her dumb fucking mouth shut.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s31m12">McDERMOTT Listen, the only girls with good personalities who are smart or maybe funny or halfway intelligent or even talented-though God knows what the fuck that means-are ugly chicks.</meta>
      <char name="VAN PATTEN">
         <dialogue id="s31d12">Absolutely.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s31m13">McDERMOTT And this is because they have to make up for how fucking unattractive they are. Pause.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s31d13">Do you know what Ed Gein said about women?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="VAN PATTEN">
         <dialogue id="s31d14">Ed Gein? Maitre d' at Canal Bar?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s31d15">No, serial killer, Wisconsin in the fifties. He was an interesting guy.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s31m16">McDERMOTT So what did Ed say?</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s31d16">He said, &quot;When I see a pretty girl walking down the street I think two things. One part of me wants to take her out and talk to her and be real nice and sweet and treat her right.&quot;</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s31m17">Pauses, finishes his drink. McDERMOTT What does the other part of him think?</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s31d17">What her head would look like on a stick.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s31m18">McDermott and Van Patten look at each other and then back at Bateman. Bateman starts to laugh, and the other two uneasily join In. Luis Carruthers walks up to the table.</meta>
      <char name="CARRUTHERS">
         <dialogue id="s31d18">(Shyly) Hi, guys. I wanna get your opinion on something.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s31m19">McDermott rolls his eyes at the rest of the table. McDERMOTT If it's about the bow-tie you're wearing, you know how we feel about it. Luis laughs good-naturedly.</meta>
      <char name="CARRUTHERS">
         <dialogue id="s31d19">Yes, I do. No, it's my business card-I decided to get a new one too.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s31m20">He pulls out something incredibly tasteful. Everyone compliments Luis except Bateman. The SOUND DROPS and all we hear is the beating of his heart as he stares at the card enviously. Luis plucks it from his hand and walks away, pleased with himself.</meta>
      <char name="VAN PATTEN">
         <dialogue id="s31d20">Listen, what about dinner?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s31d21">(Suddenly angry) Is that all you ever have to contribute, Van Patten? &quot;What about fucking dinner?&quot;</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s31m22">McDERMOTT Ah, cheer up, Bateman. (Slaps him on the back, massages his neck) What's the matter? No shiatsu this morning?</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s31d22">(Watching Luis going into the men's room) Keep touching me like that and you'll draw back a stump.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s31m23">McDERMOTT Whoa, hold on there, little buddy.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s31d23">Excuse me.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s31m24">He gets up from the table. As Bateman walks away, Van Patten grabs a waiter.</meta>
      <char name="VAN PATTEN">
         <dialogue id="s31d24">Is this tap water? I don't drink tap water Bring me an Evian or something, okay?</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s32">
      <sceneheader>INT. MEN'S ROOM - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s32m1">Bateman pulls on his gloves as he enters the men's room. Carruthers is standing in a stall with his back to Bateman. The sound of his urinating is heard until Bateman approaches, then abruptly stops. Slowly, Bateman brings his hands up over the collar of Carruthers' cashmere jacket, circling his neck until both thumbs and index fingers meet. All we can hear is the sound of Bateman's heavy breathing. Slowly he starts to squeeze. Almost in slow motion, Carruthers turns around. Carruthers looks down at Bateman's wrists as if lost in thought. Then he lowers his head and kisses Bateman's wrist. He looks back at Bateman with a shy, love-struck expression, then reaches up and tenderly touches the side of his face.</meta>
      <char name="CARRUTHERS">
         <dialogue id="s32d1">God, Patrick. Why here?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s32m2">He strokes Bateman's hair.</meta>
      <char name="CARRUTHERS">
         <dialogue id="s32d2">I've seen you looking at me. I've noticed your hot body.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s32m3">Carruthers tries to kiss him on the lips but Bateman backs away. He drops his hands from Carruthers' neck. Carruthers immediately takes them and places them back. Bateman drops them again.</meta>
      <char name="CARRUTHERS">
         <dialogue id="s32d3">Don't be shy.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s32m4">Bateman takes a deep breath, closes his eyes and tries to lift his hands again, but abandons the attempt.</meta>
      <char name="CARRUTHERS">
         <dialogue id="s32d4">You don't know how long I've wanted it. Ever since that Christmas party at Arizona 206. You know the one, you were wearing that red-striped paisley Armani tie.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s32m5">Bateman looks down and sees that Carruthers' pants are still unzipped. He moves past him out of the stall and stands by the sink and pretends to wash his hands until he realizes he still has his gloves on. Carruthers comes up behind him.</meta>
      <char name="CARRUTHERS">
         <dialogue id="s32d5">I want you. I want you...too.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s32m6">Bateman storms out of the men's room, bumping into a waiter and several customers and cursing. Noticing the maitre d' and another waiter conferring and looking at him strangely, Bateman straightens up and smiles and waves cheerfully at them. Carruthers walks up behind him.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s32d6">(Hissing) What...is...it?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="CARRUTHERS">
         <dialogue id="s32d7">Where are you going?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s32d8">(Stumbling away from him) I've gotta...I've gotta...return some videotapes.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="CARRUTHERS">
         <dialogue id="s32d9">Patrick?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s32d10">What?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="CARRUTHERS">
         <dialogue id="s32d11">(Silently mouthing the words) I'll call you.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s32m12">Bateman storms out of the restaurant.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s33">
      <sceneheader>INT. COURTNEY'S APARTMENT - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s33m1">Bateman is lying on top of Courtney in her bed, after sex. Still panting, he rolls off her, onto his back. He feels something lumpy underneath him and pulls out a stuffed toy, a black cat with blue jewel eyes. There is silence.</meta>
      <char name="COURTNEY">
         <dialogue id="s33d1">Will you call me before Thanksgiving?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s33d2">Maybe.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s33m3">Courtney sighs and reaches for a bottle of pills on her nightstand, swallowing several. Bateman gets up and begins to dress, admiring himself in the mirror. Courtney watches the TV at low volume.</meta>
      <char name="COURTNEY">
         <dialogue id="s33d3">What are you doing tonight?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s33d4">Dinner at the River Cafe. Au Bar afterwards, maybe.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="COURTNEY">
         <dialogue id="s33d5">That's nice.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s33d6">You and...Luis?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="COURTNEY">
         <dialogue id="s33d7">(Lighting a cigarette) We were supposed to have dinner at Tad and Maura's, but-you know how Luis is...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s33d8">I never knew you smoked.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="COURTNEY">
         <dialogue id="s33d9">(Smiling sadly) You never noticed.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s33m10">Bateman is making final adjustments to his tie.</meta>
      <char name="COURTNEY">
         <dialogue id="s33d10">Listen...Patrick. Can we talk?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s33d11">You look marvelous. There's nothing to say. You're going to marry Luis. Next week, no Less.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="COURTNEY">
         <dialogue id="s33d12">(Sarcastically) Isn't that special? (A pause) Patrick?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s33d13">Yes, Courtney?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="C0URTNEY">
         <dialogue id="s33d14">If I don't see you before Thanksgiving, have a nice one, okay?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s33d15">(Flatly) You too.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s33m16">Courtney picks up the black cat and starts petting its head. Bateman heads down the hallway to the front door.</meta>
      <char name="COURTNEY">
         <dialogue id="s33d16">Patrick?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s33d17">Yes?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="COURTNEY">
         <dialogue id="s33d18">Nothing.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s34">
      <sceneheader>INT. NIGHTCLUB - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s34m1">A big eighties nightclub with a mixed crowd: hip-hop kids, visitors from Jersey, downtown art people, yuppies. I Bateman makes his way through the crowd to the bar, and tries to attract the bartender's attention. He is wearing a suit and his tie is loosened. Kimball approaches him.</meta>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s34d1">Mr. Bateman?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s34m2">Bateman gasps and recovers.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s34d2">Detective Kendall...uh Campbell?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s34d3">Kimball. (Extending his hand) Call me Don.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s34d4">Don.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s34d5">So...you hang out here a lot?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s34d6">Uh, yes...I mean...whenever necessary. You know.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s34m7">Pause.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s34d7">How's the investigation going? Taken anyone in for &quot;formal questioning?&quot; (He makes quotation marks in the air and laughs a not-so-relaxed laugh)</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s34d8">0h no. Informal conversations, mostly. What's that, Stoli?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s34d9">Yeah. No Finlandia, as usual. Fucking dump.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s34d10">(Looking at his glass) Too true. You know, Bateman-people tend to reveal so much more about themselves when they're in a relaxed setting, don't you think?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s34m11">Bateman is nodding nervously, idiotically.</meta>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s34d11">Some people just can t help themselves. Another Stoli?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s34m12">Bateman shakes his head.</meta>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s34d12">I mean they want to get caught.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s34d13">Dan, great to see you again. Like I said, you need anything at all, I'm your man. I don't envy your job. I mean Owen was a...complex man.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s34m14">Bateman wanders away. He looks back uneasily at KIMBALL, who is watching him from the bar. A GUY WITH DREADLOCKS walks by.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s34d14">(Holding up his hand to high-five) Rasta Man!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s34m15">The man stares at him.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s34d15">I mean-Mon. We be jammin'...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s34m16">The man walks by, shaking his head. Bateman wanders into the next room, which is filled with a more familiar crowd: young men in designer suits, girls in black designer dresses. Across the room he spots McDermott and Price sitting with three models, all wearing black mini-dresses. Price and McDermott are having a whispered argument.</meta>
      <char name="PRICE">
         <dialogue id="s34d16">I have to talk to these girls? They're models.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s34m17">McDERMOTT Someone has to get the Bolivian marching powder. You went last time. Stay here. McDermott waves gaily to the girls and disappears. Bateman looks at the models. DAISY and CARON are staring into space, smoking. LIBBY is trying to work out how to unfold her napkin. Price signals to Bateman for help.</meta>
      <char name="PRICE">
         <dialogue id="s34d17">(Clapping his hands together) Let's have a conversation. So...it was hot out today, no?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s34m18">Silence.</meta>
      <char name="LIBBY">
         <dialogue id="s34d18">Where did Craig go?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="PRICE">
         <dialogue id="s34d19">Well, Gorbachev is downstairs. McDermott is going to sign a peace treaty with him between the United States and Russia. McDermott's the one behind glasnost, you know.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="LIBBY">
         <dialogue id="s34d20">Well...yeah. But he told me he was in mergers and acquisitions.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="PRICE">
         <dialogue id="s34d21">You're not confused, are you?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="LIBBY">
         <dialogue id="s34d22">No, not really.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="CARON">
         <dialogue id="s34d23">Gorbachev's not downstairs.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="DAISY">
         <dialogue id="s34d24">(Smiling) Are you Iying?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="PRICE">
         <dialogue id="s34d25">Yes, Caron's right. Gorbachev's not downstairs. He's at Tunnel.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s34d26">(To Daisy) Ask me a question.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="DAISY">
         <dialogue id="s34d27">So, what do you do?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s34d28">What do you think I do?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="DAISY">
         <dialogue id="s34d29">A model? An actor?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s34d30">No. Flattering, but no.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="DAISY">
         <dialogue id="s34d31">Well...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s34d32">I m into, well, murders and executions mostly.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s34m33">DAISY (Unfazed) Do you like it?</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s34d33">Welt...it depends, why?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="DAISY">
         <dialogue id="s34d34">Well, most guys I know who work in mergers and acquisitions don't really like it.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s34m35">Silence.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s34d35">So, where do you work out?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s34m37">MUCH LATER IN THE EVENING: The club is half-empty now. Price is leaning over a balcony, messed-up on drugs. Bateman comes up behind him in a menacing way that suggests he might push him over the railing. Price turns around, wild-eyed, just as Bateman is reaching for him.</meta>
      <char name="PRICE">
         <dialogue id="s34d37">(Shouting) I'm leaving. I'm getting out.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s34d38">Leaving what?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="PRICE">
         <dialogue id="s34d39">This.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s34m40">Bateman is confused, he thinks Price is referring to his drink.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s34d40">Don't, I'll drink it.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="PRICE">
         <dialogue id="s34d41">(Screaming) Listen to me, Patrick. I'm leaving.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s34d42">Where to? Are you going to go get a gram?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="PRICE">
         <dialogue id="s34d43">I'm leaving! I...am...leaving!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s34d44">Don't tell me...merchant banking?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="PRICE">
         <dialogue id="s34d45">No, you dumb son of a bitch. I'm serious. I'm disappearing.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s34d46">(laughing) Where to? Morgan Stanley? Rehab? What?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s34m47">Price looks away. McDermott and Daisy walk up to them. McDERMOTT Hey-don't worry, be happy. Price lifts his arms up as if greeting the crowd and is shouting something that can't be heard, then</meta>
      <char name="PRICE">
         <dialogue id="s34d47">Goodbye! Fuckheads!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s34m48">He climbs over the railing. DAISY What is he doing?</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s34d48">Price! Come back!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s34m49">Price leaps from the balcony. He disappears for a moment then resurfaces and runs off into the crowd.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s35">
      <sceneheader>EXT. CLUB - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <char name="DAISY">
         <dialogue id="s35d1">My ex-boyfriend, Fiddler, who was in there, he plays in this band that just opened for U2-he couldn't understand what I was doing with a yuppie.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s35d2">Oh really?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="DAISY">
         <dialogue id="s35d3">He said... (She laughs) He said you gave him bad vibes.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s35d4">That's...that's too bad.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="DAISY">
         <dialogue id="s35d5">You think I'm dumb, don't you?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s35d6">What?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="DAISY">
         <dialogue id="s35d7">You think I'm dumb. You think all models are dumb.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s35d8">(insincerely) No. I really don't.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="DAISY">
         <dialogue id="s35d9">That's okay. I don't mind. There's something sweet about you.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s35m10">She takes his hand as they get into a cab.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s36">
      <sceneheader>INT. DAISY'S HALLWAY - LATER THAT NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s36m1">Bateman leaves Daisy's apartment carrying a suitcase. He pauses in the hallway and tucks some long blonde hair back inside the case.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s37">
      <sceneheader>INT. BATEMAN'S OFFICE - LATE AFTERNOON</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s37m1">Bateman sits at his desk wearing Wayfarers doing the New York Times crossword puzzle at dusk. Jean knocks gently on the half-open door and walks in with a folder in her hand. Bateman ignores her.</meta>
      <char name="JEAN">
         <dialogue id="s37d1">Doin' the crossword?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s37m2">Bateman nods without looking up.</meta>
      <char name="JEAN">
         <dialogue id="s37d2">Need help?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s37m3">BATEMAN doesn't respond. We see that every space on the puzzle has been filled in with the words MEAT or BONE. Jean drops the folder on his desk and then walks out.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s37d3">Jean?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JEAN">
         <dialogue id="s37d4">(Re-enters office) Yes, Patrick?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s37d5">Would you like to accompany me to dinner?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s37m6">He erases one of the M's on the crossword puzzle.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s37d6">That is...if you're not doing anything.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JEAN">
         <dialogue id="s37d7">Oh no. I have no plans.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s37d8">(Lowering his Wayfarers) Well, isn't this a coincidence.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s37m9">A pause.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s37d9">Listen, where should we go?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s37m10">He leans back and pulls a Zagat's from the desk drawer.</meta>
      <char name="JEAN">
         <dialogue id="s37d10">Anywhere you want?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s37d11">Let's not think about what I want. How about anywhere you want.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JEAN">
         <dialogue id="s37d12">Oh Patrick, I can't make this decision.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s37d13">No, come on. Anywhere you want.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JEAN">
         <dialogue id="s37d14">Oh, I can't. (Sighs) I don't know.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s37d15">Come on. Where do you want to go? Anywhere you want. Just say it. I can get us in anywhere.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s37m16">A long pause.</meta>
      <char name="JEAN">
         <dialogue id="s37d16">What about...Dorsia?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s37m17">Bateman stops looking through the Zagat's guide and smiles at her.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s37d17">Soooo...Dorsia is where Jean wants to go...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JEAN">
         <dialogue id="s37d18">Oh, I don't know. No, we'll go anywhere you want.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s37d19">Dorsia is...fine.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s37m20">He dials the number.</meta>
      <char name="MAITRE D'">
         <dialogue id="s37d20">Dorsia, yes?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s37d21">Yes, can you take two tonight, oh, let's say at nine o'clock?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s37m22">He checks his Rolex and winks at Jean.</meta>
      <char name="MAITRE D'">
         <dialogue id="s37d22">We are totally booked.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s37d23">Oh really? That's great.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="MAITRE D'">
         <dialogue id="s37d24">I said we are totally booked.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s37d25">Two at nine? Perfect.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="MAITRE D'">
         <dialogue id="s37d26">There are no tables available tonight. The waiting list is also totally booked.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s37d27">See you then.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s37m28">He hangs up the phone. He walks over to the coat rack. He glances over at Jean, who is still standing in front of the desk, confused.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s37d28">Yes? You're dressed...okay.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JEAN">
         <dialogue id="s37d29">You didn't give them a name.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s37d30">They know me.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s37m31">Pause.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s37d31">Why don't you meet me at my house at seven o'clock for drinks, okay?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s37m32">She turns to leave.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s37d32">And Jean? You'll want to change before we go out.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s38">
      <sceneheader>INT. BATEMAN'S APARTMENT - EARLY EVENING</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s38m1">Jean stands by the floor-to-ceiling windows, looking out.</meta>
      <char name="JEAN">
         <dialogue id="s38d1">Patrick, it's so...elegant. What a wonderful view.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s38m2">Bateman opens up the freezer where Daisy's head is cleady visible.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s38d2">Jean? Sorbet?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JEAN">
         <dialogue id="s38d3">Thanks, Patrick. I'd love some.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s38m4">Bateman walks in with a bottle of wine and a corkscrew in his hand and hands her the sorbet. Jean is eating the sorbet.</meta>
      <char name="JEAN">
         <dialogue id="s38d4">Want a bite?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s38d5">I'm on a diet. But thank you.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JEAN">
         <dialogue id="s38d6">You don't need to lose any weight. You're kidding, right? You look great. Very fit.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s38d7">(Weighing the corkscrew examining the point for sharpness) You can always he thinner. Look...better.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JEAN">
         <dialogue id="s38d8">Well, maybe we shouldn't go out to dinner. I don't want to ruin your willpower.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s38d9">No. It's all right. I'm not very good at controlling it anyway.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s38m10">Silence, as Bateman walks around his apartment, opens up his knife drawer, looking at the knives.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s38d10">So listen, what do you really want to do with your life?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s38m11">Pause.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s38d11">And don't tell me you enjoy working with children, okay?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JEAN">
         <dialogue id="s38d12">Well, I'd like to travel. And maybe go back to school, but I really don't know...I'm at a point in my life where there seems lo be a lot of possibilities, but I'm so... I don't know...unsure.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s38m13">Bateman is touching a knife in the drawer, feeling the edge of the blade.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s38d13">Do you have a boyfriend?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JEAN">
         <dialogue id="s38d14">No, not really.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s38d15">Interesting.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JEAN">
         <dialogue id="s38d16">(Shyly) Are you seeing anyone? I mean, seriously?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s38d17">Maybe. I don't know Not really. Bateman opens up a cupboard where there are a lot of very Bateman opens a cupboard where there are a lot of neatly ordered weapons - an ax, a rifle, a chain saw, duct tape, twine and a nail gun.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s38d18">Jean, do you feel...fulfilled? I mean, in your life?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JEAN">
         <dialogue id="s38d19">Well, I guess I do. For a long time I was too focused on my work, I think, but now I've really begun to think about changing myself, you know, developing, and...growing.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s38d20">Growing. I'm glad you said that.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s38m21">Bateman picks up the duct tape.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s38d21">Did you know that Ted Bundy's first dog, a collie, was named Lassie? Had you heard this?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JEAN">
         <dialogue id="s38d22">Who's Ted Bundy?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s38d23">Forget it.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JEAN">
         <dialogue id="s38d24">What's that?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s38d25">Oh. Uh, tape. Duct tape. I...need it for... taping something. Bateman goes back to the cupboard for the nail gun.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JEAN">
         <dialogue id="s38d26">Patrick, have you ever wanted to make someone happy?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s38m27">Jean puts her spoon down on the table.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s38d27">(Looking up from loading nails into the gun) What...No! Put it in the carton.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JEAN">
         <dialogue id="s38d28">Sorry. (She puts the spoon in the carton)</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s38d29">Jean? What?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JEAN">
         <dialogue id="s38d30">Make someone happy-have you ever wanted to?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s38m31">From behind, we follow Bateman as he walks across the room and stands behind the couch.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s38d31">I'm looking for...I guess you could say I just want to have a meaningful relationship with someone special.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JEAN">
         <dialogue id="s38d32">Hmmmm.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s38m33">He points the nail gun at the back of Jean's head. The phone RINGS. Startled, Bateman hides the nail gun behind his back. The answering machine picks up. As Bateman listens he discreetly places the nail gun behind the couch. He sits down opposite Jean, enjoying her discomfort as she listens to the message.</meta>
      <char name="EVELYN">
         <dialogue id="s38d33">Patrick I know you're there. Pick up the phone, you bad boy. What are you up to tonight? It's me. Don't try to hide. I hope you're not out with some little number you picked up because you're my Mr. Bateman. My boy next door. Anyway you never called me and you said you would and I'll leave a message for Jean about this too to remind you but we're having dinner with Melania and Taylor-you know Melania, she went to Sweet Briar, auld Taylor, he went to Cornell-and we're meeting at the Cornell Club, so l'll call you tomorrow morning probably-bye, honey-oopps! You hate that. Bye Mr. Big Time CEO Patrick. Bye. Bye.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s38m34">Silence. Jean is obviously embarrassed and upset.</meta>
      <char name="JEAN">
         <dialogue id="s38d34">Was that...Evelyn?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s38m35">Silence.</meta>
      <char name="JEAN">
         <dialogue id="s38d35">Are you still seeing her?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s38m36">Silence.</meta>
      <char name="JEAN">
         <dialogue id="s38d36">I'm sorry, I have no right to ask that.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s38m37">Silence.</meta>
      <char name="JEAN">
         <dialogue id="s38d37">Do you want me to go?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s38m38">A long pause.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s38d38">Yes. I don t think I can...control myself.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JEAN">
         <dialogue id="s38d39">I know I should go. I know I have a tendency to get involved with unavailable men, and...I mean, do you want me to go?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s38m40">Another long pause.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s38d40">If you stay, I think something bad will happen. I think I might hurt you. (Almost hopefully) You don't want to get hurt, do you?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JEAN">
         <dialogue id="s38d41">No. No, I guess not. I don't want to get bruised. You're right, I should go.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s38m42">She gets up to leave.</meta>
      <char name="JEAN">
         <dialogue id="s38d42">And don't forget you have a breakfast meeting with Frederick Bennet and Charles Rust at '21.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s38d43">Thanks. It slipped my mind completely.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s38m44">He sinks back on the sofa and shuts his eyes.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s39">
      <sceneheader>INT. BATEMAN'S OFFICE - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s39m1">Bateman enters P&amp;P;, walks up the corridor and pauses outside the door to his office. He sees KIMBALL in conversation with Jean, and Jean looking through her date book. He watches for a moment, frozen with anxiety. He then bursts in, shutting the door behind him.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s39d1">Kimball-I've been wanting to talk with you, Come into my office. Jean, great jacket. Matsuda?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s39m2">Jean looks flustered. Kimball follows Bateman into his office.</meta>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s39d2">I actually came to see Timothy Price, but he's taken a leave of absence.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s39d3">Yeah, gone into rehab. Shame. (Hopefully) Is he a suspect?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s39d4">Not really.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s39m5">A pause.</meta>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s39d5">Do you remember where you were on the night of Paul's disappearance? (He checks his notebook) Which was on the twentieth of December?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s39d6">God...I guess...I was probably returning videotapes.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s39m7">He opens his desk drawer and pretends to search through his diary.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s39d7">I had a date with a girl named Veronica.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s39d8">Wait. That's not what I've got.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s39d9">What?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s39d10">That's not the information I've received.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s39d11">Well...I...Wait...What information have you received?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s39d12">Let's see... (He flips through his notebook) That you were with-</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s39d13">Well, I could he wrong.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s39d14">Well...When was the last time you were with Paul Owen?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s39d15">(Clearly nervous and under pressure) We had...gone to a new musical called...Oh Africa, Brave Africa. It was...a laugh riot...and that's about it. I think we had dinner at Orso's. No, Petaluma. No, Orso's. The...last time I physically saw him was...at an automated teller. I can't remember which...just one that was near, um, Nell's.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s39m16">Kimball is clearly giving up on Bateman for now. He opens his briefcase to put away his notebook.</meta>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s39d16">Well, thank you, Mr. Bateman.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s39d17">Patrick, please. I hope I've been informative. Long day-a bit scattered.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s39d18">Listen, I'm a little spent for now but how about lunch in a week or so when I've sorted out all this information?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s39d19">Great, yes, I'd like that.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s39d20">And if you could try and pin down where you were the night of Owen's disappearance, it would make my job a lot easier.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s39d21">Absolutely. I'm with you on that one.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s39m22">Kimball is rifling through his briefcase. He pulls out a new shrink wrapped CD and holds it up.</meta>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s39d22">Huey Lewis and the News. Great stuff. Heard it? I just bought it on my way here.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s39m23">Bateman stares at the CD - stunned, terrified.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s39d23">Never. I mean...I don't really like... singers.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s39d24">Not a big music fan, eh?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s39d25">No, I like music. Just-they're-Huey's too... black sounding. For me.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s39d26">Well, to each his own. So-lunch, Thursday? I'll call your secretary about reservations.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s39d27">I'll be there.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s40">
      <sceneheader>EXT. MEAT PACKING DISTRICT/INT. LIMOUSINE - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s40m1">The same street corner where Bateman found Christie before. The limo is kept idling as he talks to her through a half-opened window.</meta>
      <char name="CHRISTIE">
         <dialogue id="s40d1">I'm not so sure about this. I had to go to Emergency after last time...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s40d2">Oh this won't be anything like last time, I promise.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="CHRISTIE">
         <dialogue id="s40d3">I don't think so.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s40m4">He hands her a $500 bill.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s40d4">Just come in the limo and talk to me for a minute.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s40m5">The driver's here, you'll be safe. Christie gets in hesitantly.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s40d5">Nothing like last time, promise.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="CHRISTIE">
         <dialogue id="s40d6">Alright.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s40m7">He pours her a shot of vodka and makes her drink it.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s40d7">(Chatting as if they were at a cocktail party) So, you're looking great, how have you been?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="CHRISTIE">
         <dialogue id="s40d8">(A little confused) Well, I actually might need a little surgery after last time.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s40d9">(Mock shock) Really?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="CHRISTIE">
         <dialogue id="s40d10">My friend told me I should maybe even get a lawyer.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s40d11">Oh, lawyers are so complicated-don't do that. Here.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s40m12">He writes her a check for $I ,000 to cash and hands it to her. She snatches the check out of his hand and gets quickly out of the limo, walking hurriedly down the street.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s40d12">Bitch.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s40m13">He follows alongside her slowly in the limo, waving a huge wad of cash at her. She hesitates; he uses the money to lure her into the car. As she reluctantly gets into the limo, she reaches for the money. He snatches it away.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s40d13">Uh uh uh. Half now, half later.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s40m14">She takes the money and puts it inside her shirt.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s40d14">Okay, your name is Christie. We're meeting a friend of mine, Elizabeth. She'll be joining us in my new apartment shortly. You'll like her. She's a very nice girl. Don't say anything about yourself. Is that clear. Christie?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s40m15">Christie nods.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s41">
      <sceneheader>INT. PAUL OWEN'S APARTMENT - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s41m1">The living room: ELIZABETH has kicked off her shoes and flopped down on the couch underneath the Baselitz. Elizabeth is an attractive, dark-haired society girl who models occasionally. Christie is sitting on the couch opposite her, pretending to examine a CD.</meta>
      <char name="ELIZABETH">
         <dialogue id="s41d1">You look really familiar. Did you you go to Dalton?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s41m2">Christie shakes her head. The kitchen: Bateman is grinding up tabs of Ecstasy and putting them in a bottle of wine. In the living room, Elizabeth is still staring at Christie as if she came from Mars.</meta>
      <char name="ELIZABETH">
         <dialogue id="s41d2">I think I met you at Au Bar, didn't I ? With Spicey?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s41m3">Christie looks blank.</meta>
      <char name="ELIZABETH">
         <dialogue id="s41d3">Well, maybe not with Spicey but it was definitely at Au Bar.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s41m4">Christie still blank.</meta>
      <char name="ELIZABETH">
         <dialogue id="s41d4">You know, Au Bar?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s41m5">Christie shakes her head.</meta>
      <char name="ELIZABETH">
         <dialogue id="s41d5">Anyway, Au Bar sucks now, it's terrible. I went to a birth day party there for Malcolm Forbes. Oh my God, please.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s41m6">Bateman enters carrying the bottle of wine and two glasses. Christie, who seems frightened, sips her wine and stares at the floor. There is an awkward silence.</meta>
      <char name="CHRISTIE">
         <dialogue id="s41d6">This is nicer than your other apartment.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s41d7">(Offended that she prefers Owen's apartment) It's not that nice.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s41m8">Silence.</meta>
      <char name="CHRISTIE">
         <dialogue id="s41d8">Where did you two meet?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="ELIZABETH">
         <dialogue id="s41d9">Oh God! I met him at, oh God, the Kentucky Derby in '86-no, '87, and... (Turning to Patrick) You were hanging out with that bimbo Allison Poole. (Sarcastically) Hot number.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s41d10">What do you mean, she was a hot number.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="ELIZABETH">
         <dialogue id="s41d11">If you had an American Express card she'd give you a blowjob. (To Christie) Listen, this girl worked in a tanning salon, need I say more?...What do you do?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s41m12">A long silence. Christie reddens and stares at the floor.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s41d12">She's my...cousin.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="ELIZABETH">
         <dialogue id="s41d13">(Skeptically) Uh huh?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s41d14">She's from...France.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s41m15">A pause. Elizabeth looks at Bateman dubiously.</meta>
      <char name="ELIZABETH">
         <dialogue id="s41d15">Where's your phone? I've got to call Harley.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s41m16">Bateman hands her a cordless phone. She dials, and stares At Christie while she waits for someone to answer.</meta>
      <char name="ELIZABETH">
         <dialogue id="s41d16">Where do you summer? Southampton?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s41m17">Christie looks at Bateman and then back at Elizabeth.</meta>
      <char name="CHRISTIE">
         <dialogue id="s41d17">No.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="ELIZABETH">
         <dialogue id="s41d18">(Listening to the receiver) Oh God, it's his machine.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s41d19">Elizabeth, it's three in the morning.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="ELIZABETH">
         <dialogue id="s41d20">He's a goddamn drug dealer! These are his peak hours.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s41d21">Don't tell him you're here.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="ELIZABETH">
         <dialogue id="s41d22">Why would I?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s41m23">Bateman has poured her another glass of wine. She downs the whole glass, making a face.</meta>
      <char name="ELIZABETH">
         <dialogue id="s41d23">This tastes weird. (She examines the label and shrugs) Harley? It's me. I need your services. Translate that anyway you'd like. I'm at-</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s41d24">(Whispering) You're at Paul Owen s.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="ELIZABETH">
         <dialogue id="s41d25">Who?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s41d26">(Whispering) Paul Owen.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="ELIZABETH">
         <dialogue id="s41d27">I want the number, idiot. (She waves him away and continues into the reciever) Anyway, I'm at Paul Norman's and I'll try you later and if I don't see you at Canal Bar tomorrow night I'm going to sic my hairdresser on you.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s41m28">She hangs up.</meta>
      <char name="ELIZABETH">
         <dialogue id="s41d28">Did you know that guy who disappeared? Didn't he work at Pierce &amp; Pierce, too? Was he a friend of yours?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s41d29">No.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="ELIZABETH">
         <dialogue id="s41d30">Do you have any coke? Or Halcyon? I'd take a Halcyon.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s41m31">Bateman sits next to Elizabeth on the couch and pours her another glass of the drugged wine.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s41d31">Listen, I would just like to see...the two of you...get it on. What's wrong with that? It's totally disease-free.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="ELIZABETH">
         <dialogue id="s41d32">(Laughing) Patrick, you re a lunatic.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s41d33">Come on. Don't you find Christie attractive?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="ELIZABETH">
         <dialogue id="s41d34">Let's not get lewd. (Flirty) I'm in no mood to have a lewd conversation.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s41d35">Come on. I think it would be a turn-on.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="ELIZABETH">
         <dialogue id="s41d36">(To Christie) Does he do this all the time?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s41m37">Christie shrugs.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s41d37">Christie, you're not drinking your wine.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s41m38">Christie looks at her wine and gingerly takes a sip.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s41d38">(To Elizabeth) Are you telling me you've never gotten it on with a girl?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="ELIZABETH">
         <dialogue id="s41d39">No! I'm not a lesbian. Why do you think I'd be into that?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s41d40">Well, you went to Sarah Lawrence for one thing.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="ELIZABETH">
         <dialogue id="s41d41">Those are Sarah Lawrence guys, Patrick. You're making me feel weird.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s41m43">LATER: Elizabeth is now writhing around on the couch and making out with Christie. Bateman holds up a Whitney Houston CD, showing them the picture of Whitney on the cover.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s41d43">Did you know that Whitney Houston's debut LP called simply Whitney Houston had four number-one singles on it? Did you know that, Christie? Whitney's voice leaps across so many boundaries and is so versatile-though she's mainly a jazz singer-that it's hard to take in the album on a first listening.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="ELIZABETH">
         <dialogue id="s41d44">You actually listen to Whitney Houston? You actually have a Whitney Houston CD? More than one?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s41m45">She giggles, rolling off the sofa onto the floor.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s41d45">(Ignoring her) It's hard to choose a favorite track among so many great ones, but &quot;The Greatest Love of All&quot; is one of the best, most powerful songs ever written about self-preservation and dignity. It's universal message crosses all boundaries, and instills one with the hope that it's not too late to better ourselves. to act kinder. Since, Elizabeth, it's impossible in the world we live in to empathize with others, we can always empathize with ourselves.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s41m46">As he speaks, he opens the case and carefully places the CD in the player, admiring its pristine silver surface, and watches it slide into the machine.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s41d46">It's an important message, crucial, really, and it's beautifully stated on the album.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s42">
      <sceneheader>INT. BEDROOM - LATER</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s42m1">AN OUT-OF-FOCUS HOME VIDEO SHOT of Elizabeth, Christie and Bateman in the throes of sex, in the master bedroom. CUT BACK TO WIDE SHOT of the bedroom, partially blocked by the video camera in the foreground. Their bodies are an incoherent tangle of arms and legs. The only sounds are moans, heavy breathing and the slapping of flesh against flesh. CLOSE ON Christie's head and shoulders. Her eyes are shut as she grimly concentrates on giving a good professional performance, turning her head every so often to check the progress of her partners. OFFSCREEN WE HEAR Elizabeth panting in genuine pleasure, moaning loudly. Her voice gets louder and louder and then shifts to actual pain. Bateman rises up off the bed, suddenly appearing behind Christie. There is blood on his face. Christie turns her head and sees him. She screams and leaps off the bed, running out of the room. She slams the mirrored door behind her, and as it swings shut for a split second we see Elizabeth writhing in pain on the bed. We follow Christie out of the room, panicking, screaming. Christie runs down a darkened hallway, frantically opening doors, looking for an escape. She hears the SOUND OF A CHAINSAW coming from the bedroom. She opens a closet. The closet lights up as she opens the door and sees two dead, women hanging inside. She screams, then claps a hand over her mouth. She stops and listens. THE DISTANT SOUND OF THE CHAINSAW. She backs away slowly, into another dark room, lit only by the light from a television set. Through the darkness she sees a head on the top of the TV and starts to whimper. She runs toward the nearest door. Finding herself in the main hallway, she begins to jog toward the front door, then runs. Bateman appears from nowhere, holding the chainsaw, spattered with blood. Christie screams and changes direction. Bateman leaps at her, bellowing. They run through the bedroom and into the bathroom. Christie trips over Elizabeth's body, which is half in the bathtub. Both are slipping on the floor, which is slick with blood. Christie falls, tries to get up. Bateman grabs her leg. He tries to bite it. She kicks him in the face and gets up, running toward the front door. He runs after her.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s42d1">Not the face, you bitch. Not the fucking face, you piece of bitch trash!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s42m2">Christie, screaming, makes it out the front door. Bateman runs after her. She runs down the hall screaming and banging on doors. She moves to the elevator, pounding hysterically on the buttons. She sees the stairwell and runs for it. Bateman sees this and runs after her, revving the chainsaw. She runs down the stairs, Bateman two flights behind her. He stops, leans over the railing to look at her, then aims the chainsaw at her and drops it. Christie SCREAMS OFFSCREEN, then is suddenly silent. FROM BATEMAN'S POV we see Christie's body sprawled facedown at the bottom of the stairwell. The chainsaw sticks out of her back like a sword.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s43">
      <sceneheader>INT. CRAYONS - EARLY EVENING</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s43m1">An insanely expensive restaurant with a childhood motif: paper tablecloths and jars of crayons for drawing, lots of primary colors, and a goldfish bowl on each table. Bateman is at a table with Evelyn. They are both drawing on the tablecloth. Bateman is drawing Christie with the chainsaw in her back.</meta>
      <char name="EVELYN">
         <dialogue id="s43d1">I want a firm commitment.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s43d2">I think, Evelyn, that we've...lost touch.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s43m3">Evelyn waves to a couple across the room.</meta>
      <char name="EVELYN">
         <dialogue id="s43d3">(Distracted) Why? What's wrong?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s43d4">(Speaking very carefully, measuring each word) My need to engage in homicidal behavior on a massive scale cannot be, um, corrected, but I have no other way to fulfill my needs.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s43m5">The woman across the room holds up her hand, displaying a new bracelet. Evelyn smiles and nods approvingly.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s43d5">We need to talk.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="EVELYN">
         <dialogue id="s43d6">Talk about what, Patrick? What is there to talk about?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s43d7">It's over, Evelyn. It's all over</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="EVELYN">
         <dialogue id="s43d8">(Motioning to the waiter for water) Touchy, touchy. I'm sorry I brought the wedding up. Let's just avoid the issue, alright? Now, are we having coffee?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s43d9">I'm fucking serious. It's fucking over. Us. This is no joke. I don't think we should see each other anymore.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="EVELYN">
         <dialogue id="s43d10">But your friends are my friends. My friends are your friends. I don't think it would work. (Reaching over to dab his face with a napkin) You have a little something on your upper lip.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s43d11">(Brushing her hand away) I know that your friends are my friends. I've thought about that. You can have them.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s43m12">Evelyn stares at him, suspicious and bewildered, a realization dawning.</meta>
      <char name="EVELYN">
         <dialogue id="s43d12">You're really serious, aren't you?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s43d13">Yes, I am.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="EVELYN">
         <dialogue id="s43d14">But what about the past? Our past?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s43d15">We never really shared one.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="EVELYN">
         <dialogue id="s43d16">You're inhuman.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s43d17">I'm...in touch with humanity. Evelyn, I'm sorry. (He pauses, as if searching for the right words) You're just not terribly important to me.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s43m18">Evelyn begins to cry.</meta>
      <char name="EVELYN">
         <dialogue id="s43d18">No, no, no.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s43d19">I know my behavior is...erratic sometimes.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s43m20">She reaches desperately across the table and takes his hand. Bateman pulls his hand away.</meta>
      <char name="EVELYN">
         <dialogue id="s43d20">(Sobbing) What do you want me to do, what is it you want?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s43m21">The occupants of nearby tables begin to stare. Bateman is becoming increasingly agitated and embarrassed.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s43d21">(Looking uncomfortably around the room) If you really want to do something for me, you can stop making this scene right now.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="EVELYN">
         <dialogue id="s43d22">Oh God, I can't believe this.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s43d23">I'm leaving now. I've assessed the situation and I'm going.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s43m24">Evelyn makes an effort to compose herself. She blots the tears so they will not affect her make-up.</meta>
      <char name="EVELYN">
         <dialogue id="s43d24">(Surprisingly calm) Where are you going?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s43d25">I'm just leaving.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="EVELYN">
         <dialogue id="s43d26">But where?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s43d27">I have to return some videotapes.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s43m28">He rushes out of the room.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s44">
      <sceneheader>EXT. TRIBECA STREET - EVENING</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s44m1">Bateman wanders into misty Tribeca streets, sees a stray cat.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s44d1">Here kitty, kitty.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s44m2">The small mangy cat rubs against him. He picks it up and walks toward an ATM, holding the cat. He puts his card in the machine. The screen reads: FEED ME A STRAY CAT. Bateman begins to attempt to shove the kitten into the deposit slot with some difficulty. The kitten squeals. He takes a gun from out of his pocket and points it at the kitten. He doesn't notice the woman waiting behind him.</meta>
      <char name="WOMAN">
         <dialogue id="s44d2">Oh my God! Stop that! What are you doing?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s44m3">Bateman wheels around and shoots her. She falls screaming to the floor. Responding to the gunshot, A POLICE CAR SIREN WAILS in the distance. Bateman breaks into a run. The police car screeches after him.</meta>
      <char name="COP CAR (O.S.)">
         <dialogue id="s44d3">HALT STOP. PUT DOWN YOUR WEAPON.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s44m4">Bateman ducks down an alley.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s45">
      <sceneheader>EXT. ALLEY - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s45m1">A COP rushes toward him, seemingly from out of nowhere, and tackles him, trying to get the gun away from him. Bateman manages to shoot the cop in the face while both of them have their hands on the gun, then shoots him again. He reloads the gun. The sound of more COP CARS arriving. He runs out of the alley.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s46">
      <sceneheader>EXT. STREET - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s46m1">As he reaches the street, he finds A PHALANX OF POLICE CARS approaching.</meta>
      <char name="COP CAR">
         <dialogue id="s46d1">Halt. Put down your weapon.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s46m2">The cops leap out and fire a warning shot in the air. Bateman shoots at them. The police return fire. Bateman ducks down behind a parked car and continues shooting wildly. A bullet hits the gas tank of one of the police cars. It catches fire and explodes. The flames light up the scene, illuminating the bodies of policemen both living and dead. NEW ANGLE: Bateman flees from the scene. The camera follows him as he runs along a row of Porsches, trying to open each one, setting off a cacophony of CAR ALARMS. THE SOUND OF POLICE SIRENS draws near. NEW ANGLE: He runs, panting, until he ends up in front of a tail, brilliantly lit office building. As he approaches, the lights in the building are going off floor by floor.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s47">
      <sceneheader>INT. OFFICE BUILDING - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s47m1">He rushes into the lobby, running for the elevator.</meta>
      <char name="NIGHT WATCHMAN">
         <dialogue id="s47d1">Burning the midnight oil, Mr. Smith? You forgot to sign in.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s47m2">Bateman wheels around and shoots him. He runs toward the revolving doors. As he swings around in the doors, he notices a JANITOR who has witnessed the shooting. He revolves back into the lobby and shoots the janitor.</meta>
      <meta id="s47m3">NEW ANGLE: He runs out of the building and across the street to an identical office building, the one that houses Pierce &amp; Pierce.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s48">
      <sceneheader>INT. PIERCE &amp; PIERCE LOBBY - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s48m1">Bateman nods at the Pierce &amp; Pierce NIGHT WATCHMAN and signs in. He breathes a sigh of relief as the elevator doors close behind him.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s49">
      <sceneheader>INT. BATEMAN'S OFFICE - NIGHT</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s49m1">Bateman stands looking out through the floor-length windows at a panoramic night view of the city and the river. Below him he sees a SWAT TEAM swarming over the roof of the opposite building. There are ambulances standing by, flares everywhere, distant sirens. Suddenly, THE SOUND OF A HELICOPTER draws near. Frightened, he drops to the floor behind his desk. Helicopter searchlights scan the building, illuminating Bateman's office for a few moments with a blaze of light. He is crouched in one corner, half-sobbing, talking into the phone, as the searchlight keeps circling.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s49d1">Harold, it's Bateman. Patrick Bateman. You're my lawyer so I think you should know-I've killed a lot of people. Some escort girls, in an apartment uptown, some homeless people, maybe five or ten, an NYU girl I met in Central Park. I left her in a parking lot, near Dunkin' Donuts. I killed Bethany, my old girlfriend, with a nail gun. and a man, some old faggot with a dog. Last week I killed another girl with a chainsaw-I had to, she almost got away There was someone else there, maybe a model, I can't remember but she's dead too. And Paul Owen. I killed Paul Owen with an ax, in the face. His body is dissolving in a bathtub in Hell's Kitchen. I don't want to leave anything out here...I guess I've killed 20 people, maybe 40-I have tapes of a lot of it. Some of the girls have seen the tapes, I even... well, I ate some of their brains and I tried to cook a little. Tonight I just, well, I had to kill a lot of people and I'm not sure I 'm going to get away with it this time-I mean I guess I'm a pretty sick guy. So-if you get hack tomorrow, I may show up at Harry's Bar, so, you know, keep your eyes open.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s49m2">Bateman hangs up the phone. The helicopter searchlight circles back, briefly illuminating the room. The camera rises up over Bateman huddled in the corner, staring blankly at the sky.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s50">
      <sceneheader>INT. SMITH AND WOLLENSKY RESTAURANT - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s50m1">KIMBALL and Bateman are sitting at a corner table.</meta>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s50d1">(Very surprised) No hash browns?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s50d2">Not in the mood, I guess.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s50d3">But...everyone orders the hash browns here. I mean- it's-have you been here before?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s50d4">(Deliberately nonchalant) Yes, of course. The hash browns are delicious. I'm just...not... ordering them.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s50d5">(Looking at him like he's nuts) Suit yourself, I guess.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s50m6">Pause.</meta>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s50d6">So, the night he disappeared? Any new thoughts on what you did?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s50d7">I'm not really sure. I had a shower...and some sorbet?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s50d8">I think maybe you've got your dates mixed up.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s50d9">But how? Where do you place Paul that night?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s50d10">According to his date book, and this was verified by his secretary, he had dinner with...Marcus Halberstam.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s50d11">And?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s50d12">I've questioned him.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s50d13">Marcus?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s50d14">Yes. And he denies it. Though at first he couldn't be sure.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s50d15">But Marcus denied it?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s50d16">Yes.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s50d17">Well, does Marcus have an alibi?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s50d18">Yes.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s50m19">A pause.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s50d19">He does? You're sure?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s50d20">(smiling) I checked it out. It's clean.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s50d21">Oh. KIMBALL Now where were you? (He laughs)</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s50d22">(Laughing with him) Where was Marcus?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s50d23">He wasn't with Paul Owen.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s50d24">So who was he with?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s50d25">He was at Atlantis with Craig McDermott, Frederick Dibble, Harry Newman, George Butner and  (He pauses, Then looks up) - you.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s50m26">A moment of stunned silence.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s50d26">Oh, right. Of course...We had wanted Paul Owen to come. But he said he had plans...I guess I had dinner with Victoria...the following night.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="KIMBALL">
         <dialogue id="s50d27">Personally I think the guy went a little nutso. Split town for a while. Maybe he did go to London. Sightseeing. Drinking. Whatever. Anyway, I'm pretty sure he'll turn up sooner or later. (A pause) I mean, to think that one of his friends killed him, for no reason whatsoever would be too ridiculous. Isn't that right, Patrick?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s50m28">McDermott stops by the table. McDERMOTT KIMBALL! How's the investigation? Talking to Bateman? Don't believe a word he says. (Laughs uproariously slapping him on the back) Bateman, what's wrong with ,you? Bateman looks at him in silence, panicking. McDERMOTT You can't eat at Smith and Wollensky without ordering the hash browns. Jesus, Bateman, you're a raving maniac. Been at Pierce &amp; Pierce too long. (He wanders off muttering) No fucking hash browns...</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s51">
      <sceneheader>INT. PAUL OWEN'S APARTMENT BUILDING - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s51m1">Bateman walks into the lobby of Paul Owen's building. He has a surgical mask in one hand.</meta>
      <char name="DOORMAN">
         <dialogue id="s51d1">What can I do for you, sir?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s51d2">20B.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="DOORMAN">
         <dialogue id="s51d3">Of course. Mrs. Wolfe is up there right now.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s51d4">Mrs. Wolfe?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="DOORMAN">
         <dialogue id="s51d5">The real estate agent? You do have an appointment, don't you?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s51m6">Bateman steps out of the elevator and walks cautiously down the hallway. Owen's door is open. The apartment is freshly painted and has been immaculately redecorated in English country-house style: overstuffed sofas, lots of chintz. There are flowers everywhere, and a YOUNG YUPPIE COUPLE stands admiring the place talkingto the realtor, MRS. WOLFE. Bateman wanders down the hallway, looking for familiar signs. He stops at the closet where we last saw two dead girls hanging. He opens the door and the light switches on, but it is empty. Mrs. Wolfe approaches, smiling.</meta>
      <char name="MRS. WOLFE">
         <dialogue id="s51d6">Are you my two o'clock?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s51d7">No.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s51m8">Mrs. Wolfe eyes him strangely, then looks down at the surgical mash clutched in his hand. Her expression changes.</meta>
      <char name="MRS. WOLFE">
         <dialogue id="s51d8">Can I help you?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s51d9">I'm looking for...Paul Owen's...place.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s51m10">She stares at him impassively.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s51d10">Doesn't he live here?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="MRS. WOLFE">
         <dialogue id="s51d11">No, he doesn't.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s51d12">Are you sure?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="MRS. WOLFE">
         <dialogue id="s51d13">You saw the ad in the Times?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s51d14">No. Yes. I mean yes, I did. In the Times. But... doesn't Paul Owen still live here?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="MRS. WOLFE">
         <dialogue id="s51d15">There was no ad in the Times.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s51m16">Bateman is shaking as they continue to stare at each other.</meta>
      <char name="MRS. WOLFE">
         <dialogue id="s51d16">I think you should go now.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s51d17">But I think...I want to know what happened here.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="MRS. WOLFE">
         <dialogue id="s51d18">Don't make any trouble. Please. I suggest you go.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s51m19">Bateman backs away slowly.</meta>
      <char name="MRS. WOLFE">
         <dialogue id="s51d19">Don't come back.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s51d20">I won't...don't worry.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s51m21">Mrs. Wolfe glares at him as he walks down the hall, rattled, and gets into the elevator.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s52">
      <sceneheader>EXT. DEPARTMENT STORE - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s52m1">Bateman enters the revolving door of an office building, panicking and breathing heavily. He is sweating, his hair is wild, and he looks deranged. He goes around the revolving door twice and comes out onto the street again, where he bumps smack into a GUY just like him.</meta>
      <char name="GUY">
         <dialogue id="s52d1">Hey, Kinsley.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s52m2">Bateman looks up at him wild-eyed.</meta>
      <char name="GUY">
         <dialogue id="s52d2">See you at Fluties, okay?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s52m3">The guy walks away, utterly unfazed. Bateman wanders down the street, banging his briefcase against walls, garbage cans, etc.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s53">
      <sceneheader>EXT. MIDTOWN PHONE BOOTH - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s53m1">Bateman searches his pockets for pills. He finds three different pills and swallows them. He's sweating, and takes his jacket off to wipe his face, dialing a number.</meta>
      <char name="JEAN (O.S.)">
         <dialogue id="s53d1">Patrick Bateman's office.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s53d2">Jean? Hello? Jean?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JEAN (O.S.)">
         <dialogue id="s53d3">Patrick? Is that you?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s53d4">Hello? Jean, I need help!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JEAN (O.S.)">
         <dialogue id="s53d5">Where are you?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s53d6">Jean-I'm not-</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JEAN (O.S.)">
         <dialogue id="s53d7">Craig McDermott called. He wants to meet you and David Van Patten and Tim Price at Harry's for drinks.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s53d8">Oh God, what did you say, you dumb bitch?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JEAN (O.S.)">
         <dialogue id="s53d9">Patrick? I can't hear you.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s53d10">What are I doing?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JEAN (O.S.)">
         <dialogue id="s53d11">Where are you? Patrick, what's wrong?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s53d12">I don't think I'm gonna make it, Jean.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s53m13">Pause.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s53d13">...to the office this afternoon.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JEAN (O.S.)">
         <dialogue id="s53d14">Why?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s53d15">(Screaming) Just...say...no!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="JEAN (O.S.)">
         <dialogue id="s53d16">What is it, Patrick? Are you alright?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s53d17">Stop sounding so Fucking sad! Jesus!</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s53m18">He hangs up. He throws the Walkman which is around his neck into a nearby trash can, and wipes his face with his jacket.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s54">
      <sceneheader>INT. BATEMAN'S OFFICE- SAME DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s54m1">Jean sits at Bateman's desk. She looks around, and then opens his desk drawer and tentatively begins to search through it.</meta>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s55">
      <sceneheader>INT. HARRY'S BAR - EVENING</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s55m1">Bateman comes into the bar, a little cleaned up from the previous scene (he's smoothed his hair), but still panicking and disheveled. He spots his friends in a corner, sits down, still breathing heavily. Price is on his cell-phone, trying to get reservations. McDERMOTT Bateman, you're looking a little wild-eyed rough day at the office? They all laugh. McDERMOTT Hey, look-Price is back. And he's drinking Perrier. He s a changed man. Except...he still can't get a reservation to save his life. Bateman sits down silently. McDERMOTT Why don't you try I 50 Wooster? Just fucking call them.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s55d1">(On automatic) I'm not going anywhere unless we have a reservation.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="VAN PATTEN">
         <dialogue id="s55d2">Le Cirque, Flamingo East, Oyster Bar, come on, faggots-just get a res.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="PRICE">
         <dialogue id="s55d3">Keep your shirt on. Maybe lose the suspenders.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s55m4">Bateman spots HAROLD CARNES at the bar, tenses.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s55d4">(He downs his drink) Excuse me, gentlemen. Right back. He approaches Carnes cautiously.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="CARNES">
         <dialogue id="s55d5">Face it-the Japanese will own most of this country by the end of the '90s.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s55m6">Bateman approaches, trying to act casual.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s55d6">Shut up, Carnes, they will not.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s55m7">Carnes is surprised, turns around, looks vaguely confused.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s55d7">So, Harold, did you get my message?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s55m8">Carnes lights a cigarette, stalling. Then laughs.</meta>
      <char name="CARNES">
         <dialogue id="s55d8">Jesus, Davis. Yes. That was hilarious. That was you, wasn't it?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s55d9">(Waving smoke out of his face) Yes, naturally.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="CARNES">
         <dialogue id="s55d10">Bateman killing Owen and the escort girls? Oh that s fabulous. That's rich...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s55m11">Pause</meta>
      <char name="CARNES">
         <dialogue id="s55d11">It was a pretty long message, wasn't it?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s55d12">What exactly do you mean?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="CARNES">
         <dialogue id="s55d13">The message you left.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s55m14">Carnes is distracted, waving at people.</meta>
      <char name="CARNES">
         <dialogue id="s55d14">By the way Davis, how is Cynthia? You're still seeing her, right?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s55d15">But wait, Harold, what do you mean?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s55m16">Carnes isn't really listening.</meta>
      <char name="CARNES">
         <dialogue id="s55d16">Excuse me. Nothing. Good to see you. Is that Edward Towers?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s55m17">He turns to go.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s55d17">Carnes? Wait.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="CARNES">
         <dialogue id="s55d18">(Sighing) Davis. I'm not one to bad-mouth anyone, your joke was amusing. But come on, man, you had one fatal flaw: Bateman's such a dork, such a boring, spineless lightweight, that I couldn't fully appreciate it. I wasn't fooled for a second. Now, if you'd said Price, or McDermott...Otherwise, it was amusing. Now, let's have lunch or dinner or something. Hilarious, Davis. A killer.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s55d19">What are you talking about? Bateman is what?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="CARNES">
         <dialogue id="s55d20">Oh Christ. He can barely pick up an escort girl, let alone...what was it you said he did to her?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s55m21">Carnes looks around the club, raises his glass to a passing couple. He laughs politely.</meta>
      <char name="CARNES">
         <dialogue id="s55d21">Now, if you'll excuse me, I really must...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s55d22">(Desperate, shouting) Wait. Stop. You don't seem to understand. You're not really comprehending any of this. I killed him. I did it, Carnes. I'm Patrick Bateman. I chopped Owen's fucking head off. I tortured dozens of girls. The whole message I left on your machine was true.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="CARNES">
         <dialogue id="s55d23">Excuse me. I really must he going.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s55d24">No! Listen, don't you know who I am? I'm not Davis, I'm Patrick Bateman! I talk to you on the phone all the time! Don't you recognize me? You're my lawyer.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s55m25">Carnes stares at him in confusion and annoyance.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s55d25">Now, Carnes, listen to me. Listen very, very carefully. I killed Paul Owen and I liked it. I can't make myself any clearer</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="CARNES">
         <dialogue id="s55d26">But that's simply not possible. And I don't find this funny anymore.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s55d27">It never was supposed to he! Why isn't it possible?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="CARNES">
         <dialogue id="s55d28">(Eyeing Bateman worriedly) It's just not.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s55d29">Why not, you stupid bastard?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s55m30">Carnes stares at him.</meta>
      <char name="CARNES">
         <dialogue id="s55d30">Because I had dinner with Paul Owen twice in London...just ten days ago.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s55d31">No, you...didn't?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="CARNES">
         <dialogue id="s55d32">Now, if you'll excuse me.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s55m33">Bateman returns back to his friends' table, in a daze. They are all looking at the television, where Ronald Reagan is giving a speech about Iran Contra. They are halfheartedly arguing about whether or not he's lying.</meta>
      <char name="PRICE">
         <dialogue id="s55d33">How can he lie like that? How can he pull that shit?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="VAN PATTEN">
         <dialogue id="s55d34">What shit? Now where do we have reservations at? I mean I'm not really hungry, but I would like to have reservations somewhere.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="PRICE">
         <dialogue id="s55d35">(To Bateman) I don't believe it. He looks so...normal. He seems so... out of it. So...undangerous.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s55m36">McDERMOTT He is totally harmless you geek. Was totally harmless. Just like you are totally harmless. But he did do all that shit and you have failed lo get us into I 50, so, you know, what can I say?</meta>
      <char name="PRICE">
         <dialogue id="s55d36">I just don't see how someone, anyone, can appear that way and yet be involved in such total shit. How can you be so fucking, I don't know, cool about it?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="VAN PATTEN">
         <dialogue id="s55d37">Some guys are just born cool, I guess.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s55m38">Bateman laughs at this. Price shoots him a look.</meta>
      <char name="PRICE">
         <dialogue id="s55d38">And Bateman, what are YOU SO fucking zany about?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s55d39">I'm just a happy camper. Rockin' and a-rollin'.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <char name="VAN PATTEN">
         <dialogue id="s55d40">(To Price) Rehab's done wonders for you, pal. Working for UNICEF now?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s55m41">McDERMOTT Do you want another Perrier Timothy? Some seltzer water?</meta>
      <char name="PRICE">
         <dialogue id="s55d41">Oh brother look-he presents himself as a harmless Old codger. But inside...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s55m42">Pause.</meta>
      <char name="PRICE">
         <dialogue id="s55d42">But inside...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s55m43">The SOUNDS OF THE BAR FADE AWAY and we hear Bateman's thoughts:</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN (V.O.)">
         <dialogue id="s55d43">But inside doesn't matter...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s55m44">THE SOUNDS OF THE BAR RETURN. McDERMOTT (Bored) Inside? Yes, inside? Believe it or not, Price we're actually listening to you.</meta>
      <char name="PRICE">
         <dialogue id="s55d44">Bateman? Come on, what do you think?</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s55m45">Bateman looks up and smiles at Price. Then shrugs.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN">
         <dialogue id="s55d45">Whatever.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s55m46">The conversation breaks up as Van Patten takes out his phone.</meta>
      <char name="VAN PATTEN">
         <dialogue id="s55d46">Whose moronic idea was it to drink dry beers? I need a Scotch.</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s55m47">The sounds of the bar fade down. The following voiceover runs over images of Bateman and his friends ordering drinks, talking on portable phones, talking, laughing - combined with images of other very similar young men at other tables drinking, talking on portable phones, talking, laughing,</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN (V.O.)">
         <dialogue id="s55d47">There are no more barriers to cross. All I have in common with the uncontrollable and the insane, the vicious and the evil, all the mayhem I have caused and my utter indifference toward it, I have now surpassed...</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s56">
      <sceneheader>INT. BATEMAN'S OFFICE - DAY</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s56m1">Jean is alone in Bateman's office, looking through his diary. We see the pages that she is looking at. They are filled with doodles of mutilated women and their names...Jean looks lost and frightened, and begins to cry.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN (V.O.)">
         <dialogue id="s56d1">My pain is constant and sharp and I do not hope for a better world for anyone. I fact I want my pain to be inflicted on others. I want no escape.</dialogue>
      </char>
   </scene>
   <scene id="s57">
      <sceneheader>INT. HARRY'S BAR - EARLY EVENING</sceneheader>
      <meta id="s57m1">leaning back in his leather armchair, drinking a double Scotch, his eyes blank.</meta>
      <char name="BATEMAN (V.O.)">
         <dialogue id="s57d1">But even after admitting this, there is no catharsis. I gain no deeper knowledge about myself, no new knowledge can be extracted from my telling. There has been no reason for me to tell you any of this. This confession has meant nothing...</dialogue>
      </char>
      <meta id="s57m2">The camera moves up to a sign on the wall behind him: &quot;THIS IS NOT AN EXIT.&quot;</meta>
      <meta id="s57m3">CREDITS ROLL</meta>
   </scene>
</movie>
